<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wellesley | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/wellesley/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-05-08T22:54:46-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Description of the Wellesley Weston Magazine]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/07/a-description-of-the-wellesley-weston-magazine/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/07/a-description-of-the-wellesley-weston-magazine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For several years now, the residents of my hometown of Wellesley, Massachussetts have received
free copies of the <em>Wellesley Weston Magazine</em> once a quarter. The nearly 200-page, glossy,
full-color magazine is printed on luxoriously thick paper. The magazine features articles about
local charitable organizations, individuals, and events but is mostly advertisements. The 182-page
spring 2011 edition has a editorial-to-ad ratio of about 1:2. I&rsquo;m not an avid reader of the
<em>Wellesley Weston Magazine</em>, but I think the magazine speaks a lot about the towns.</p>

<p>A large porportion of the ads are real estate listings or any of the various services associated
with owning and maintaining a McMansion. The second page is a Coldwell Banker brokerage ad. It&rsquo;s
followed by a Williams &amp; Spade interior design ad. Then there&rsquo;s a table of contents page followed
by home listings ranging from $1 million to nearly $7 million.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>There&rsquo;s an article titled &ldquo;10 Tips for Adding Variety to Your Workout Routine.&rdquo; It recommends
trying out pilates, zumba, or getting a personal trainer at various Wellesley/Weston clubs and
fitness centers. There&rsquo;s a section with news briefs about the two towns&#8217; people places, and
businesses. There&rsquo;s one about how Ms. So-and-So &ldquo;of Centry 21 Commonwealth was honored recently at
the Centry 21 Top Agent Retreat held at the Atlantis Paradise Island resort in the Bahamas.&rdquo;</p>

<p>An ad for luxury watches with a black and white photo of a father holding a watch open in his
hands and displaying it towards his 10-year-old-looking son who&rsquo;s wearing white gloves and a
magnifying monocle.</p>

<p>For a closer look at the magazine, just go to <a href="http://www.wellesleywestonmagazine.com/">their website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wellesley High School 2006 Commencement Address]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/wellesley-high-school-2006-commencement-address/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/wellesley-high-school-2006-commencement-address</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the commencement address delivered at my high school graduation by David McCullough Jr.,
son of historian <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_McCullough">David McCullough</a> Sr. As I was about to post this, I tried to find this
speech online to check for copyright and permission to republish. It used to be hosted on
Wellesley High School&rsquo;s website. Since then they seem to have taken it down, and I&rsquo;m not able to
find it online anywhere. So for posterity, here it is.</em></p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;GO&rdquo; 2006 Commencement Address – David McCullough</strong></p>

<p>Dr. King, Mrs. Mirkin, Mr. Keegan, Mrs. Jablonski, friends and families of the graduates, members
of the Wellesley High School class of 2006, for the honor of the invitation to speak this
afternoon I am very grateful. Thank you.</p>

<p>The occasion is commencement, a beginning. Let us not, therefore, spend too much time looking
backward. Suffice to say you spent four useful and, I hope, happy years in that lovely pile of
bricks, that you now know the difference between Dickens and Dickinson and recognize a pythagorean
theorem when you trip over one, that you can conjugate an unAmerican verb or two and navigate most
regions of the periodic table. You know, I hope, something of history and its particulars, and you
understand it is (present tense) populated with people, every bit as real and vital as you are,
with loves and wishes and apprehensions just like yours. I hope in that building and on its green
fields you learned the indispensability of passion and practice and teamwork, that you felt both
victory and defeat, that you learned something of the connection between dedication and
achievement, between effort and results. You enjoyed, I hope, the peace of mind of knowing you
tried your best.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>But more important than any of that–and all of that is of course enormously important–I hope your
experience taught you how to learn&hellip; and, more important still, why to learn–not just for the more
productive and fulfilling life it will bring you, but also to help you meet your responsibilities
as citizens of the planet.</p>

<p>As maybe you&rsquo;ve noticed, the human body is designed for forward motion&hellip; eyes, ears, feet, knees,
hips, all of it engineered not just to meet the future, but to stride into it, every step a leap
of faith in our capacity to handle whatever we might encounter in a universe rife with opportunity
and peril. We&rsquo;re at our best, we human beings, moving forward. Lying around, stasis, these are a
misuse of the machine, an abuse really, as unhealthy for the spirit as for the body–and no good
either for the rest of us who stand to benefit from your good deeds. I&rsquo;m reminded of one of those
illustrated evolutionary charts in a sixth grade life science textbook, monkey to man, the full
parade, a hunched little gibbon-looking thing&rsquo;s first tentative steps becoming eventually
Homosapien&rsquo;s confident suburban power walk, each moving–compelled by instinct–into a future as
unknown to him as ours is to us. But now the whizzes over in Cambridge tell us genetic evidence
suggests it wasn&rsquo;t necessarily such a linear forward march after all, not such clean break from
our monkey forebears. There were, apparently, trial separations then&hellip; reconciliations. Of a
tranquil moonlit evening, somewhere in the suddenly inappropriately named Rift Valley, it appears
man and monkey reunited, looked longingly into one another&rsquo;s eyes and&hellip; perhaps there was
champagne&hellip; made beautiful music together&hellip; and, it seems, bouncing baby, uh, primates. &ldquo;Look, mom,
there&rsquo;s something weird floating in the gene pool!&rdquo; Which, as much as anything can, explains my
brother in law.</p>

<p>No, our trek across the millennia has been neither direct nor without misstep. We&rsquo;ve strayed,
we&rsquo;ve blundered, we&rsquo;ve done terrible things to ourselves and our planet. But that&rsquo;s looking
backward and I said we wouldn&rsquo;t do that. It&rsquo;s now X:XX p.m., Friday, June 2, 2006 AD. You are, or
will be momentarily, high school graduates–and rather than a vague abstraction waiting for you
somewhere next month or next year, the rest of your life is already barreling right along. As of
course it always has been. I hope you&rsquo;ve learned that, too. And you have by now, I hope, developed
wisdom and backbone enough to resist the seductions of comfort, of leisure, of easy satisfactions,
and the thick, shiny catalogue of pop culture idiocies. You have the resolve, I hope, to make
shoulds and shouldn&#8217;ts wills and won&#8217;ts. And you have enough regard for yourself to define who you
are not by what you have, but by what you do. And believe me, there&rsquo;s plenty to be done.</p>

<p>On that note, last week American Idol&rsquo;s Taylor Hicks received more votes than the chief executive
of the world&rsquo;s preeminent democracy. At first glance this is of course disturbing&hellip; but you have to
remember Mr. Hicks is at least pretty good at something. Still, we don&rsquo;t need Simon Whatshisname
to tell us the world is a mess. The polar ice caps are melting. Glaciers are receding faster than
Barry Bonds&#8217; integrity. Blistering heat waves, catastrophic hurricanes, tornadoes, floods,
droughts&hellip; they&rsquo;re happening with increasing frequency, intensity and devastation–and we know why;
yet still we&rsquo;re chugging fossil fuels like frat boys on spring break and the current
administration appears more concerned about Exxon-Mobil and friends than the environment. Disease,
starvation, poverty, racism, political and economic oppression, terrorism, ethnic cleansing, wars
of dubious intent and otherwise, religious crackpots rampaging right and left, drug abuse, human
trafficking, illiteracy, exploitation, pandemic greed, small-mindedness and incivility&hellip; Ours is a
seriously afflicted planet. And this, I&rsquo;ll remind you, is your world. It belongs to you as much as
it belongs to anyone.</p>

<p>Your world in all its parts. Your, for example, Africa&hellip; where nearly half a million children are
dying of AIDS every year&hellip; where in 2010, the year most of you will graduate from college, the
United Nations projects there will be 40 million children orphaned because of AIDS, 40
million–that&rsquo;s the population of Massachusetts times six. Today in Zimbabwe life expectancy is all
of 33 years. In Sudan, an Arabic word meaning &ldquo;land of the blacks,&rdquo; Arabs are, with their
government&rsquo;s encouragement, systematically killing tribal blacks because they find them
inconvenient, from infants to the elderly–and in just two years the death toll is approaching
200,000. In Congo we&rsquo;re witnessing the bloodiest human conflict since World War II. An estimated
1,250 Congolese are dying every day, with totals in eight years of war approaching four million.
Now this is not National Geographic-Animal Planet-Tarzan movie-click-change-the-channel-who-cares
Africa. This is, again, your Africa, everyone&rsquo;s Africa, the only Africa we have. These are human
beings (see if this sounds familiar) every bit as real and vital as you are, with loves and wishes
and apprehensions just like yours, with, I&rsquo;ll add, human rights every bit as valid and compelling
as yours. And if anything is going to be done about these eminently preventable crises, these
outrages, those in a position to help have to step forward and do it. I nominate you.</p>

<p>In The Great Gatsby, which all of you read&hellip; were assigned &hellip;F. Scott Fitzgerald laments the
despoliation of the American continent and the corruption of the founding fathers&#8217; noble ideals.
Now, today, it&rsquo;s worse, even, than in those sunny summer days in the Eggs: Time magazine tells us,
for example, for the first time since the depths of the Depression we Americans are spending more
than we earn. Today it&rsquo;s life, liberty and the pursuit of stuff, the pursuit of prestige, the
pursuit of whiter whites and rock-hard abs and an understatedly spectacular shingled Robert Stern
rambler on a breezy Nantucket heath and in the purple-and-white crushed quahog-shell driveway a
Mercedes-Benz G500 Grand Edition SUV, silver preferably, with a 4,966 cubic centimeter, 24 valve,
90 degree V8 engine and variable-focus halogen headlights with heated high-pressure washers, and
multicontour premium leather seats with pneumatic side bolsters, and, in case we get lost, a GPS
navigational system with an in-dash 5″ color LCD screen. And when at last we can no longer amuse
ourselves and wish the alarmist, party-pooping nags would just go away, when the GPS navigational
system with an in-dash 5″ color LCD screen cannot help us, we must deal with the consequences of
how we&rsquo;ve chosen to conduct our lives. &ldquo;&hellip;gradually,&rdquo; Nick Carraway tells us in a reflective moment
at the end of the novel&hellip;</p>

<p>I became aware of the old island here that flowered once for Dutch sailors&#8217; eyes–a fresh green
breast of the new world. Its vanished trees, the trees that had made way for Gatsby&rsquo;s house, had
once pandered in whispers to the last and greatest of all human dreams; for a transitory enchanted
moment man must have held his breath in the presence of this continent, compelled into an
aesthetic contemplation he neither understood nor desired, face to face for the last time in
history with something commensurate with his capacity for wonder.</p>

<p>And a few lines later, this pessimistic conclusion: &ldquo;So we beat on, boats against the current,
borne back ceaselessly into the past.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A lovely mournful passage, poetic, and a provocative thought–but Nick is wrong. He&rsquo;s wrong 10,958
times a day. (That&rsquo;s the daily average number of births in this country.) You see, Nick Carraway
had no children. Nick Carraway did not have the privilege of knowing you, of seeing you in action
in the classroom and on those fields and in this community. The last time in history? Every child
surpasses mankind&rsquo;s capacity for wonder, and every freshly minted high school graduate, too. For
in each of you is the surpassing beauty of immeasurable promise, a percolating life spirit close
to overflowing, boundless energy, superlative ability. Each of you represents mankind&rsquo;s great hope
to redress grievances, counteract stupidity, rectify injustice, relieve suffering, to lead
humanity forward. In each of you is great work yet to be done, ignorance to be enlightened,
malefaction to be set right, beauty and utility to be created&hellip; and, of course, in time, children
of your own–and it starts all over again.</p>

<p>Over the next few years of your lives the focus of your education will become narrower, deeper and
more specialized, and the paths you&rsquo;ll follow will become clearer. Along the way work hard always.
Resist, please, the temptations of exclusionary self-interest, and be careful not to confuse
fulfillment with satisfaction. If you can manage it, earn your living in something you&rsquo;d do for
free. In everything persevere. Prize integrity. Cultivate interests. More than nice, be kind, be
courteous, be respectful. Try to control your use of the word &ldquo;like.&rdquo; And when someone thanks you,
respond with something other than &ldquo;No problem.&rdquo; Go easy on the salt. Watch less television. Read.
Get outside. See Italy. Dream big. Love your family, even when&hellip; especially when&hellip; they make it
difficult. Carpe the heck out of every diem, remembering it is your world to take care of, yes,
but also to explore, to enjoy.</p>

<p>And, since democracies tend to get the governments they deserve, please vote&hellip; in political
elections, that is. Let American Idol get along without you.</p>

<p>In the last of his &ldquo;Four Quartets,&rdquo; T.S. Eliot, a contemporary of Fitzgerald&rsquo;s not noted for his
optimism, wrote,</p>

<blockquote><p>With the drawing of this Love and the voice of this Calling<br/>
  We shall not cease from exploration<br/>
  And the end of our exploring<br/>
  Will be to arrive where we started<br/>
  And know the place for the first time.</p></blockquote>

<p>At the end of your exploring you will find, I hope, a world improved for your having been there,
and a better understanding of where and with whom and for what reasons you began. And I&rsquo;ll remind
you now you began in one of the finest public school systems anywhere&hellip; public: that means paid for
by a community that believes in you &hellip;a public school system charged two hundred and twenty-eight
years ago by John Adams (maybe you&rsquo;ve heard of him) in the Constitution of the Commonwealth of
Massachusetts to &ldquo;countenance and inculcate the principles of humanity&hellip; and all social affections
and generous sentiments among the people.&rdquo; Please think about that.</p>

<p>A school, says an old adage, is four walls with tomorrow in it. Today, here, one diploma at a
time, we throw open the doors and let tomorrow free. Borne back ceaselessly into the past, Nick?
No way. From this place you&rsquo;ll stride forward. And where your eyes and feet and imagination take
you, go. Where need beckons, go. With quiet confidence worn lightly and the courage of honorable
purpose, go. With our abiding affection and admiration and every good wish, go.</p>

<p>David McCullough Jr<br/>
Wellesley High School Commencement<br/>
June 2, 2006</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Wish Your Town Had This Park]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/07/you-wish-your-town-had-this-park/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/07/you-wish-your-town-had-this-park</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-JL2RJ7TU6ok/TyB8SYHdYlI/AAAAAAAAAEs/0y79SZRmL4Y/s800/20070515_18.jpg">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-JL2RJ7TU6ok/TyB8SYHdYlI/AAAAAAAAAEs/0y79SZRmL4Y/s800/20070515_18.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;510&#8221; height=&#8221;680&#8221;></p>

<p>Centennial Park is one of the local parks in my town. I often bike or walk there to enjoy its
wildlife and scenery. I&rsquo;ve seen snakes, deer, hawks, and tadpoles there. There&#8217;s jewelweed,
rhubarb, milkweed, and bittersweet vine too.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-KmjEhcTbxRE/TyB8SYgQAgI/AAAAAAAAAEs/l5wb3I3oCWE/s800/100_0045.jpg">https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-KmjEhcTbxRE/TyB8SYgQAgI/AAAAAAAAAEs/l5wb3I3oCWE/s800/100_0045.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;510&#8221; height=&#8221;383&#8221;></p>

<p>At the back of the park, on top of a hill, there&rsquo;s a bench with a plastic container filled with
journals. The container&rsquo;s lid reads, &ldquo;A little book for your thoughts as you sit in this beautiful
place.&rdquo; Regular townsfolk walking with their dogs, spouses, sweethearts, or simply by themselves
will sit down and share their lives.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-sYa5uEbslcw/TyB8SfwSyoI/AAAAAAAAAEs/q1c25GOvzMU/s800/20070521_1.jpg">https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-sYa5uEbslcw/TyB8SfwSyoI/AAAAAAAAAEs/q1c25GOvzMU/s800/20070521_1.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;510&#8221; height=&#8221;680&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why My English Teacher Is So Cool]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2009/10/why-my-english-teacher-is-so-cool/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2009/10/why-my-english-teacher-is-so-cool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My younger brother Harvey, who has become a contributing blogger to this hopelessly doomed
enterprise, has something to say about what makes an engaging teacher. Listen up all you boring
professors.</em></p>

<p>Certain teachers stand out, especially ones who say,</p>

<blockquote><p>Oh, there&rsquo;s the word &ldquo;breast&rdquo; again. Haha, everyone see Michael sit up straight when I read it?</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p>Michael could only avert his embarrassed eyes from the looks of his classmates while Mr. Wilson
grinned.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TJfm-vzUwkI/AAAAAAAAAqw/jSD2_sLoQio/s800/1.jpg">http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TJfm-vzUwkI/AAAAAAAAAqw/jSD2_sLoQio/s800/1.jpg</a>&#8221; title=&#8221;high school hallway&#8221; ></p>

<p>Mr. Wilson teaches honors sophomore English in my school, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wellesley_High_School">Wellesley High</a>. His students
quickly realized his class wasn&rsquo;t the typical English class filled with boring analysis of boring
texts from a boring time period. This class was none of that. It was <strong>sexual innuendos and
complete disregard for conventional classroom decorum</strong>.</p>

<p>&ldquo;He uses the word breast and bosom a lot,&rdquo; Mr. Wilson commented about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nathaniel_Hawthorne">Nathaniel Hawthorne</a>. He
then nodded at a student: &ldquo;Cody O&#8217;Brien&rsquo;s favorite word of course. Whenever they come up just look
at him.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Cody is Mr. Wilson&rsquo;s favorite target for classroom antics. During a discussion on
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ralph_Waldo_Emerson">Ralph Waldo Emerson</a>&rsquo;s essay &ldquo;<a href="http://www.youmeworks.com/selfreliance.html">Self Reliance</a>,&rdquo; Mr. Wilson interjected,</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;&hellip;just like how O&#8217;Brien keeps saying that he&rsquo;ll ask out Livy, but he never does it!&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>to demonstrate the idea of how people should follow through on what they say.</p>

<p><div class='image left <a'><img  src="href="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TJfm-6jASqI/AAAAAAAAAq0/GNBHAslaEqU/s288/2.jpg">http://lh3.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TJfm-6jASqI/AAAAAAAAAq0/GNBHAslaEqU/s288/2.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;252&#8221; height=&#8221;314&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;This man had the balls to ask out Livy. Do you?&rdquo; &ldquo;Emerson&rdquo;&#8221; ><div class='caption'>&ldquo;This man had the balls to ask out Livy. Do you?&rdquo; &ldquo;Emerson&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>Cody&rsquo;s used to all the directed comments by now. The class was a <strong>breath of fresh air</strong> for him
and many others during a monotonous school day. For one hour they can enjoy entertainment, humor,
and uncertainty. In my math class, I overheard one kid say, &ldquo;I can&rsquo;t wait for Mr. Wilson&rsquo;s next
lesson about &rdquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annabel_Lee">Annabel Lee</a>!&ldquo; This kid was excited about the <strong>necrophilic</strong> imagery.</p>

<p>Phallic symbols are another popular topic for Mr. Wilson. &ldquo;Think about it, &lsquo;opening the doors&rsquo;,
&lsquo;coming in.&rsquo; Eww. That&rsquo;s almost graphic,&rdquo; he said while talking about <em><a href="http://etext.lib.virginia.edu/toc/modeng/public/Eaf135.html">The Scarlet Letter</a></em>.</p>

<p>High school can be a place deprived of entertainment, happiness, and color. But every so often a
teacher comes along who throws out the handbook and risks losing his job with comments the
administration considers &ldquo;inappropriate.&rdquo; He is, however, nothing less than a hero to his students.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back-to-School Cockout?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2009/09/back-to-school-cockout/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2009/09/back-to-school-cockout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My brother&rsquo;s school, <a href="http://www.wellesley.k12.ma.us/whs/WHS_HOME.HTM">Wellesley High</a>, recently invited students, family members, and teachers
to attend their annual &ldquo;Back-to-School Cockout.&rdquo;</p>

<p><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3447/3921542264_b0c4aa591f.jpg" title="Back-to-School Cockout" alt="Back-to-School Cockout" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
