<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-05-17T14:28:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Yorker Redesign]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2014/08/New-Yorker-Redesign/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2014/08/New-Yorker-Redesign</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>The New Yorker</em> recently redesigned their web site and made all articles free for a limited time.
Everything looks great except for that giant sticky header that takes up at least an inch of your
screen. I hope they get rid of it.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xap1/v/t1.0-9/10533444_10101414612546912_8361665153142220985_n.jpg?oh=ee288fe0748f8866836b4ddd6dd13ad5&amp;oe=547C0D89&amp;__gda__=1416912604_7a048a895f2b1729416f64fae8142c95">https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xap1/v/t1.0-9/10533444_10101414612546912_8361665153142220985_n.jpg?oh=ee288fe0748f8866836b4ddd6dd13ad5&amp;oe=547C0D89&amp;__gda__=1416912604_7a048a895f2b1729416f64fae8142c95</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;700&#8221; height=&#8221;378&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dieter Rams – Less but Better]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/04/dieter-rams-less-but-better/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/04/dieter-rams-less-but-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished reading the monograph <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0714849189/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0714849189"><em>Dieter Rams: As Little Design as Possible</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0714849189" alt="" />. The
book covers the life and work of the influential German industrial designer whose hundreds of
products are still manufactured and whose principles are still practiced.</p>

<p>This was my first introduction to Rams, but I recognized his work in the 606 Universal Shelving
System, Braun shavers, and the SK4 record player. These products were so successful they set the
standard design for whole classes of products to follow. For example, I&rsquo;ve never seen a record
player without a clear case.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dc/606-Universal-Shelving-System.jpg/640px-606-Universal-Shelving-System.jpg">https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dc/606-Universal-Shelving-System.jpg/640px-606-Universal-Shelving-System.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;540&#8221; height=&#8221;397&#8221; title=&#8221;606 Universal Shelving Sytem&#8221; ></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://www.iainclaridge.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/sk4_1.jpg">http://www.iainclaridge.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/sk4_1.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;470&#8221; height=&#8221;470&#8221; title=&#8221;SK4 record player&#8221; ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>As I read, I found myself agreeing with much of Rams&#8217; principles; some half-formed ideas I
couldn&rsquo;t yet articulate were crystallized by his words.</p>

<h2>Rams on Aesthetics</h2>

<p>Rams&#8217; tenet that resonated with me most was the idea that aesthetic beauty requires a certain
simplicity and humility. He disliked &ldquo;visual pollution&rdquo; and strived for calm and order:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>I wanted to clean up, to get rid of the chaos. But the chaos has got worse since then. Chaos
from products, noise, and pollution. We are not really in control of anything&hellip;We have too many
things. Our world is filled with too many products with superficial attractions and little or no
use.</p><footer><strong>Dieter Rams</strong> <cite>&ldquo;Ich Habe Einen Traum&rdquo; <em>Zeit Magazin Leben</em> No. 14</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<h2>On the Unsustainability of Rampant Consumerism</h2>

<p>Rams believed rampant consumerism couldn&rsquo;t be forever viable and stressed quality over quantity,
restraint over vanity, and environmental sustainability over ostentatious consumption. Even though
he worked within the system of capitalism and mass production, he didn&rsquo;t think his work and
beliefs were contradictory. Rams saw design as a motor for change, as a way to convince users to
buy fewer goods that, although more expensive, lasted longer. &ldquo;Weniger aber besser&rdquo; (less but
better), he&rsquo;d say.</p>

<p>He drew a distinction between <em>verbraucher</em> – one who consumes or uses things up – and
<em>gerbraucher</em> – one who makes use of something. I think of this as the difference between someone
who merely accepts input vs someone who leverages modern products to create something of value.</p>

<h2>On What Makes a Good Designer and Product</h2>

<p>A good designer can empathize with users, analyze their needs, and use appropriate media to create
a product that fulfills its intended use in an innovative way. Rams went so far as to say,
&ldquo;Indifference towards people and the reality in which they live is actually the one and only
cardinal sin in design.&rdquo; This reminds me of Linus Torvald&rsquo;s <a href="https://lkml.org/lkml/2012/3/8/495" title="Torvalds on Linux and users">sentiments</a> <a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=638477#c129" title="user doesn't care">on Linux</a>.</p>

<p>A good product is the result of designers&#8217; ability to anticipate the needs of the user.</p>

<blockquote><p>One has to get to know the use-reality of the product. One has to understand the wishes and
  expectations of the user. One must know the limitations of the technology and the production. One
  has to understand the market and understand what is best left alone and what would be plain fraud.</p></blockquote>

<h2>On the Role of Design Within a Company</h2>

<p>Rams believed that for a company to be product-driven, the emphasis must be supported across the
board not just the design department. This commitment brings profitable and lasting market
performance as well as innovation that creates entirely new markets. Can you spell A-p-p-l-e?</p>

<h2>Rams&#8217; House</h2>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://blog.iso50.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/p_dieter-hallway_1710371c-on-wanken-450x281.jpg">http://blog.iso50.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/p_dieter-hallway_1710371c-on-wanken-450x281.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;450&#8221; height=&#8221;281&#8221; title=&#8221;Dieter Rams house&#8221; ></p>

<p><blockquote><p>[The] composition of these rooms represents the basic intention behind my design: simplicity,
essentiality, and openness. The objects do not boast about themselves, take center stage or
restrict but withdraw into the background&hellip;In a world which is&hellip;destructively loud and visually
confusing, design&hellip;help[s] generate a level of calm that allows people to come to themselves.
(Lovell, 141)</p><footer><strong>Dieter Rams</strong> <cite>Lovell Page 141</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://www.wallpaper.com/galleryimages/17052483/gallery/dieter_ram_book_tl010611_06.jpg">http://www.wallpaper.com/galleryimages/17052483/gallery/dieter_ram_book_tl010611_06.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;540&#8221; height=&#8221;340&#8221; title=&#8221;dieter rams house&#8221; ></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01710/p_dieter-rams-hous_1710374c.jpg">http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01710/p_dieter-rams-hous_1710374c.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;460&#8221; height=&#8221;289&#8221; title=&#8221;dieter rams yard&#8221; ></p>

<h2>Rams&#8217; 15 Principles</h2>

<ol>
<li>The first question is not if one should be designing but how.</li>
<li>Is the product that we are designing really necessary? Are there not already other similar,
tried, and tested appliances that people have got used to and are good and functional? Is
innovation in this instance really necessary?</li>
<li>Will it really enrich people&rsquo;s lives or does it just appeal to their covetousness,
possessiveness, or idea of status? Or does it wake desire because it is offering something new?</li>
<li>Is it conceived for the short- or long-term, does it just help increase the speed of the cycle
of throwaway goods or does it help slow it down?</li>
<li>Can it be simply repaired or does it rely on an expensive customer service facility? Can it in
fact be repaired at all or is the whole appliance redundant when just one part of it breaks?</li>
<li>Does it exhibit fashionable and therefore aesthetically short-lived design elements?</li>
<li>Does it help people or incapacitate them? Does it make them more free or more dependent?</li>
<li>Is it so accomplished and perfect that it perhaps incapacitates or humiliates you?</li>
<li>Which previous human activity does it replace and can that really be called progress?</li>
<li>What possibility for change, what scope does the product offer people?</li>
<li>Can the product be used in other, perhaps playful, ways?</li>
<li>Does the product really offer convenience or does it encourage passivity?</li>
<li>What does the experience improvement look like in a broader context?</li>
<li>Does it make an action or act on the whole more complete or simpler, is it easy to operate or do
you have to learn how to use it?</li>
<li>Does it arouse curiosity and the imagination? Does it encourage desire to use it, understand it,
and even to change it?</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redesign]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/02/redesign/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/02/redesign</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished redesigning my site. It was a lot more work than I expected. After becoming
interested in <a href="http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2009/07/17/lessons-from-swiss-style-graphic-design/" title="Lessons From Swiss Style Graphic Design">Swiss design</a>, both philosophically and aesthetically, I was inspired by the
personal websites of Rdio and Django designer <a href="http://www.wilsonminer.com/" title="Wilson Miner's personal website">Wilson Miner</a>, former New York Times web
designer <a href="http://www.subtraction.com/" title="Khoi Vinh's personal website">Khoi Vinh</a>, and an <a href="http://www.rodrigogalindez.com/" title="Rodrigo Galindez's personal website">Argentinian designer</a>.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So I took elements from all three and combined them with my own tastes for minimalism, grids, and
readability. At first I was going to unabashedly copy Miner&rsquo;s site since I liked it so much. But
some of my friends said it was confusing at first glance. Although Miner&rsquo;s layout is beautiful, it
might through off short-attention-spanned web surfer who are used to conventional blog layouts.
And users who don&rsquo;t understand a site right away will bounce.</p>

<p>Compare <a href="http://themeshaper.com/thematic/guide/?page_id=16" title="Thematic demo site">old</a> vs new. I reduced the header&rsquo;s thickness and moved the navigation to the top. I
got rid of italicized font and cut down on meta-data displayed for each post. A few dark lines
also make it feel less white and empty.</p>

<p>I tried to implement this redesign with Django instead of WordPress for no reason other than
wanting to play with the Python-based framework. Bad idea. Although I finished the <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/intro/tutorial01/" title="Writing your first Django app part 1">Django app
walkthrough</a>, Django confused me with its project-app distinction, file hierarchy, and
templating system. Having done Rails and feeling like RoR just clicked for me, Django was a
frustrating experience. On top of that, live deployment on a LAMP stack was excruciating. Can
someone explain to me why Django deals with static and media assets in <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/howto/static-files/" title="Django Managing static files">this way</a>? <code>sudo
a2enmod mod_python</code>, right? But wait – I&rsquo;m <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/3319585/553994" title="Stack Overflow mod-wsgi-mod-python-or-just-cgi">supposed to use mod_wsgi</a>?</p>

<p>After making painstakingly slow progress over the course of a day, I gave up and came crawling
back to WordPress. Despite the <a href="http://kevinjohngallagher.com/2012/01/wordpress-has-left-the-building/" title="Wordpress has left the building">grumbling against it</a> and its security flaws (why put sensitive
files under the document root?), WordPress is used by so many sites ranging from <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2009/09/03/inside-peek-how-the-new-york-times-uses-blogs/" title="Inside peek: How The New York Times uses blogs">The New York
Times</a> to <a href="https://tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/wp-login.php" title="TechCrunch WordPress login">TechCrunch</a> because of a single overwhelming reason: <strong>it just works</strong>.
Five-minute installation, production-hardened, no-sysadmin-required.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been using the <a href="http://themeshaper.com/thematic/" title="Thematic, A WordPress Theme Framework">Thematic theme</a> for a long time now. I love it&rsquo;s clean and simple design,
but I wanted to fine-tune it. Unfortunately, I had to spend a couple of days extensively modifying
the theme&rsquo;s core code. I tried to do it with a child theme and <a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/Plugin_API#Hooks.2C_Actions_and_Filters" title="Wordpress Hooks, Actions and Filters">hooks, actions, and filters</a>,
but it became ugly fast. So I just duplicated the theme and directly messed with it. The downside
is this theme cannot be shipped; the upside is that it&rsquo;s truly unique to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Sticking With WordPress' Thematic Theme]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/10/im-sticking-with-wordpress-thematic-theme/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/10/im-sticking-with-wordpress-thematic-theme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m going to keep my Thematic WordPress theme. Nothing beats its simplicity and minimalism. It&rsquo;s
so crisp and clean. I don&rsquo;t put up many photos or non-textual media, and Thematic lets readers
focus on the writing. I just can&rsquo;t find anything I like better.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to thank Ian Stewart for Thematic, which you can download <a href="http://themeshaper.com/">here</a>. I&rsquo;ve modified
Thematic on both my blog and my homepage by setting up a child theme that inherits properties of
its parent.</p>

<p>Child themes allow you to tweak the design and look of your WordPress blog by overriding the
properties the parent theme sets up. So why would you want to do this instead of directly altering
the parent? If your theme is updated and you download that update, all your modifications will be
erased. But if you have a child theme, they&rsquo;ll be preserved since they&rsquo;re in a separate file.</p>

<p>Here are some <a href="http://op111.net/53">good </a><a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/Child_Themes">places </a>to learn about creating your own WordPress child theme.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sexy Audio Plugin, Oh So Sexy]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/06/sexy-audio-plugin-oh-so-sexy/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/06/sexy-audio-plugin-oh-so-sexy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve just updated my WordPress audio plugin. The only time I&rsquo;ve ever used it was for <a href="/2009/06/cantonese-pick-up-lines" title="Cantonese pickup lines">this
post</a> on Cantonese pick-up lines. This is one of my most popular posts that always brings in a
steady trickle of horny expats who&rsquo;ve just found out their firm is relocating them to Hong Kong.
&ldquo;Quick! How do you say, &lsquo;Your place or mine?&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So click back to my <a href="/2009/06/cantonese-pick-up-lines" title="Cantonese pickup lines">old post</a>. Play with the embedded player. Notice it&rsquo;s sleek design. It&rsquo;s
slick sliding animation. That loading bar, that countdown timer. Sexy. Oh, so sexy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
