<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-02-05T17:11:23-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Upstream Kubernetes Java Models Is Much Better Than Raw YAML]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2018/11/using-upstream-kubernetes-java-models-is-much-better-than-raw-yaml/"/>
    <updated>2018-11-11T17:11:38-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2018/11/using-upstream-kubernetes-java-models-is-much-better-than-raw-yaml</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I blogged about something tech related, but I had some
free time today.</p>

<p>Recently, I&rsquo;ve been trying to refactor an internal Spotify deployment tool my
team built and maintains. This deployment tool takes Kubernetes (k8s) YAML
manifests, changes them, and essentially runs <code>kubectl apply</code>. We add metadata
to the k8s manifests like labels.</p>

<p>Right now this tool receives the input YAML as strings, converts them to
Jackson ObjectNodes, and manipulates those ObjectNodes. The disadvantage of
this is that there&rsquo;s no k8s type-safety. We might accidentally add a field to a
Deployment that isn&rsquo;t valid or remove something from a Service that&rsquo;s required.</p>

<p>My refactor uses upstream k8s model classes from <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-client/java">kubernetes-client/java</a>
which are themselves <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-client/gen">generated</a> from the official Swagger spec. Here&rsquo;s a
helpful Yaml utility class that deserializes YAML strings into concrete classes
and can also serialize them back into YAML strings. So helpful.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, there&rsquo;s some bugs in the YAML (de)serialization that prevent me
from finishing this effort.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-client/java/pull/417">kubernetes-client/java issue 417</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-client/java/issues/431">kubernetes-client/java issue 431</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-client/java/issues/340">kubernetes-client/java issue 340</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Nonetheless, it&rsquo;ll be much nicer to change k8s resources in a type-safe way
instead of parsing and rewriting raw YAML strings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet Meme Role Models]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2018/01/internet-meme-role-models/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-07T11:29:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2018/01/internet-meme-role-models</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m compiling a list of Internet meme role models. Here&rsquo;s what I have so far. These people &mdash;
they must be real human beings &mdash; must have either gone out of their way to do the right
thing in a smart manner, something courageous with bonus points for being funny, or just be
ridiculous. And they must be memeified. Exceptions will be made for exceptional but not
memeified people like Hilde Lysiak.</p>

<p>Who else deserves to be on this list?</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b58mzz7mQpg">Snack Man</a> defused a violent fight on the subway between a couple before anyone got hurt. He did
it by standing in between them and munching on Pringles and Gummy Bears.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m9Md78SJO6s">Ben Innes</a> asked the EgyptAir Flight 181 hijacker who comandeered the airplane with a fake
explosive belt if he could take a selfie with him. &ldquo;I thought, why not? If he blows us all up it
won&rsquo;t matter anyway.&rdquo;</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/31/books/hilde-lysiak-child-reporter.html">Hilde Lysiak</a> is ten years old and the writer and publisher of Orange Street News.
She <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ShfNQOUeAY">doesn&rsquo;t take shit from anyone</a>.</li>
<li>Salt Bae is&hellip;well you just have to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xWMWJwXvzWk&amp;t=376s">see for yourself</a>.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Max Knows How to Make a Latte]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/08/now-max-knows-how-to-make-a-latte/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-30T01:19:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/08/now-max-knows-how-to-make-a-latte</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I work at a music company but am more interested in politics and history. Artists visit our
office often.</p>

<p>So I, often being ignorant of their fame, have casually interacted with them or criticized their
milk steaming techniques when they&rsquo;re using the office&rsquo;s $20K espresso machine.</p>

<p>Only later am I told by their posse, &ldquo;Did you know that was Mark Ronson/Bebe Rhexa/Max Martin/etc?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s OK,&rdquo; I say. &ldquo;Now Max knows how to make a real latte.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Dumplings With My Grandparents]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/07/making-dumplings-with-my-grandparents/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-05T22:50:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/07/making-dumplings-with-my-grandparents</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whenever I go back home to my parents&#8217; house near Boston,
if my maternal grandparents are there, they make hundreds of dumplings for me.
I try to help out. We make everything from scratch including the skins. I&rsquo;m good at rolling the
skins but have much to learn on all other parts of the process. I&rsquo;m becoming better at packing
and closing the dumplings now though.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve come to cherish this little tradition more and more. I need to plan my next trip to Boston!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/FkpZb8Jh.jpg"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/InwCZuBh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/bT9F8neh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/qMkalGoh.jpg"></p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/shNvpsrlaF0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Fascinating and Weird People]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/06/four-fascinating-and-weird-people/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-01T06:36:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/06/four-fascinating-and-weird-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are the stories of four fascinating and weird people that will make you laugh, be inspired,
or cringe. Chang and Eng Bunker were conjoined twins who married two sisters and were slave-owners
on the side of the Southern Confederacy. Rose Wilder Lane is the daughter of the author who wrote
the <em>Little House</em> childrens books, a founding member of the American Libertarian movement, and just
all around boss ass bitch. John Harvey Kellogg was the inventor of corn flakes, doctor, zealous
anti-masturbation campaigner, and eugenicist.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>1. Chang and Eng Bunker</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chang_and_Eng_Bunker">Chang and Eng</a> were two conjoined twins born
in Vietnam in the 1800s. The term &ldquo;Siamese twins&rdquo; is based on them.</p>

<blockquote><p>The brothers were joined at the sternum by a small piece of cartilage, and though their livers
  were fused, they were independently complete.</p></blockquote>

<p>After a Scotsman noticed them and paraded them around as a freak show attraction for ten
years, the Bunker twins settled down in Wilkesboro, North Carolina. They married two local white
women who were sisters. They became naturalized American citizens and even owned slaves.</p>

<p>The Bunkers and their wives slept in a bed built for four. After a while their wives started to not
get along. So they alternated between two different houses. Chang had twelve children while
Eng had ten. Today their descendents number more than 1,500 and hold reunions. Their liver is on
display in at the Mütter Museum in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>

<h2>2. Rose Wilder Lane</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane">Rose Wilder Lane</a> was the eldest child of Laura
Ingalls Wilder, the ostensible author of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Little_House_on_the_Prairie_books">Little House book series</a>.
Lane was by all means a boss ass bitch who lived a full life.</p>

<p>Sick of crop failures and tough frontier life, Lane moved in 1908 to San Francisco, California.
She married a salesman named Gillette Lane and became pregnant. Sadly, her son was stillborn, and
a subsequent surgery left her unable to have kids.</p>

<blockquote><p>She felt her intellectual interests did not mesh with the life she was living with her husband.
Keenly aware of her lack of a formal education, during these years, Lane read voraciously and
taught herself several languages. Her writing career began around 1908, with occasional
freelance newspaper jobs that earned much-needed extra cash.</p><footer><strong>Early career, marriage and divorce</strong> <cite><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Early_career.2C_marriage_and_divorce'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Lane&rsquo;s writing career took off. She wrote for publications like <em>Harper&rsquo;s</em> and <em>Saturday Evening
Post</em>.</p>

<blockquote><p>In the late 1920s, Lane was reputed to be one of the highest-paid female writers in America, and
along with Hoover, she counted among her friends well known figures such as Sinclair Lewis,
Isabel Paterson, Dorothy Thompson, John Patric, and Lowell Thomas.</p><footer><strong>Freelance writing career</strong> <cite><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Freelance_writing_career'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>When Lane&rsquo;s mother approached her with a rough autobiographical manuscript of her own childhood,
Lane sensed that an American public fatigued by the Great Depression would take to the story of
the loving, persistent, and independent Ingalls family. Lane encouraged and helped her mother
rewrite and sell the story as a children&rsquo;s novel. The book became a big success, and an entire
series replete with T.V. shows, merchandise, and museums followed. Their family was raking
in the dough.</p>

<p>I read the entire series as a kid and stil wax nostalgic for it. I thought Lane&rsquo;s mother, who&rsquo;s the
titled author, wrote every book on her own and only received encouragement from her Lane. It turns
out, however, that the truth is more interesting.</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8230;an ongoing mutual collaboration that involved Lane more extensively in the
earlier books, and to a much lesser extent by the time the series ended, as Wilder&#8217;s confidence
in her own writing ability increased. Lane insisted to the end that her role was little more than
that of her mother&#8217;s adviser, despite documentation to the contrary&#8230;Literary historians
believe that Lane&#8217;s editing skills brought the dramatic pacing, literary structure, and
characterization critically needed to make the stories publishable in book form.</p><footer><strong>Literary collaboration</strong> <cite><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Literary_collaboration'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Even more fascinating is Lane&rsquo;s societal and political views. She was a libertarian, economically
laissez faire, anti-racist, and anti-communist. She protested paying income taxes, opposed the New
Deal, and thought Social Security was a Ponzi scheme that would destroy the United States.</p>

<blockquote><p>Lane played a hands-on role during the 1940s and 1950s in launching the &#8220;libertarian movement&#8221;
and began an extensive correspondence with figures such as DuPont executive Jasper Crane and
writer Frank Meyer, as well as her friend and colleague, Ayn Rand. She wrote book reviews
for the National Economic Council and later for the Volker Fund, out of which grew the Institute
for Humane Studies. Later, she lectured at, and gave generous financial support to, the Freedom
School headed by libertarian Robert LeFevre.</p><footer><strong>Later years and death</strong> <cite><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Later_years_and_death'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I want to reread the <em>Little House</em> books now knowing she was a die-hard libertarian who along with
her mother purposefully wove themes of individualism into the series.</p>

<blockquote><p>Rose Wilder Lane died in her sleep at age 81, on October 30, 1968, just as she was about to
depart on a three-year world tour. She was buried next to her parents at Mansfield Cemetery in
Mansfield, Missouri.</p><footer><strong>Later years and death</strong> <cite><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Later_years_and_death'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<h2>3. John Harvey Kellogg</h2>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t read the entire Wikipedia entry on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Harvey_Kellogg">John Harvey Kellogg</a> yet since
a colleague only recently drew my attention to this smart, prolific, and bizarre man. These parts
stood out to me at first glance though.</p>

<ul>
<li>he invented corn flakes with his brother, Will Keith Kellogg</li>
<li>he was a medical doctor &ldquo;who ran a sanitarium using holistic methods, with a particular focus on
nutrition, enemas, and exercise. Kellogg was an advocate of vegetarianism&rdquo;</li>
<li>he also created various phototherapeutic and electrotherapeutic inventions</li>
<li>he advocated sexual abstinence and &ldquo;advocated keeping the diet plain to prevent sexual arousal&rdquo;</li>
<li>he was an &ldquo;especially zealous campaigner against masturbation&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>He also recommended, to prevent children from this &#8220;solitary vice&#8221;, bandaging or tying their hands,
covering their genitals with patented cages and electrical shock.</p><footer><strong>Masturbation prevention</strong> <cite><a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Harvey_Kellogg#Masturbation_prevention'>en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<ul>
<li>he liked yogurt enemas</li>
<li>he was a eugenicist</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Site for TLS Server Test]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/05/useful-site-for-testing-tls-server-configuration/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-20T12:49:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/05/useful-site-for-testing-tls-server-configuration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My home server&rsquo;s hard disk&rsquo;s partition map was somehow corrupted. So I&rsquo;m serving this website
from <a href="https://m.do.co/c/74c553045962">Digital Ocean</a> for now instead of my apartment. While rewriting the nginx server configs,
I found this useful site that <a href="https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/index.html">tests your server&rsquo;s TLS configuration</a>. It&rsquo;ll give you a grade
and warn you of weak encryption, key exchange protocols, cipher suites, etc.</p>

<p><a href="https://mozilla.github.io/server-side-tls/ssl-config-generator/">Mozilla&rsquo;s TLS configuration generator</a> is useful for providing secure defaults.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m proud to say this site has an A.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[British Virgin Islands Sailing Trip Video]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/05/british-virgin-islands-sailing-trip-video/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-20T11:51:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/05/british-virgin-islands-sailing-trip-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally got around to editing the footage from the sailing trip.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7ZaCY7rHLgg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[British Virgin Islands Sailing Trip]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/03/british-virgin-islands-sailing-trip/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-03T21:10:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/03/british-virgin-islands-sailing-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learned the basics of sailing on a week-long sailing trip in the British Virgin Islands aboard
a 48-foot catamaran we called Millenium Falcon.</p>

<h3>January 30</h3>

<p>We moored off the coast of Virgin Gorda and Saba Rock. President Obama was wind surfing at neighboring Necker Island as a guest of Richard Branson.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/xtJYYezh.jpg"></p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/WY4BnbMh.jpg" title="The dinghy race at Virgin Gorda." ><div class='caption'>The dinghy race at Virgin Gorda.</div></div>




<!-- more -->


<h3>January 31</h3>

<p>Anegada</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/eZ8wlJjh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/8BhieRQh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/Z9eqNS4h.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/vGEIw30h.jpg"></p>

<h3>Last day - February 4</h3>

<p>Sailing through Tatch Island Cut during the race. We stopped racing because the wind died
and we needed to return the charter boat on time.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/rOfYB1Uh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/qofwLFhh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/3VJRFjHh.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/rfuiRe4h.jpg"></p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/IOXPlZxh.jpg" title="Boat mate and colleague Bastian." ><div class='caption'>Boat mate and colleague Bastian.</div></div>




<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/VcsIgQAh.jpg" title="The rest of my boat's crew." ><div class='caption'>The rest of my boat&#8217;s crew.</div></div>




<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/62Prw81h.jpg" title="We saw lots of nice houses built on cliffs." ><div class='caption'>We saw lots of nice houses built on cliffs.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Test Your Home's Water for Lead]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/02/how-to-test-your-homes-water-for-lead/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-20T19:37:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/02/how-to-test-your-homes-water-for-lead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read the <em>New York Times</em> article <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/03/24/nyregion/how-nyc-gets-its-water-new-york-101.html">&ldquo;How New York Gets Its Water&rdquo;</a> a while ago. The end of the
article described how you could order a free lead testing kit.</p>

<blockquote><p>The <a href="https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2015-11/documents/2005_09_14_faq_fs_homewatertesting.pdf">EPA offers some guidance</a> on how and when to obtain an in-home testing kit through your local
water supplier. In New York City, residents can obtain one <a href="http://www1.nyc.gov/nyc-resources/service/1266/water-lead-test-kit-request">at no cost through 311</a>.</p>

<p>For more information, visit <a href="www.epa.gov/safewater/lead">www.epa.gov/safewater/lead</a>, or call the Safe Drinking Water Hotline
at 1-800-426-4791.</p></blockquote>

<p>I read this article in the aftermath of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flint_water_crisis">Flint water crisis</a> and wanted to test my
apartment&rsquo;s drinking water. I filled out the online form, received a package in the mail containing
two large plastic bottles, a pre-paid mailing label, and detailed instructions. The instructions
said to fill one bottle with water after not using any faucet in my apartment for six hours. I
filled the second bottle with water after having run the tap. After dropping the bottles now full
of water into a mailbox, NYC&rsquo;s Nureau of Water Supply sent me the results only week or so later.</p>

<blockquote><p>We have received the results of your recent tap water lead test. Both samples were under the
federal action level of 15 micrograms per liter (μg/L). Your specific results were:</p>

<p>First draw: 0 μg/L
1-2 minute flush: 0 μg/L</p></blockquote>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/uxwBi0bl.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/98MoXGNl.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I'm Looking for in a Volunteering Position]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/10/what-im-looking-for-in-a-volunteering-position/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-31T13:59:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/10/what-im-looking-for-in-a-volunteering-position</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>My Absolute Requirements</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Does not require a law degree</strong>

<ul>
<li>Although I have thought about getting one just so I can apply for certain volunteering gigs that require one.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Does not require me to write code</strong> for a significant portion of my volunteer time. I already do
that full time and am not looking for more. I am fine giving high level tech guidance, however.</li>
</ul>


<h2>My Preferences</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>in-person and local</li>
<li>intellectually challenging</li>
<li>accommodating of my full time work schedule and personal life</li>
<li>5-10 hours a week</li>
<li>months-long to year-long commitment</li>
<li>not just a desk job but also field work</li>
</ul>


<h2>Skills I Want to Learn or Improve Upon</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>public speaking</li>
<li>community organizing and building trust with people who have different backgrounds</li>
<li>negotiating and building consensus with and between people who don&rsquo;t necessarily see eye-to-eye</li>
<li>Learning to lobby public officials and organizations</li>
<li>learning more about the law or government or various industries</li>
<li>investigative reporting</li>
</ul>


<h2>Values of Organizations in which I&rsquo;ll Thrive</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>competence</li>
<li>hard work</li>
<li>innovation or at least open-mindedness</li>
<li>passion and compassion</li>
<li>personal responsibility</li>
</ul>


<h2>Skills I Can Contribute</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of ability</em></p>

<ul>
<li>writing code, creating web sites, general computer stuff (see my <a href="https://github.com/davidxia">github</a>)</li>
<li>writing prose such as reports, summaries, and essays (see my <a href="https://www.davidxia.com/">blog</a>)</li>
<li>analytical and quantitative (I was a math major in college. Now I work at Spotify as a software
engineer.)</li>
<li>effective at collaborating and working as part of a team</li>
<li>good at spoken communication</li>
<li>has a knack for establishing rapport and building strong relationships with all kinds of people</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<h2>Causes I Believe In</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>civil rights

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;protect individuals&#8217; freedom from infringement by governments, social organizations, and
private individuals. They ensure one&rsquo;s ability to participate in the civil and political life
of the society and state without discrimination or repression&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Environmentalism">environmentalism</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;advocate for the lawful preservation, restoration and/or improvement of the natural
environment&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;attempt to balance relations between humans and the various natural systems on which they
depend in such a way that all the components are accorded a proper degree of sustainability&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Consumer_protection">consumer protection</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;promoting laws and organizations that ensure the rights of consumers as well as fair trade,
competition and accurate information in the marketplace. The laws are designed to prevent
businesses that engage in fraud or specified unfair practices from gaining an advantage over
competitors&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nypirg.org/goodgov/">good governance</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;advocate for eliminating barriers to voting, fighting for better ethics oversight and limiting
the role of powerful interests in elections,&rdquo; etc</li>
<li>examples include making &ldquo;campaign finance information for state and local candidates&rdquo;
available on the Internet, reporting &ldquo;lobbying of state agencies and local governments&rdquo;,
deterring and justly punishing ethical misconduct, and making legislative and budgetary
processes more transparent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labor_rights">labor rights</a>

<ul>
<li>advocating for &ldquo;legal rights and claimed human rights having to do with labor relations
between workers and their employers, usually obtained under labor and employment law. In
general, these rights&#8217; debates have to do with negotiating workers&#8217; pay, benefits, and safe
working conditions&rdquo;</li>
<li>e.g. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/24/business/graduate-students-clear-hurdle-in-effort-to-form-union.html">Grad Students Win Right to Unionize in an Ivy League Case</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community_organizing">community organizing</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;community organizers generally assume that social change necessarily involves conflict and
social struggle in order to generate collective power for the powerless. A core goal of
community organizing is to generate durable power for an organization representing the
community, allowing it to influence key decision-makers on a range of issues over time&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community_development#Definitions">community development</a></li>
<li>Education</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Recent Family Photo]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/09/a-recent-family-photo/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-18T18:29:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/09/a-recent-family-photo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/mwtquEjl.jpg" width="640" height="640" title="Post-dimsum photo with my parents and maternal grandparents on their weekend visit to NYC." ><div class='caption'>Post-dimsum photo with my parents and maternal grandparents on their weekend visit to NYC.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southern UK 2016]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/southern-uk-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-24T18:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/southern-uk-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My trip with my parents to southern UK in March this year. The video includes highlights from
London, Cambridge, Seven Sisters, Jurassic Coast, Lyme Regis, and Lulworth Cove.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/seJO_6-Tk2Q?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Sailing Class]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-sailing-class/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-24T13:37:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-sailing-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend a bunch of Spotify collleagues and I took our first sailing classes at Manhattan Yacht
Club in Jersey City. I could get used to this sport. The sun was brutal though. I&rsquo;ll never get used
to that.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8hPEr4sa-YM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/g6jwSpXl.jpg" width="480" height="640"></p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/rbyvOtml.jpg" width="480" height="640" title="I had to wear a hot and stuffy life vest on a 90-degree day." ><div class='caption'>I had to wear a hot and stuffy life vest on a 90-degree day.</div></div>




<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/5cHxUtKl.jpg" width="480" height="640" title="A great view of lower Manhattan." ><div class='caption'>A great view of lower Manhattan.</div></div>




<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/ivnVCYXl.jpg" width="480" height="640" title="Sailing close to the Statue of Liberty." ><div class='caption'>Sailing close to the Statue of Liberty.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify-organized Surfing Trip in Santa Teresa, Costa Rica 2015]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/spotify-organized-surfing-trip-in-costa-rica-2015/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-09T10:13:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/spotify-organized-surfing-trip-in-costa-rica-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In March 2015, about twenty colleagues and I went on a Spotify-organized surf trip to Santa Teresa,
Costa Rica for a week of surf lessons. The company, surf, and food were unforgettable. One of Spotify&rsquo;s
social events organizers knew <a href="www.surfakademin.se">a group of traveling Swedish surf instructors</a>,
and helped get a group discount for Spotifiers and their guests. The total cost of lodging, lessons,
and daily breakfast and lunch was about $650 for a week.</p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/WvJyqW4l.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="The relaxing mini-resort where we stayed. It had a pool, lounge areas, and a small cafe." ><div class='caption'>The relaxing mini-resort where we stayed. It had a pool, lounge areas, and a small cafe.</div></div>


<p>The best memories I have from the trip are waking up at the crack of dawn every day, grabbing a
surf board, and rushing headlong into the water. The sun was gentle in the early morning, but the
waves were not. The force and speed of the ocean awed and at times terrified me. I&rsquo;d paddle like mad
to get over waves, but every once in a while, a monster swell would catch me at the worst moment.
The crest of the wave would hit me like a hammer and sweep me aside like a match stick. I was taught
to cover my head with my arms to prevent the surf board from giving me a concussion.
Eventually I learned to do a turtle roll and was able to see a bit ahead of time if a wave would be
large or small.</p>

<!--more-->




<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/Lj4BEIel.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="The large suite in which I lived with my two non-Spotify friends I invited: Grace Gui and Jason Alarcon." ><div class='caption'>The large suite in which I lived with my two non-Spotify friends I invited: Grace Gui and Jason Alarcon.</div></div>


<p>After a couple of hours of surfing on an empty stomach, I would be ravenous. Our group would trudge
back to the resort where several Costa Rican women staff members had prepared a large
breakfast for us: scrambled eggs, watermelon and pineapple,
salad, rice and beans, and plantains. I&rsquo;d go back for seconds and thirds.</p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/QQ2zrxil.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="From left to right: Mo Tracey, Fredrik Johansson, Chris Hansen, Jeffrey Foster, David Xia, and Grace Gui." ><div class='caption'>From left to right: Mo Tracey, Fredrik Johansson, Chris Hansen, Jeffrey Foster, David Xia, and Grace Gui.</div></div>


<p>One of my colleagues Fredrik and I were pretty good beginners and had the privilege of being invited
by the instructors to a different beach at least an hour&rsquo;s drive away from the
resort. Fredrik and I rode in a taxi with one of the instructors and two other guests who were
seasoned surfers. The ride through dirt and gravel roads was bumpy and hot and all around unpleasant.
A sandless beach awaited us when we arrived. I lathered on sunscreen to protect against the intense
midday sun, took my board, and carefully walked across the seemingly endless stretch of sharp rocks
until I could mount my board and start paddling. After an hour of surfing, I remember being
exhausted but extremely grateful that I was lucky enough to experience the raw power of mother
nature in such a majestic setting. I was also extremely grateful I hadn&rsquo;t been injured so far on the
trip. The waves could be truly terrifying.</p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/dBL3Hw0l.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="I guess I couldn't keep my balance." ><div class='caption'>I guess I couldn&#8217;t keep my balance.</div></div>


<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/EExUThOl.jpg" width="480" height="640" title="I can't remember what we were trying to do in the pool." ><div class='caption'>I can&#8217;t remember what we were trying to do in the pool.</div></div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Open Water Swimming Event]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-open-water-swimming-event/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-08T22:51:51-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-open-water-swimming-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I visited the southern UK with my parents last March. We visited the coast where I took a photo of the
English Channel and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/davidxia2/posts/10102320113525692">posted it on Facebook</a> with the caption,
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m looking across the English Channel now wondering if I have what it takes to swim across to
France. It&rsquo;s 21 miles across at its narrowest point and the fastest swimmer made it across in a
little over seven hours and the slowest one was 27 hours. Average water temperatures in the summer
are 14-18 degrees Celsius.&rdquo;</p>

<p>My high school swim coach Jen saw it and said, &ldquo;If you are seriously considering, let me know &mdash; I
have many friends who have done this swim (yes I hang out with weirdos)!&rdquo;. Let&rsquo;s start with
something a bit more realistic I said. Jen encouraged me to participate in the annual Wayland Three
Mile Swim which she organizes. The race takes place in Lake Cochituate, a small body of water in
Wayland, Massachusetts which borders my hometown of Wellesley.</p>

<p>So I <a href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/when-routine-becomes-ritual/">trained religiously</a> for three months. A couple of days before June 19,
I took a bus from New York City back to Wellesley for the open water swim that would start at
7:30AM.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>My parents were very supportive of my endeavor and even woke up with me at 5AM to come watch.
We drove fifteen minutes to Wayland Town Beach. I met and hugged Jen and my other high school coach
Sandy both of whom I haven&rsquo;t seen in many years. We waited for a boat to setup the large
neon-colored, inflatable buoys in the lake.</p>

<p>There were twenty swimmers registered for the three mile race. I didn&rsquo;t have any expectations for
myself. I never swam continuously for such a long distance before (I was a sprinter in high school),
so my base goal was to simply finish within two hours, the maximum time allowed.</p>

<p>Summary:</p>

<ol>
<li>I did better than I thought I would. <a href="http://www.coolrunning.com/results/16/ma/Jun19_Waylan_set6.shtml">1 hour and 30 minutes.</a></li>
<li>I had my ass handed to me by 50-year-old men and teenage girls.
(Jeff Naylor, age 57, came in second place with a time of 1:05:21. Jeff, what are you on?
&#35;lifegoals)</li>
<li>I&rsquo;d definitely do it again. The water and weather were perfect. The lake tasted great.
I know because I drank half of it.</li>
</ol>


<p>Here are some photos.</p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/afzPLf7l.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="I pose for a photo after finishing the swim. Everything is sore." ><div class='caption'>I pose for a photo after finishing the swim. Everything is sore.</div></div>


<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/prSXIsel.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="Moments before the race begins. Jeff Naylor is on my left and Sandy Smith on my right." ><div class='caption'>Moments before the race begins. Jeff Naylor is on my left and Sandy Smith on my right.</div></div>


<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/Ifoh58ll.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="That's me and my kayak escort Spencer, Jen's son. I'm lucky he volunteered. I don't know who I would've had escort me otherwise." ><div class='caption'>That&#8217;s me and my kayak escort Spencer, Jen&#8217;s son. I&#8217;m lucky he volunteered. I don&#8217;t know who I would&#8217;ve had escort me otherwise.</div></div>


<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/8w3OgzLl.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="Another photo of right before the start." ><div class='caption'>Another photo of right before the start.</div></div>


<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/KOXM9t4l.jpg" width="583" height="470" title="Three mile race results." ><div class='caption'>Three mile race results.</div></div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My QCon NYC 2016 Slides - Reach Production Faster With Containers in Testing]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-20T17:15:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are the slides from my <a href="https://qconnewyork.com/ny2016/presentation/reaching-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing">QCon NYC 2016 talk titled &ldquo;Reach Production Faster with Containers in
Testing.&rdquo;</a> in various formats. <span xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" property="dct:title">All formats of &ldquo;Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing&rdquo;</span> by <a xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/ns#" href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides-reach-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing/" property="cc:attributionName" rel="cc:attributionURL">David Xia</a> are licensed under a <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</a>.</p>

<iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/p1uEfRmocwplbk" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen> </iframe>


<p> <div style="margin-bottom:5px"> <strong> <a href="//www.slideshare.net/DavidXia/qcon-nyc-2016-reach-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing" title="QCon NYC 2016: Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing" target="_blank">QCon NYC 2016: Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="//www.slideshare.net/DavidXia" target="_blank">David Xia</a></strong> </div></p>

<p>More formats here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkSloyT3gxalRuYjQ/view?usp=sharing">PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkSm9BVW5uWFR5TFk/view?usp=sharing">Keynote</a></li>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkRkpQWk5paUZOUW8/view?usp=sharing">PowerPoint</a></li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/w0P47Ugl.jpg" width="640" height="619"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Strange Swimming Experiences]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-strange-swimming-experiences/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-18T14:14:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-strange-swimming-experiences</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve had some strange swimming experiences.</p>

<p>In 2012 I vacationed on a tiny cay in Belize with a group of college friends.
The island was so small that its surface area was probably equal to that of a  medium-sized suburban
house. An even smaller cay lay a quarter of a mile away with nothing but white sand, coral
reefs, and pristine blue water separating them. One day I decided to swim to the smaller island
and back. I wore a long-sleeved shirt and pants to not get sunburned and waded into the water with
my snorkel mask. I carefully made my way around the sharp corals near the island. Once the water
became deep enough, I was surrounded by nothing but deep blue water.
I couldn&rsquo;t see the bottom or any distinguishable shapes in the ocean.</p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://i.imgur.com/LDg8qfd.jpg" width="640" height="322" title="Photo by Todd Quackenbush is licensed under CC BY-NC-SA 3.0" ><div class='caption'>Photo by Todd Quackenbush is licensed under CC BY-NC-SA 3.0</div></div>


<p>I started seeing ghostly shapes swimming around me. I was scared because I
wasn&rsquo;t sure if I was seeing large fish or if my eyes were just playing tricks on me.
I had seen barricudas, rays, and sharks in the water on previous days. I kept swimming. By now I
was halfway to the other island. After about 20 minutes I reached shore.
The ocean&rsquo;s depths and creatures made me feel naked and vulnerable and at times like I
was going crazy. But I stuck it out and felt strangely triumphant afterwards.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D-Ii7pKSEkQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I was six and attending summer camp. The counselors occasionally took us to the Evelyn Kirrane Aquatics
Center in Brookline, Massachusetts. One day I stepped into the deep-end of a pool without knowing
and began to panic. I tried screaming but couldn&rsquo;t get my mouth out of the water long enough to
take a breath and exhale. I started gulping a lot of water. Luckily, it was a small pool, and I
eventually made my way to the wall. I was surprised, however, that I couldn&rsquo;t signal for help and
that no one seemed to notice my distress. Later in life I learned it&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.ribride.co.uk/blog/drowning-does-not-look-like-drowning/" title="A Drowning Person Does Not Look Like a Drowning Person">difficult for an untrained
person to notice that someone is drowning</a>. Many small children drown each year just a short
distance away from their parents.</p>

<p>I lap swim regularly at the Chelsea Recreation Center. Multiple swimmers share a single lane by
swimming counter-clockwise. One day, another swimmer was swimming towards me in the opposite direction.
According to the rules, we each stuck to our respective right-hand sides. He must&rsquo;ve been a large
person because his wake was bigger than I&rsquo;m used to. I tilted my head to the side and took a breath
just as his wake hit me. Water unexpectedly entered my mouth and nose. I was surprised by how my
brain went into auto-pilot emergency mode. I tensed up and began to flail involuntarily.
The water and lack of breath was a strong signal to my brain that overrode everything else.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confessions of a Noob Landlord IV - How to Buy a Co-op Unit]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-15T06:57:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a story of I jumped through countless complex bureaucratic, legal, and financial hurdles of
Murphy&rsquo;s Law and emerged with less liquidity and more debt. OK. I&rsquo;m being facetious, but what
happened to me is the easiest and most straightforward way to buy a property. Seriously.
The events below transpired in New York City. The buying process may be different in other areas,
but the most of the process such as contract of sale and mortgage application is the same across
the U.S.</em></p>

<div class='image center'><img  src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG" width="640" height="772" title="By RKO radio pictures (eBay item photo front photo back) [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons. Promotional photo of Cary Grant and Myrna Loy for the film Mr. Blandings Builds His Dream House (1948)" ><div class='caption'>By RKO radio pictures (eBay item photo front photo back) [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons. Promotional photo of Cary Grant and Myrna Loy for the film Mr. Blandings Builds His Dream House (1948)</div></div>


<ul>
<li>My mother found an affordable co-op unit for sale while browsing StreetEasy on her iPad
during Christmas vacation in 2015.</li>
<li>We noticed the listing was made by the seller himself. I emailed him that night.</li>
<li>The seller promptly called me. I scheduled a viewing of the unit which is at the top
of a six-floor walk-up.</li>
<li>My parents and I climbed the six flights of stairs and met the seller who was a nice man named
Alan. We walked around and inspected his unit.</li>
<li>We asked Alan about the apartment&rsquo;s condition, the co-op&rsquo;s financials and rules, the property
manager, etc.</li>
<li>We sat down with Alan, chatted, and negotiated. My mother pointed out neither party has a broker
which is good because brokers take a 6% commission. We felt out Alan on how many offers he&rsquo;s
received and what they are.</li>
<li>My mother verbally offered Alan 94% of the listing price. He said he&rsquo;ll see. My mom seemed
confident he&rsquo;d take it. I was impressed by her ability to knock off over $20K right off the bat.</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>My parents and I started looking for a mortgage broker and an attorney who&rsquo;s good with co-op
purchases. (They were professional and competent. Contact me if you want a referral.)</li>
<li>We decided how much money we wanted to borrow and how long. I settled on a 15-year mortgage at a
great interest rate of 2.875%. I minimized closing and discount points in order to pay less money
up front.</li>
<li>My mortgage broker Deborah started collecting relevant documents from me to start the mortgage
approval process. These include but aren&rsquo;t limited to bank statements, pay stubs (W2), federal
income tax returns (1040). I didn&rsquo;t have to use a mortgage broker and could&rsquo;ve shopped around
myself simply by applying online at various commercial banks&#8217; websites. But I&rsquo;m pretty busy,
and the broker&rsquo;s fee would be paid by the lender in my case.</li>
<li>Alan accepted our verbal offer and sent over a contract of sale. This document is a major
checkpoint. It stated what, when, and how we would exchange property and money. Once I signed it
and included a contract deposit (10% of the purchase price), it meant Alan and I were in a
legally binding agreement and that he wasn&rsquo;t considering any other offers.

<ul>
<li>If I reneged, Alan could keep my contract deposit.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not sure what legal recourse or damages I could pursue if Alan reneged. The contract
vaguely stated:

<blockquote><p>In the event of a default or misrepresentation by Seller, Purchaser shall have such remedies
as Purchaser is entitled to at law or in equity, including specific performance, because
the Unit and possession thereof cannot be duplicated.</p></blockquote></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Our respective attorneys went back and forth modifying the contract of sale with riders that
protected each of us, respectively. For example, my attorney Andrew added a clause stipulating
the wall Alan built to divide the bedroom into two bedrooms was approved by the co-op board and
I would get a written approval letter at closing. Alan&rsquo;s attorney Michael added a clause stating
I couldn&rsquo;t back out of the sale if the maintenance increased after I&rsquo;d signed the contract.</li>
<li>I signed the contract on January 25, 2016. And I expected a counter-signed copy back shortly.</li>
<li>So I waited.</li>
<li>And waited.</li>
<li>And waited&hellip;</li>
<li>It seems that the more sellers there are on the contract, the more likely it there are to be
issues. In my case, there were a total of three sellers. Two of them were individuals:
Alan and his ex-wife. The third seller was the estate of Alan&rsquo;s deceased father. This estate
had two executors: Alan and his sister.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re not confused yet, you will be.</li>
<li>Alan told me his ex-wife wasn&rsquo;t being cooperative with the sale but that a court order would
help convince her as a last resort.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, my mortgage broker Deborah was busy securing a lender for me. I also needed to have
the unit appraised which depended on the contract being fully signed.</li>
<li>On February 4, Deborah tells me the co-op has an insurance policy that&rsquo;s shared with other
buildings. She said most lenders won&rsquo;t underwrite a mortgage in a building with a pooled policy.
She said she&rsquo;ll try other lenders.</li>
<li>After an entire month (March 5 to be precise), Alan successfully compelled his ex-wife to sign
with the issuance of a court order. This allowed me to schedule the appraisal.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, I still hadn&rsquo;t secured the mortgage. Guaranteed Rate, Citi, Chase, Wells and various
portfolio lenders all refused. With each lender that turned me down because of
the co-op insurance policy, the more likely it seemed that Deborah and I would have to somehow
convince the co-op board to buy a new individual policy. The property management company would
also have to complete lots of paperwork. I&rsquo;ve never met the board, and the management company
seemed like a tangled bureaucracy. I was seriously questioning how I&rsquo;d be able to pull this off.</li>
<li><em>To be continued&hellip;</em></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Years of Working at Spotify, Four Years of Shared Values]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/four-years-of-working-at-spotify-four-years-of-shared-values/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-13T13:01:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/four-years-of-working-at-spotify-four-years-of-shared-values</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can&rsquo;t believe it&rsquo;s been four years since I started working at Spotify. Every Friday, the
Technology, Product, and Design group at Spotify&rsquo;s New York City office
gathers to eat freshly catered snacks, introduce new hires, announce &ldquo;wins of the week,&rdquo; and
commemorate the anniversaries of existing employees.</p>

<p>Last Friday was my turn to stand before the couple hundred members of TPD. It&rsquo;s customary for people
celebrating their employment anniversaries to speak about their favorite Spotify memory.
I don&rsquo;t get many chances to address so many of my colleagues at
once. So I took this opportunity to prepare a short statement. It went something like this.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s my favorite Spotify memory? I have a hard time with this question because I don&rsquo;t have a
good answer. There&rsquo;s so many.</p>

<p>I find another question more interesting. That question is, &ldquo;What, after four years, makes me look
forward to getting up every weekday morning and working at Spotify?&rdquo; Four years is a long time to
be doing anything continuously.</p>

<p>I can tell you what&rsquo;s not the main reason. It&rsquo;s not the snacks or perks or the amazing office.
It&rsquo;s not even Celebration X [Spotify&rsquo;s massive 10-year anniversary party in Stockholm].
These are all great things, but they&rsquo;re not the main reason I show up everyday.</p>

<p>The main reason is values. I&rsquo;ve never been at a place where I share so many values with my
colleagues and the company. My teammates like Matt and Staffan and Mats share my values of hard
work, competence, and personal responsibility (and beer). The company constantly strives to become
a better version of itself through being risk-taking, passion, and compassion.</p>

<p>Every day is a new memory. Every day I feel blessed to be here working with all of you. Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skydiving With Friends - Jumping Out of Planes Is Fun]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/skydiving-with-friends-jumping-out-of-planes-is-fun/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-28T10:59:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/skydiving-with-friends-jumping-out-of-planes-is-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On April 16, seven friends and I went skydiving at Skydive the Ranch in New Jersey. We rented
a black SUV (a Hyundai that had terrible acceleration and braking) and each did a tandem dive.
It was a first for many of us including me.</p>

<p>My takeaway was that tandem diving out of a plane at 14-thousand feet is easy. The instructor takes
care of everything. I just had to sit back and enjoy the view. If anything went wrong and I died,
I wouldn&rsquo;t feel that bad about it because I wasn&rsquo;t the one who screwed it up.</p>

<p>Driving seven of your friends out of and back into New York City is nerve-wracking, on the other
hand. I was personally responsible for everyone&rsquo;s lives. Trying to return the rental car on time
while driving through Union Square in Manhattan where
there&rsquo;s a pedestrian fair going on, ambulances and cop cars, and drivers double parking wherever
they want is very stressful.</p>

<p>Hopefully Avis doesn&rsquo;t notice the small white scratch on the mirror of their mint condition car
(18 miles when I got it) that was left when I managed to squeeze through two city buses before they
crushed me.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaSiFui6vt0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
