<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Current Events | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/current-events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-05-17T15:28:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farts and Craps With David Xia – Waterboarding]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/02/farts-and-craps-with-david-xia-waterboarding/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/02/farts-and-craps-with-david-xia-waterboarding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tOSd1W9KEHs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Waterboarding has been a controversial topic ever since the fall of 2007, when it was widely
reported that the CIA was using waterboarding on extrajudicial prisoners and that the Justice
Department authorized the procedure as an &ldquo;enhanced interrogation technique.&rdquo; Many consider
waterboarding torture and a violation of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Article_3_of_the_Geneva_Conventions#Common_Article_3_relating_to_Non-International_Armed_Conflict" title="Common Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions">Common Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m in no way trying to diminish the implications waterboarding with this personal experiment. I
wanted to experience waterboarding first-hand in order to better understand the context
surrounding the debate. I never truly feared for my life because my trusted friends administered
the waterboarding and I held a wooden block which I would drop when I couldn&rsquo;t take anymore. But I
can say that when done right, I felt like I was drowning. I had no control over my spasms and
gags.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Read Steve Jobs' Biography]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/why-you-should-read-steve-jobs-biography/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/why-you-should-read-steve-jobs-biography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve got 140 pages left to go in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1451648537/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1451648537">Steve Jobs&#8217; biography</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1451648537" alt="" />, and I&rsquo;ve laughed, shuddered,
but most of all, felt inspired by all the pages so far. I can&rsquo;t believe I didn&rsquo;t know more about
Jobs&#8217; personal background; the creation, near death, and triumphant rise of Apple; or the myriad
other people in the tech world that were related to Jobs&#8217; life.</p>

<p>Isaacson writes with clarity and detail. The anecdotes are numerous and often funny. The portrait
Isaacson paints of Jobs has inspired, scared, and taught me a lot. I admire Jobs&#8217; passion for life
and creation; I&rsquo;m repulsed by his streaks of cruelty. Because of and despite of his character
strengths and flaws, he left a lasting legacy. The biography&rsquo;s author Walter Isaacson put it this
way:</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>The Apple II, which took Wozniak&rsquo;s circuit board and turned it into the first personal computer
that was not just for hobbyists.</li>
<li>The Macintosh, which begat the home computer revolution and popularized graphical user interfaces.</li>
<li><em>Toy Story</em> and other Pixar blockbusters, which opened up the miracle of digital imagination.</li>
<li>Apple stores, which reinvented the role of a store in defining a brand.</li>
<li>The iPod, which changed the way we consume music.</li>
<li>The iTunes Store, which saved the music industry.</li>
<li>The iPhone which turned mobile phones into music, photography, video, email, and web devices.</li>
<li>The App store, which spawned a new content-creation industry.</li>
<li>The iPad, which launched tablet computing and offered a platform for digital newspapers,
magazines, books, and videos.</li>
<li>iCloud, which demoted the computer from its central role in managing our content and let all of
our devices sync seamlessly.</li>
<li>And Apple itself, which Jobs considered his greatest creation, a place where imagination was
nurtured, applied, and executed in ways so creative that it became the most valuable company on
earth.</li>
</ul>


<p>Anyone who owns an Apple product, from occasional iPod users to the most hard-core cult-of-Apple
fanboys, should crack open this book.</p>

<p>Here are some of my favorite excerpts:</p>

<h3>Product design simplicity</h3>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Jonathan Ive page 343, Steve Jobs %}
Why do we assume that simple is good? Because with physical products, we have to feel we can
dominate them. As you bring order to complexity, you find a way to make the product defer to you.
Simplicity isn&rsquo;t just a visual style. It&rsquo;s not just minimalism or the absence of clutter. It
involves digging through the depth of the complexity. To be truly simple, you have to go really
deep. For example, to have no screws on something, you can end up having a product that is so
convoluted and so complex. The better way is to go deeper with the simplicity, to understand
everything about it and how it&rsquo;s manufactured. You have to deeply understand the essence of a
product in order to be able to get rid of the parts that are not essential.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<h3>Jobs obsessing over the color of the iMac in a print ad</h3>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Walter Isaacson, Steve Jobs %}
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Clow">Lee Clow</a> was preparing a series of colorful magazine ads, and when he sent Jobs the page
proofs he got an outraged phone call in response. The blue in the ad, Jobs insisted, was different
from that of the iMac. &ldquo;You guys don&rsquo;t know what you&rsquo;re doing!&rdquo; Jobs shouted. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m going to get
someone else to do the ads, because this is fucked up.&rdquo; Clow argued back. Compare them, he said.
Jobs, who was not in the office, insisted he was right and continued to shout. Eventually Clow got
him to sit down with the original photographs. &ldquo;I finally proved to him that the blue was the blue
was the blue.&rdquo; Years later, on a Steve Jobs discussion board on the website Gawker, the following
tale appeared from someone who had worked at the Whole Foods store in Palo Alto a few blocks from
Jobs&rsquo;s home: &ldquo;I was shagging carts one afternoon when I saw this silver Mercedes parked in a
handicapped spot. Steve Jobs was inside screaming at his car phone. This was right before the
first iMac was unveiled and I&rsquo;m pretty sure I could make out, &lsquo;Not. Fucking. Blue. Enough!!!&rsquo;&rdquo;
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<h3>Apple stores</h3>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Walter Isaacson, Steve Jobs %}
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ron_Johnson_(businessman)">[Ron] Johnson</a> said that the size of a store signaled the importance of the brand. &ldquo;Is Apple
as big of a brand as the Gap? he asked. Jobs said it was much bigger. Johnson replied that its
stores should therefore be bigger. &#8220;Otherwise you won&rsquo;t be relevant.&rdquo; Jobs described Mike
Markkula&rsquo;s maxim that a good company must &ldquo;impute&rdquo; – it must convey its values and importance in
everything it does, from packaging to marketing. Johnson loved it. It definitely applied to a
company&rsquo;s stores. &ldquo;The store will become the most powerful physical expression of the band,&rdquo; he
predicted.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;ll read more biographies. Who needs fictional characters when you&rsquo;ve got real ones like
Jobs?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Love the Moth. Why Is Voss Underwriting Them?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/i-love-the-moth-why-is-voss-underwriting-them/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/i-love-the-moth-why-is-voss-underwriting-them</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://themoth.org/">The Moth</a> is an organization that hosts events made of real stories told live on stage. Every
event has a different theme around which story tellers weave their narratives. They&rsquo;re one of my
favorite podcasts. I love listening to the well-crafted stories told by writers, artists, and
regular folk.</p>

<p>The stories are about 15 minutes long with simple narrative arcs, but their messages are often
complex. Some of the most memorable stories for me are:</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Mike Birbiglia talks about breaking up with his girlfriend while stranded on an island:</p>

<p>{% audio <a href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-149-mike-birbiglia.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-149-mike-birbiglia.mp3</a> %}</p>

<p>Steve Burns of children&rsquo;s show <em>Blues Clues</em> talks about grappling with TV fame.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CwmtkFPYXsg?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I admire the Moth&rsquo;s storytellers. It&rsquo;s not easy speaking in front of a large audience let alone
<a href="/2010/12/how-to-tell-good-stories/">captivating them with a great story</a> without notes.</p>

<p>I often download their latest podcast on Sunday morning and listen to it while biking or jogging.
The Moth makes their podcast free and sometimes has an ad at the end of the podcast. Usually the
ad is for a product or brand that makes sense with The Moth&rsquo;s branding and demographic. I envision
that demographic to be highly educated urbanites ages 30 to 50 who are married and listen to NPR
and skew liberal.</p>

<p>So I was surprised to hear an ad for Voss water in the last two Moth podcasts. Here at 15:08</p>

<p>{% audio <a href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-195-adam-gopnik.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-195-adam-gopnik.mp3</a> %}</p>

<p>and here at 17:30.</p>

<p>{% audio <a href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/the-moth-podcast-194-david-chang.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/the-moth-podcast-194-david-chang.mp3</a> %}</p>

<p>These ads are read by the host Dan Kennedy and include a reason why Moth listeners should buy the
product or subscribe to the brand.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the script for the Voss ad:</p>

<blockquote><p>Voss is the perfect pairing for your special dining moments. A night worth talking about always
  starts with Voss on the table because with Voss comes great conversation. And with a great
  conversation comes a story worth sharing.</p></blockquote>

<p>Am I hearing this right? If I drink bottled water I&rsquo;ll have better conversations and be a rockstar
conversationalist?</p>

<p>Is this brand mismatch? The Moth is a non-profit organization where people share stories. Voss is
a luxury lifestyle product in the form of bottled water. They call it <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artesian_water">artesian water</a> which is
simply water from an aquifer that&rsquo;s under positive pressure. What&rsquo;s so great about that? And even
if this kind of water were all that, there have been allegations that Voss water is really just
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voss_(water)#cite_note-3">tap water</a> in a sleek glass bottle.</p>

<p>But there is a silver lining. Voss has a <a href="http://www.thevossfoundation.org/about/">foundation</a> that helps people in Sub-Saharan Africa
get access to clean drinking water. In 2010 the Voss Foundation
<a href="http://www.thevossfoundation.org/assets/Voss-Foundation-2010-Year-in-Review.pdf">spent $137,346 toward its cause</a>. It seems like a drop in the bucket in solving
<a href="http://www.cfr.org/africa/water-stress-sub-saharan-africa/p11240">Sub-Saharan Africa&rsquo;s water problems</a>, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing.</p>

<p>I think of the situation as a bunch of people buying fancy bottles and transferring their wealth
to a company good at marketing. This company then gives a portion (I have no idea what percentage
because Voss seems to be a private company with no public financial statements) to helping people
who have a hard time finding potable water.</p>

<p><em>Update: Since writing this post The Moth has not had anymore Voss ads in their podcasts. Yay.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light a Fire Under Politicians' Asses]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/light-a-fire-under-politicians-asses/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/light-a-fire-under-politicians-asses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The inner populist in me is heartened to see the Occupy Wall Street movement grow and even
<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/16/world/occupy-wall-street-protests-worldwide.html?hp">spread to other countries</a>. It&rsquo;s about time the penny-wise-pound-foolish policies of careerist
politicians and hamstrung governments came back to bite them in the ass.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I want to see the Occupy Wall Street movement not only gain more steam but also to become more
organized and remain vigilantly peaceful. Right now I&rsquo;m not sure what it stands for besides
general malaise. The movement is not a response to the financial crisis or Wall Street barons as
supporters might say. If Wall Street made boatloads of money and Main Street also enjoyed low
unemployment and decent salaries, this movement wouldn&rsquo;t exist. That&rsquo;s why no one occupied Wall
Street in 2008 right after the crash.</p>

<p>Instead, it took three years of high unemployment and falling wages and <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/16/realestate/rents-in-manhattan-rebound-to-record-highs.html">rising rents</a> to
slowly generate this movement. Occupy Wall Street supporters are demonstrating more against the
political elite not the financial elite. It&rsquo;s the political elite who didn&rsquo;t fix things afterward
the financial elite fucked up. Now the commoners are thinking &ldquo;wait, if the people in charge are
incompetent, what gives them the right to rule?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s some insightful analysis by George Friedman of Stratfor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Privileged and Precarious Life]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/my-privileged-and-precarious-life/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/my-privileged-and-precarious-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m always painfully aware of how privileged my life is. I grew up in New England&rsquo;s affluent
suburbs as part of the upper middle class. I attended college at Columbia University with generous
financial aid. And now I&rsquo;m working in one of the few industries that&rsquo;s aggressively hiring in a
job position that&rsquo;s seeing growth. There&rsquo;s a stark contrast between my situation and those less
fortunate around me. New York City&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.labor.ny.gov/stats/pressreleases/pruistat.shtm">current unemployment rate of 8%</a> remains unchanged since
a year ago. U.S. <a href="http://www.google.com/publicdata/explore?ds=z1ebjpgk2654c1_&amp;met_y=unemployment_rate&amp;tdim=true&amp;fdim_y=seasonality:S&amp;dl=en&amp;hl=en&amp;q=national%20unemployment%20rate#ctype=l&amp;strail=false&amp;nselm=h&amp;met_y=unemployment_rate&amp;fdim_y=seasonality:S&amp;scale_y=lin&amp;ind_y=false&amp;rdim=state&amp;ifdim=state&amp;tdim=true&amp;hl=en&amp;dl=en">unemployment is 9.1%</a>.</p>

<p>Right now there&rsquo;s so much more demand for technical talent than supply of it that I wish I could
wave a magic wand and turn
<a href="http://www.census.gov/compendia/statab/2011/tables/11s0624.pdf">idle construction workers, durable goods manufacturers, and fishermen</a> into
<a href="http://railsforzombies.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> developers.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Although my life is privileged, I&rsquo;m afraid it&rsquo;s precarious. The basic human necessities for
survival are water, food, shelter, and (depending upon climate) clothing. I can create a website
and scrape data, but at the end of the day I can&rsquo;t eat my Ubuntu virtual or code a web app to
generate potable water. Although I can create a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linked_list">linked list in C</a>, if I&rsquo;m left by myself in
the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Side_of_the_Mountain">Catskill mountains</a> or the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_House_on_the_Prairie#Story">frontiers of society</a>, I doubt I&rsquo;d come out like Sam
Gribley or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laura_Ingalls_Wilder">Laura Ingalls Wilder</a>.</p>

<p>I often think of what I&rsquo;d do in a catastrophic scenario. A day after my friend said I was silly
for worrying about doomsday scenarios, I wake up to hear Mayor Bloomberg
<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/08/27/nyregion/new-york-city-begins-evacuations-before-hurricane.html?_r=1&amp;hp">ordering the evacuation</a> of the city&rsquo;s coastal areas and shutting down the transit system. We
also quickly forget major crises as soon as they pass.</p>

<p>These are only some of the recent natural disasters.</p>

<ul>
<li>July-August 2010. Floods triggered by heavier-than-normal monsoon rains hit northwest Pakistan.
By the time the waters began to recede in late August, more than 160,000 square kilometres of land
— about one-fifth of the country — was under water. More than 1,700 people were killed and 17.2
million people have been affected.</li>
<li>Jan. 12, 2010. A 7.0-magnitude earthquake in Haiti killed over 230,000 people.</li>
<li>May 12, 2008. A 7.9-magnitude earthquake in Sichuan, China killed over 70,000 people.</li>
<li>May 3, 2008. Cyclone Nargis, swept along by winds that exceeded 190 kmh and waves six metres
high struck the Burmese peninsula and may have left as many as 100,000 dead, according to U.S.
estimates.</li>
<li>Oct. 8, 2005. A 7.6-magnitude earthquake in Kashmir, Pakistan killed at least 80,000 people and
left three million homeless.</li>
<li>Dec. 26, 2004. A 9.0-magnitude quake off the coast of Sumatra triggered tsunamis that swept
through the coastal regions of a dozen countries bordering the Indian Ocean. The death toll has
been estimated at between 225,000 and 275,000.</li>
</ul>


<p>And let&rsquo;s not forget about the disasters we humans create ourselves: crime, terrorism, war,
financial crises, pollution, etc.</p>

<p>The food I eat and the goods I buy come from a sprawling yet fragile industrialized system. My
Macbook Air I&rsquo;m typing on is made from many components from many companies. I don&rsquo;t know how to
draw water from a well, how to slaughter a chicken, or do subsistence farming. My atavistic side
feels neglected. Of course, these are skills that won&rsquo;t benefit me as a service worker in this
post-industrial age, but I feel exposed and vulnerable. I live off the top of so many other layers
of civilization that make everything run smoothly, provide my Macbook Air electricity, and deliver
food to my local grocery stores. The more complex and specialized society becomes, the energy is
required to maintain it. Just look at America&rsquo;s decaying infrastructure. I see it everyday when I
take New York&rsquo;s crowded and creaking subway, when I try to avoid all the potholes in Manhattan
streets.</p>

<p>A really scary documentary I watched is <em>Collapse</em>. It&rsquo;s an 82-minute monologue with Michael
Ruppert, ex-LA cop and investigative reporter. Supporters think he&rsquo;s a visionary and radical
thinker. Critics call him a conspiracy theorist and an alarmist.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WAyHIOg5aHk?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<blockquote><p>The key to understanding infrastructure lies at the heart of complex civilizations. When roads
  and bridges fail; levees aren&rsquo;t rebuilt; when dams, transmission lines and generating stations are
  not maintained; when any of a hundred possible things fail for lack of money or
  material&hellip;civilization starts to break down. – Michael Ruppert</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
