<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Current Events | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/current-events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-18T10:02:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Michael Lewis' the Premonition]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2021/08/notes-on-michael-lewis-the-premonition/"/>
    <updated>2021-08-16T11:18:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2021/08/notes-on-michael-lewis-the-premonition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I finished reading Michael Lewis&#8217; <em>The Premonition</em>. The following parts of the book (with
page numbers) stood out to me.</p>

<p>The U.S. Centers for Disease Control (CDC) is portrayed as a risk-averse bureaucracy that wants to
study disease and not take strong measures to control disease. Sometimes this interest conflicts
with local health officials who want to save lives and see strong measures as necessary even if not
all the evidence is available yet. Health officials are always firefighting and can&rsquo;t wait for more
data. Lewis compared them to platoon leaders during battle. (page 40)</p>

<!-- Carter Mecher is laser focused under pressure. (61) -->


<p>Deadly mistakes are often result from the combination of systemic and human failures. Lewis tells the
story of a Veterans Affairs (VA) patient who was accidentally boiled alive in an Atlanta VA
hospital. The hospital heated water to a specific temperature hot enough to kill certain bacteria
but not hot enough to scald people. Bathtub faucets had a special valve that prevented water that
was too hot from emerging. The water heating mechanism was broken, however. So the nurses
compensated by adjusting the valve to a hotter temperature. Then one day, plumbers fixed the heating
mechanism without telling the nurses. Normally a patient would tell the nurses when the water was
too hot. But the nurses happened to be bathing one patient who was an older man with mental health
problems. He always screamed no matter what. The nurses didn&rsquo;t think anything was wrong when he
screamed this time. &ldquo;An hour later, the man&rsquo;s skin was peeling away, and he was dying of thermal
burns.&rdquo; (67) This is a powerful story. Unfortunately, I&rsquo;m unable to find corroborating news
articles, and Lewis doesn&rsquo;t have references or footnotes.</p>

<p>Why and how people learn.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&hellip;people don&rsquo;t learn what is imposed upon them but rather what they frely seek, out of desire or<br/>need. For people to learn, they need to want to learn&hellip; &ldquo;People in an organization learn,&rdquo; said<br/>Carter. &ldquo;They&rsquo;re learning all kinds of things. But they aren&rsquo;t learning what you are teaching them.<br/>You go to a formal meeting. The important conversation is not in the meeting. It&rsquo;s in the halls<br/>during the breaks. And usually what&rsquo;s important is taboo. And you can&rsquo;t say it in the formal<br/>meeting.&rdquo;</p><footer><strong>72-3</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Is Lewis&#8217; account of the CDC&rsquo;s aversion to computer models accurate? <em>Premonition</em> says the CDC had
models that were just in people&rsquo;s heads. &ldquo;They, too, used models. They, too, depended on
abstractions to inform their judgments. Those abstractions just happened to be inside their heads.&rdquo; (85)</p>

<p>One of the two main protagonists of the book is an American physician named Carter Mecher. From 1996
to 2005, Mecher served as the Chief Medical Officer for the Southeast Veterans Administration
Network. Mecher wanted to figure out how government should allocate resources.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Each year, Congress would hand more than a hundred billion dollars to Veterans Affairs, and various<br/>people inside the VA would bay for more than they&rsquo;d gotten the year before. The top brass had no way<br/>to figure out who was actually busting their ass and needed more help and who was loafing&hellip;He hated<br/>in particular the way some people were able to use their own inefficiency to create a seeming need<br/>for more funding; and other people, people with a gift for making do with less, were, as a result,<br/>given even less. &ldquo;It drove out the entrepreneurial spirit,&rdquo; said Carter.</p><footer><strong>162</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>ICE under the Trump administration was bussing and flying undocumented immigrants into
cities in California to manufacture a humanitarian crisis according to the other protagonist of the
book, a public health official named Charity Dean. (187, 190) This seemed insane to me, but I was
able to find news articles about this. The actual story seems a bit more nuanced as one can read
from this AP article &ldquo;<a href="https://apnews.com/article/us-news-ap-top-news-mi-state-wire-az-state-wire-immigration-1c7aec8b18ae4cb3a8ed0a624c641eb9">Far from border, US cities feel effect of migrant releases</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Charity Dean explained to the CDC at the beginning of 2020 that there is no &ldquo;<strong>system</strong> of public
health in the United States, just a patchwork of state and local health officers, beholden to a
greater or lesser degree to local elected officials. Three thousand five hundred separate entities
that had been starved of resources for the past forty years.&rdquo; This explains why the U.S. had no
coordinated and science-based approach to Covid. (205-6)</p>

<p>A major antagonist of the book is Sonia Angell. She was the director of California&rsquo;s Public Health
Department and supervisor to Charity Dean who was the deputy director at the time. Lewis describes
how she actively prevented any measures to acknowledge the severity of the virus or to try to
contain it. Did Lewis try to interview and incorporate Sonia Angell&rsquo;s side of the story?</p>

<p>A particularly egregious story of CDC incompetence is when they didn&rsquo;t bother recording the
addresses of Americans returning from China.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>When local health officers called the CDC to say how hard it was to track down John Smith when the<br/>CDC had listed his residence as &ldquo;Los Angeles International Airport,&rdquo; the CDC said, &ldquo;Just don&rsquo;t<br/>follow up on them.&rdquo; What was the point of having these travel restrictions from Wuhan if the federal<br/>government was going to just let people loose upon their return?</p><footer><strong>206</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a particularly enraging and scary part of the book on CDC inaction. Mecher learns
about Covid transmission, hospitalization, and death reates among passengers on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COVID-19_pandemic_on_Diamond_Princess">Diamond
Princess cruise ship</a>. This is a perfect and scary real life simulation of
how Covid will behave in the general population. Mecher compares the situation of the world at the
time to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mann_Gulch_fire">Mann Gulch fire</a>. This was a wildfire that initially looked containable. 13
smokejumpers parachuted in to fight it. But then &ldquo;unexpected high winds caused the fire to suddenly
expand, cutting off the men&rsquo;s route and forcing them back uphill. During the next few minutes, a
&#8220;blow-up&rdquo; of the fire covered 3,000 acres (1,200 ha) in ten minutes, claiming the lives of 13
firefighters, including 12 of the smokejumpers. Only three of the smokejumpers survived.&ldquo; Mecher
tries desparately to convince the CDC to take strong enough actions.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ldquo;I sense confusion among very smart people,&rdquo; he wrote in early March. &ldquo;[They] hear that more than<br/>80% of those who are infected have mild disease and that overall case fatality rates are on the<br/>order of .5%. And then they equate these states to a mild outbreak.&rdquo; &hellip; Using the most conservative<br/>assumptions suggested by the cruise ship&mdash;an attack rate of 20 percent and a fatality rate of<br/>half of 1 percent&mdash;you wound up with 330,000 dead Americans&hellip; &ldquo;You have all been quiet for<br/>most of the discussion over the past several weeks. I would urge you to read the article I just sent<br/>out and upbrief your boss&hellip; History will long remember what we do and what we don&rsquo;t do at this<br/>critical moment. It is time to act and it is past the time to remain silent. This outbreak isn&rsquo;t<br/>going to magically disappear on its own.&rdquo;</p><footer><strong>214-8</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s obvious that people at the top of government agencies at all levels are lost. No one&rsquo;s
coming to save us. Here&rsquo;s another enraging anecdote about Angell.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>On March 6, Gavin Newsome convened a hundred of the state&rsquo;s top officials to discuss the new<br/>coronavirus. Sonia Angell had told Charity that she, Angell, would give the briefing to the<br/>governor, and that it was better if Charity did not attend the meeting. <em>You have no role</em>, Angell<br/>explained, <em>so you should not be there</em>. Charity didn&rsquo;t believe Angell had the ability to get up in<br/>front of the audience and explain what was going on. &ldquo;I just had a feeling that something would<br/>happen and she wouldn&rsquo;t be able to make it,&rdquo; she recalled. Sure enough, the morning of the event,<br/>the phone call came. Angell couldn&rsquo;t make the meeting. Might Charity step in at the last minute to<br/>replace her?</p><footer><strong>226</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Media changes now force technical people to consider the cynical perception of their actions instead
of strictly whether their decision in and of itself is the best. (287)</p>

<p>Lewis introduces the interesting concept of L6.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>In any large organization, the solution to any crisis was usually found not in the officially<br/>important people at the top but in some obscure employee far down the organization&rsquo;s chart. A case<br/>in point was the day the software used by the State Department to process visa applications stopped<br/>working. That day the U.S. government simply lost its ability to issue visas&hellip; &ldquo;Six layers down<br/>from the people in charge we found two contractors who actually understand what is broken.&rdquo; The L6.</p><footer><strong>231</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The private sector is inefficient at generating knowledge because profit motive prevents
collaboration and openness. (246)</p>

<p>Another story about how the federal government&rsquo;s laissez-faire attitude towards helping state and
local governments secure personal protective equipment led to a market free-for-all that drove
prices way up. (253)</p>

<p>Local health offices are understaffed and behind the times. Joseph DeRisi is an American biochemist
who heads the Chan Zuckerberg Biohub, a nonprofit research organization. In April 2020, Biohub had
developed a Covid test kit and offered it free to any local public health officials who needed it.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Once his team began to deliver free test kits to them, he understood why they&rsquo;d been slow to take up<br/>the Biohub&rsquo;s offer of free testing. Many local health officers were so understaffed and<br/>underequipped they had trouble using the test kits. Most were unable to receive the results<br/>electronically; they needed the results faxed to them. Some had fax machines so old that they<br/>couldn&rsquo;t receive more than six pages at a time. A few didn&rsquo;t even have functioning fax machines, and<br/>so the Biohub got into the business of buying and delivering fax machines along with test kits.</p><footer><strong>254</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>This story is corroborated by this NYT article &ldquo;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/13/upshot/coronavirus-response-fax-machines.html">Bottleneck for U.S. Coronavirus Response: The Fax
Machine</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>One reason why the CDC is dysfunctional is because Reagan changed its director from being a
civil servant to a presidential appointee. (289-90)</p>

<p>Local health officials who were courageous lost their jobs and feared for their safety because
there was a lack of leadership from CDC and federal and state leaders. (291)</p>

<h2>further reading</h2>

<ul>
<li>Barry&rsquo;s <em>The Great Influenza</em></li>
<li>Rajeeev&rsquo;s 12 page document written in 2005</li>
<li>interviews with Carter Mecher or Charity Dean</li>
<li>former CDC director Bill Foege&rsquo;s letter to Robert Redfield who was CDC director at the time</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farts and Craps With David Xia – Waterboarding]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/02/farts-and-craps-with-david-xia-waterboarding/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/02/farts-and-craps-with-david-xia-waterboarding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tOSd1W9KEHs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Waterboarding has been a controversial topic ever since the fall of 2007, when it was widely
reported that the CIA was using waterboarding on extrajudicial prisoners and that the Justice
Department authorized the procedure as an &ldquo;enhanced interrogation technique.&rdquo; Many consider
waterboarding torture and a violation of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Article_3_of_the_Geneva_Conventions#Common_Article_3_relating_to_Non-International_Armed_Conflict" title="Common Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions">Common Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m in no way trying to diminish the implications waterboarding with this personal experiment. I
wanted to experience waterboarding first-hand in order to better understand the context
surrounding the debate. I never truly feared for my life because my trusted friends administered
the waterboarding and I held a wooden block which I would drop when I couldn&rsquo;t take anymore. But I
can say that when done right, I felt like I was drowning. I had no control over my spasms and
gags.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Read Steve Jobs' Biography]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/why-you-should-read-steve-jobs-biography/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/why-you-should-read-steve-jobs-biography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve got 140 pages left to go in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1451648537/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1451648537">Steve Jobs&#8217; biography</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1451648537" alt="" />, and I&rsquo;ve laughed, shuddered,
but most of all, felt inspired by all the pages so far. I can&rsquo;t believe I didn&rsquo;t know more about
Jobs&#8217; personal background; the creation, near death, and triumphant rise of Apple; or the myriad
other people in the tech world that were related to Jobs&#8217; life.</p>

<p>Isaacson writes with clarity and detail. The anecdotes are numerous and often funny. The portrait
Isaacson paints of Jobs has inspired, scared, and taught me a lot. I admire Jobs&#8217; passion for life
and creation; I&rsquo;m repulsed by his streaks of cruelty. Because of and despite of his character
strengths and flaws, he left a lasting legacy. The biography&rsquo;s author Walter Isaacson put it this
way:</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>The Apple II, which took Wozniak&rsquo;s circuit board and turned it into the first personal computer
that was not just for hobbyists.</li>
<li>The Macintosh, which begat the home computer revolution and popularized graphical user interfaces.</li>
<li><em>Toy Story</em> and other Pixar blockbusters, which opened up the miracle of digital imagination.</li>
<li>Apple stores, which reinvented the role of a store in defining a brand.</li>
<li>The iPod, which changed the way we consume music.</li>
<li>The iTunes Store, which saved the music industry.</li>
<li>The iPhone which turned mobile phones into music, photography, video, email, and web devices.</li>
<li>The App store, which spawned a new content-creation industry.</li>
<li>The iPad, which launched tablet computing and offered a platform for digital newspapers,
magazines, books, and videos.</li>
<li>iCloud, which demoted the computer from its central role in managing our content and let all of
our devices sync seamlessly.</li>
<li>And Apple itself, which Jobs considered his greatest creation, a place where imagination was
nurtured, applied, and executed in ways so creative that it became the most valuable company on
earth.</li>
</ul>


<p>Anyone who owns an Apple product, from occasional iPod users to the most hard-core cult-of-Apple
fanboys, should crack open this book.</p>

<p>Here are some of my favorite excerpts:</p>

<h3>Product design simplicity</h3>

<p><blockquote><p>Why do we assume that simple is good? Because with physical products, we have to feel we can
dominate them. As you bring order to complexity, you find a way to make the product defer to you.
Simplicity isn&rsquo;t just a visual style. It&rsquo;s not just minimalism or the absence of clutter. It
involves digging through the depth of the complexity. To be truly simple, you have to go really
deep. For example, to have no screws on something, you can end up having a product that is so
convoluted and so complex. The better way is to go deeper with the simplicity, to understand
everything about it and how it&rsquo;s manufactured. You have to deeply understand the essence of a
product in order to be able to get rid of the parts that are not essential.</p><footer><strong>Jonathan Ive page 343</strong> <cite>Steve Jobs</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<h3>Jobs obsessing over the color of the iMac in a print ad</h3>

<p><blockquote><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Clow">Lee Clow</a> was preparing a series of colorful magazine ads, and when he sent Jobs the page
proofs he got an outraged phone call in response. The blue in the ad, Jobs insisted, was different
from that of the iMac. &ldquo;You guys don&rsquo;t know what you&rsquo;re doing!&rdquo; Jobs shouted. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m going to get
someone else to do the ads, because this is fucked up.&rdquo; Clow argued back. Compare them, he said.
Jobs, who was not in the office, insisted he was right and continued to shout. Eventually Clow got
him to sit down with the original photographs. &ldquo;I finally proved to him that the blue was the blue
was the blue.&rdquo; Years later, on a Steve Jobs discussion board on the website Gawker, the following
tale appeared from someone who had worked at the Whole Foods store in Palo Alto a few blocks from
Jobs&rsquo;s home: &ldquo;I was shagging carts one afternoon when I saw this silver Mercedes parked in a
handicapped spot. Steve Jobs was inside screaming at his car phone. This was right before the
first iMac was unveiled and I&rsquo;m pretty sure I could make out, &lsquo;Not. Fucking. Blue. Enough!!!&rsquo;&rdquo;</p><footer><strong>Walter Isaacson</strong> <cite>Steve Jobs</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<h3>Apple stores</h3>

<p><blockquote><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ron_Johnson_(businessman)">[Ron] Johnson</a> said that the size of a store signaled the importance of the brand. &ldquo;Is Apple
as big of a brand as the Gap? he asked. Jobs said it was much bigger. Johnson replied that its
stores should therefore be bigger. &#8220;Otherwise you won&rsquo;t be relevant.&rdquo; Jobs described Mike
Markkula&rsquo;s maxim that a good company must &ldquo;impute&rdquo; – it must convey its values and importance in
everything it does, from packaging to marketing. Johnson loved it. It definitely applied to a
company&rsquo;s stores. &ldquo;The store will become the most powerful physical expression of the band,&rdquo; he
predicted.</p><footer><strong>Walter Isaacson</strong> <cite>Steve Jobs</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;ll read more biographies. Who needs fictional characters when you&rsquo;ve got real ones like
Jobs?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Love the Moth. Why Is Voss Underwriting Them?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/i-love-the-moth-why-is-voss-underwriting-them/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/i-love-the-moth-why-is-voss-underwriting-them</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://themoth.org/">The Moth</a> is an organization that hosts events made of real stories told live on stage. Every
event has a different theme around which story tellers weave their narratives. They&rsquo;re one of my
favorite podcasts. I love listening to the well-crafted stories told by writers, artists, and
regular folk.</p>

<p>The stories are about 15 minutes long with simple narrative arcs, but their messages are often
complex. Some of the most memorable stories for me are:</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Mike Birbiglia talks about breaking up with his girlfriend while stranded on an island:</p>

<p><audio controls><source src='<a'><source src='href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-149-mike-birbiglia.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-149-mike-birbiglia.mp3</a>&#8217;></audio></p>

<p>Steve Burns of children&rsquo;s show <em>Blues Clues</em> talks about grappling with TV fame.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CwmtkFPYXsg?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I admire the Moth&rsquo;s storytellers. It&rsquo;s not easy speaking in front of a large audience let alone
<a href="/2010/12/how-to-tell-good-stories/">captivating them with a great story</a> without notes.</p>

<p>I often download their latest podcast on Sunday morning and listen to it while biking or jogging.
The Moth makes their podcast free and sometimes has an ad at the end of the podcast. Usually the
ad is for a product or brand that makes sense with The Moth&rsquo;s branding and demographic. I envision
that demographic to be highly educated urbanites ages 30 to 50 who are married and listen to NPR
and skew liberal.</p>

<p>So I was surprised to hear an ad for Voss water in the last two Moth podcasts. Here at 15:08</p>

<p><audio controls><source src='<a'><source src='href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-195-adam-gopnik.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-195-adam-gopnik.mp3</a>&#8217;></audio></p>

<p>and here at 17:30.</p>

<p><audio controls><source src='<a'><source src='href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/the-moth-podcast-194-david-chang.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/the-moth-podcast-194-david-chang.mp3</a>&#8217;></audio></p>

<p>These ads are read by the host Dan Kennedy and include a reason why Moth listeners should buy the
product or subscribe to the brand.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the script for the Voss ad:</p>

<blockquote><p>Voss is the perfect pairing for your special dining moments. A night worth talking about always
  starts with Voss on the table because with Voss comes great conversation. And with a great
  conversation comes a story worth sharing.</p></blockquote>

<p>Am I hearing this right? If I drink bottled water I&rsquo;ll have better conversations and be a rockstar
conversationalist?</p>

<p>Is this brand mismatch? The Moth is a non-profit organization where people share stories. Voss is
a luxury lifestyle product in the form of bottled water. They call it <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artesian_water">artesian water</a> which is
simply water from an aquifer that&rsquo;s under positive pressure. What&rsquo;s so great about that? And even
if this kind of water were all that, there have been allegations that Voss water is really just
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voss_(water)#cite_note-3">tap water</a> in a sleek glass bottle.</p>

<p>But there is a silver lining. Voss has a <a href="http://www.thevossfoundation.org/about/">foundation</a> that helps people in Sub-Saharan Africa
get access to clean drinking water. In 2010 the Voss Foundation
<a href="http://www.thevossfoundation.org/assets/Voss-Foundation-2010-Year-in-Review.pdf">spent $137,346 toward its cause</a>. It seems like a drop in the bucket in solving
<a href="http://www.cfr.org/africa/water-stress-sub-saharan-africa/p11240">Sub-Saharan Africa&rsquo;s water problems</a>, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing.</p>

<p>I think of the situation as a bunch of people buying fancy bottles and transferring their wealth
to a company good at marketing. This company then gives a portion (I have no idea what percentage
because Voss seems to be a private company with no public financial statements) to helping people
who have a hard time finding potable water.</p>

<p><em>Update: Since writing this post The Moth has not had anymore Voss ads in their podcasts. Yay.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light a Fire Under Politicians' Asses]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/light-a-fire-under-politicians-asses/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/light-a-fire-under-politicians-asses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The inner populist in me is heartened to see the Occupy Wall Street movement grow and even
<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/16/world/occupy-wall-street-protests-worldwide.html?hp">spread to other countries</a>. It&rsquo;s about time the penny-wise-pound-foolish policies of careerist
politicians and hamstrung governments came back to bite them in the ass.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I want to see the Occupy Wall Street movement not only gain more steam but also to become more
organized and remain vigilantly peaceful. Right now I&rsquo;m not sure what it stands for besides
general malaise. The movement is not a response to the financial crisis or Wall Street barons as
supporters might say. If Wall Street made boatloads of money and Main Street also enjoyed low
unemployment and decent salaries, this movement wouldn&rsquo;t exist. That&rsquo;s why no one occupied Wall
Street in 2008 right after the crash.</p>

<p>Instead, it took three years of high unemployment and falling wages and <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/16/realestate/rents-in-manhattan-rebound-to-record-highs.html">rising rents</a> to
slowly generate this movement. Occupy Wall Street supporters are demonstrating more against the
political elite not the financial elite. It&rsquo;s the political elite who didn&rsquo;t fix things afterward
the financial elite fucked up. Now the commoners are thinking &ldquo;wait, if the people in charge are
incompetent, what gives them the right to rule?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s some insightful analysis by George Friedman of Stratfor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
