<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Food & Drink | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/food-and-drink/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-05-02T23:46:21+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make Chocolate Soufflé, Sauce, and Truffles]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/12/how-to-make-chocolate-souffle-sauce-and-truffles/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/12/how-to-make-chocolate-souffle-sauce-and-truffles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On October 30, I attended Mehdi Chellaoui&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.skillshare.com/Intro-to-Chocolate-workshop/1123695509/534026005">Intro to Chocolate</a> workshop. It was the perfect
laid-back class to do on a brisk Sunday afternoon. Mehdi held his class on the second floor of
Zabar&rsquo;s, a grocery and kitchenware store on 80th Street and Broadway.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>He worked on a large table in front of an audience of about 26 people. Most were middle-aged and
elderly women. Some were shopping at Zabar&rsquo;s and happened to hear the announcement of the free
chocolate class over the loudspeaker. I was one of only four guys in attendance. We learned how to
make chocolate soufflé with Grand Marnier, chocolate sauce, and Ganache truffles. (See recipes
below).</p>

<p>Mehdi and the Zabar staff ran the class in a very organized way. They started and stopped exactly
on time. They handed out the recipes and even served everyone a sample of each at the end. The
audience paid rapt attention and asked a lot of questions. The older they were the more questions
they asked.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How do you &lsquo;temper&rsquo; chocolate?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Do you need to use a marble slab to cool and agitate the hot chocolate?&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Chocolate Soufflé with Grand Marnier</h3>

<p>Serves 4</p>

<ul>
<li>Butter and granulated sugar, for the soufflé mold</li>
<li>4 ounces (115g) Guittard semisweet or bittersweet chocolate</li>
<li>4 tablespoons (&frac12; stick; 60g) unsalted butter</li>
<li>4 eggs, separated</li>
<li>grated zest of 1 orange</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Grand Marnier</li>
<li>1/8 teaspoon cream of tartar</li>
<li><p>confectioners&#8217; sugar, for dusting</p></li>
<li><p>Preheat oven to 475°F with the oven rack in the lowest position. Butter and sugar a 4-cup
soufflé mold.</p></li>
<li>In a small saucepan, combine the chocolate and butter and melt over low heat. Remove from the
heat, whisk in the egg yolks, and pour into a large bowl. Stir in the grated orange zest and
Grand Marnier.</li>
<li>In a large bowl, beat the egg whites with the cream of tartar until stiff peaks form.</li>
<li>With a whisk, fold one-third of the beaten egg whites into the chocolate mixture. Fold in the
remaining egg whites with a rubber spatula. Pour into the prepared soufflé mold and level the
surface with a spatula. Run your thumb around the top of the mold to clean off any excess batter.
(The soufflé can be prepared ahead to this point; see &ldquo;Preparing Soufflés for the Oven Ahead of
Time,&rdquo; page 264.)</li>
<li>Bake the soufflé for 5 minutes. Lower the temperature to 425°F and bake until the soufflé has
risen 3 to 4 inches above the top of the mold and is springy to the touch, another 4 to 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Dust the soufflé with confectioners&#8217; sugar and serve immediately.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Chocolate Sauce</h3>

<p>Makes &frac34; cup</p>

<ul>
<li>4 ounces (115g) Guittard semisweet or bittersweet chocolate</li>
<li><p>&frac12; cup water (see note)</p></li>
<li><p>in a small saucepan, melt the chocolate with the water over medium heat, about 2 minutes. When
the water and chocolate come to a boil, stir gently with a whisk until smooth. If the sauce is
too thin, cook it longer. If it is too thick, add more liquid and stir to blend well.</p></li>
<li>Remove the sauce from the heat and serve hot or cold. Refrigerate any leftovers. Note: Use only
&frac14; cup water for a thick sauce.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Ganache Truffles**</h3>

<p>Makes 80 to 90 pieces (2 pounds)</p>

<p>Truffle Mixture</p>

<ul>
<li>12 ounces (340g) Guittard semisweet or bittersweet chocolate</li>
<li>1 cup heavy cream</li>
<li>3 tablespoons Grand Marnier or other liqueur</li>
</ul>


<p>Chocolate Covering</p>

<ul>
<li>1 pound (450g) Guittard semisweet or bittersweet chocolate</li>
<li><p>2 ounces (60g) Guittard unsweetened cocoa powder</p></li>
<li><p>Make the truffle mixture: in a saucepan, heat the chocolate and heavy cream over low heat,
stirring occasinoally until the chocolate is melted.</p></li>
<li>Remove from the heat and pour into a bowl. Stir in the Grand Marnier. Place the mixture in the
refrigerator until it is firm, a minimum of 2 hours.</li>
<li>Cover a baking sheet with a piece of waxed paper. Using two spoons, scoop out and drop mounds
of &frac12; to 1 teaspoonful, depending on the size you wish to make, onto the paper. Refrigerate
overnight.</li>
<li>When cold, loosen the mounds from the paper and use your fingers to make them as round as you
can, if not already so. Refrigerate until ready to coat.</li>
<li>Make the chocolate covering: In an overproof saucepan, melt the chocolate in a very low oven
(see &ldquo;Melting Chocolate,&rdquo; page 294).</li>
<li>When the chocolate has melted, stir it well from time to time as it cools to body temperature.
(This is determined when you notice no difference in temperature when you touch the chocolate with
the knuckle of your smallest finger.)</li>
<li>Lift the cocoa powder evenly onto a chilld jelly-roll pan or plate.</li>
<li>Remove the truffles form the refrigerator and drop two at a time into the coating chocolate.
Using two forks, turn the truffles, coating them well with chocolate. Lift a truffle with one
fork, tapping that fork with the other to knock off excess chocolate, then drop the coated truffle
onto the pan containing the cocoa powder. Using a spoon, quickly roll and coat with the powder,
then push it to the side.</li>
<li>When the coating has cooled and teh truffles are firm enough tot handle, transfer them to a
bowl and refrigerate or freeze until ready to serve. (They will keep well in the refrigerator for
about 2 weeks and can be stored in the freezer for several months.)</li>
<li>To serve: Mound the truffles in a serving dish. They are delicious when served at room
temperature or cold from the refrigerator.</li>
</ul>


<p>From <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0761158545/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0761158545"><em>French Classics Made Easy</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0761158545" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wisdom of Traditional Cuisines]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/the-wisdom-of-traditional-cuisines/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/the-wisdom-of-traditional-cuisines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading Michael Pollan&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143038583/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=0143038583"><em>The Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0143038583&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369" alt="" />, I learned how much wisdom
traditional cuisines embodied and that certain foods are eaten together not only because they
taste good but because there are health benefits.</p>

<p>The Japanese eat raw fish, which can contain bacteria, with wasabi, a potent anti-microbial.
Strong spices of cuisines originating from tropical areas have antibacterial properties because
food is likely to spoil in hot temperatures. Asian cuisine often combines soy ingredients with
rice because this makes these foods more nutritious than when eaten alone.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Many Meso-American dishes are prepared by cooking corn with lime and eating it with beans. Cooking
corn with an alkali such as lime, allows its <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niacin">niacin</a>, an essential human nutrient, to be
absorbed by our bodies. If you didn&rsquo;t eat niacin, your skin would peel off, you&rsquo;d become
paralyzed, and you&rsquo;d slowly go crazy. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pellagra">pellagra</a>. So corn and niacin are good
stuff, but you&rsquo;d still lack a complete set of essential amino acids. That&rsquo;s where the beans come
in. Corn and beans lack essential amino acids lysine and methionine, respectively, and by eating
both you&rsquo;re good to go.</p>

<p>So skip the Jenny Craig, South Beach, Atkins diet. Eat traditional cuisine. Would you rather trust
millennia of passed down knowledge or Jenny Craig and some American cardiologists?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funny Fortune Cookies]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/funny-fortune-cookies/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/funny-fortune-cookies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img center <a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/Tc21KUosp7I/AAAAAAAAAzc/cUdr3Gaqc58/s400/fortune%20cookie2.jpg">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/Tc21KUosp7I/AAAAAAAAAzc/cUdr3Gaqc58/s400/fortune%20cookie2.jpg</a> 400 300 %}</p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/Tc21HhP9niI/AAAAAAAAAzU/dN_os52w7SE/s400/fortune%20cookie1.jpg">https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/Tc21HhP9niI/AAAAAAAAAzU/dN_os52w7SE/s400/fortune%20cookie1.jpg</a> 400 300 So what do I do when the moment comes? %}</p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/Tc21KMSpmNI/AAAAAAAAAzY/FXx_ntaOhrE/s400/fortune%20cookie3.jpg">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/Tc21KMSpmNI/AAAAAAAAAzY/FXx_ntaOhrE/s400/fortune%20cookie3.jpg</a> 400 300 I don&rsquo;t have any clean party clothes %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smarter Ways to Produce Food]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/smarter-ways-to-produce-food/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/smarter-ways-to-produce-food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After attempting to read some pretty simplistic and unsophisticated books like <em>What Would Google
Do</em> and <em>The World is Flat</em>, I finally got around to reading <em>The Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma</em>. Yes. Thank
you, Michael Pollan for being nuanced and thorough and writing like a real investigative
journalist. You&rsquo;ve established trust as an author.</p>

<p>So well written, and detailed. Pollan&rsquo;s book made me sad, indignant, hopeful. I seriously came
almost to tears at some points.</p>

<p>If you want to know where your dinner comes from, please pick up this book. If you don&rsquo;t care
enough about yourself to even try to understand the stuff you&rsquo;re putting into your own stomach,
then you&rsquo;re only doing yourself a disservice.</p>

<p>Food was always very important in my family. Coming from a Chinese background - back in China,
most people put a very high premium on freshness and quality of food. The food industry in China
is no where as developed as the one in the US, so there are still many local open-air markets that
sell fresh produce and live chickens and fish that local farmers bring to town. Compare this to
the ridiculous extent to which Americans have industrialized their food. Microwaveable TV dinners,
Easy Mac that cooks in 1 minute, the countless combinations of processed foods all made
essentially from corn and soy.</p>

<p>Pollan explains how the US&#8217; way of growing, processing, and distributing food is unsustainable,
contributes to obesity, and uproots humans from nature.</p>

<p>Externalities makes capitalism faulty
The Problems of Externalities in Capitalism</p>

<p>OD 243 Joel Salatin: &ldquo;Whenever I hear people say clean food is expensive, I tell them it&rsquo;s
actually the cheapest food you can buy. That always gets their attention. Then I explain that with
our food all of the costs are figured into the price. Society is not bearing the cost of water
pollution, of antibiotic resistance, of food-borne illnesses, of crop subsidies, of subsidized oil
and water - of all the hidden costs to the environment and the taxpayer that make cheap food
<em>seem</em> cheap. No thinking person will tell you they don&rsquo;t care about all that. I tell them the
choice is simple: You can buy honestly priced food or you can buy irresponsibly priced food.&rdquo;</p>

<p>It would be a great rule, that in order to eat meat, people should remind themselves of what it
means to the animal. To eat a chicken, you must first experience the act of killing a chicken.
We&rsquo;ve gotten too disconnected from the domestic animals we depend on. We&rsquo;ve lost touch with other
life forms. We need to get reacquainted with Mother Nature.</p>

<p>Make slaughterhouses glass for transparency.</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;q=cache:ABPgzgRshSQJ:artsites.ucsc.edu/faculty/gustafson/FILM%2520161.F08/readings/berger.animals%25202.pdf+why+look+at+animals&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=us&amp;pid=bl&amp;srcid=ADGEESgFI8j5p846MQ9ArZ7WsCRbrUzHJfsViJxsiBmM4hfsnVSWjuA7EKxBHWeB-xPbLdzKWvaRCq1y7Kb4qWP1AtWn1WwB3G49PdK6a7rAAin-nCGbv-4QgPKMU363xOBT3E7T__j1&amp;sig=AHIEtbQnx283SntTPKB55G_Ai346f39OWg">Why look at animals?</a> by John Berger</p>

<p>OD 318: &ldquo;A tension has always existed between the capitalist imperative to maximize efficiency at
any cost and the moral imperatives of culture, which historically have served as a counterweight
to the moral blindness of the market. This is another example of the cultural contradictions of
capitalism - the tendency over time for the economic impulse to erode the moral underpinnings of
society. Mercy toward the animals in our care is one such casualty.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Killing Animals</p>

<p>In the second section of Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma, Pollan writes about his experience on Polyface Farms,
an organic, local farm. He includes this quote by farm-owner Joel Salatin:</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr %}
Me and the folks who buy my food are like the Indians - we just want to opt out. That&rsquo;s all the
Indians every wanted - to keep their teepees, to give their kids herbs instead of patent medicines
and leeches. They didn&rsquo;t care if there was a Washington, D.C., or a Custer or a USDA; just leave
us alone. But the Western mind can&rsquo;t bear an opt-out option. We&rsquo;re going to have to refight the
Battle of the Little Big Horn to preserve the right to opt out, or your grandchildren and mine
will have no choice but to eat amalgamated, irradiated, genetically prostituted, bar-coded,
adulterated fecal spam from the centralized processing conglomerate.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>Them is fightin&#8217; words.</p>

<p>A better way to farm would be to emulate Mother Nature&rsquo;s closed-loop biological systems. On
Salatin&rsquo;s farm, the cows are allowed to graze on pastures but rotated to prevent overgrazing.
Grazing stimulates grass&#8217; root growth. The cows provide natural manure. Then a mobile henhouse is
brought in. The hens pick the cowpats for insects and thus spread out the manure to fertilize the
grass and eliminate parasites. Chickens also provide nitrogen for the greass. Their eggs taste
better and they&rsquo;re raised more humanely.</p>

<p>But Whole Foods does not buy from this type of farm. To have a business this large, you are forced
to buy from big suppliers because of the high transaction costs of dealing with hundreds of small
ones. page 161 OD: &ldquo;As soon as your business involves stocking the frozen food case or produce
section at a national chain, whether it be Wal-Mart or Whole Foods, the sheer quantities of
organic produce you need makes it imperative to buy from farms operating on the same industrial
scale you are. Everything&rsquo;s connected. The industrial values of specialization, economies of
scale, and mechanization wind up crowding out ecological values such as diversity, complexity, and
symbiosis.&rdquo;</p>

<p>One of my friends doubted wether small-scale farms would be able to save us energy or feed
everyone. But we&rsquo;re not feeding everyone. We&rsquo;re feeding the majority of Americans well. Some too
well as witnessed by rising obesity rates and obesity-related illnesses. But many people in the
world suffer from starvation and malnutrition. And according to Pollan (page 161, Omnivore&rsquo;s
Dilemma) small farms are more productive on a per acre basis than large farms.</p>

<p>OD 200: &ldquo;So feeding ruminants corn came to make a certain economic sense - I say &#8220;certain&rdquo; because
that statement depends on the particular method of accounting our economy applies to such
questions, one that tends to hide the high cost of cheap food produced from corn. The
ninety-nine-cent price of a fast-food hamburger simply doesn&rsquo;t take account of that meal&rsquo;s true
cost - to soil, oil, public health, the public purse, etc., costs of which are never charged
directly to the consumer but, indirectly and invisibly, to the taxpayer (in the form of
subsidies), the health care system (in the form of food-borne illnesses and obesity), and the
environment (in the form of pollution), not to mention the welfare of the workers in the feedlot
and the slaughterhouse and the welfare of the animals themselves. If not for this sort of
blind-man&rsquo;s accounting, grass would make a lot more sense than it now does.&#8221;</p>

<p>OD 214: &ldquo;&lsquo;Efficiency&rsquo; is the term usually invoked to defend large-scale industrial farms, and it
usually refers to the economies of scale that can be achieved by the application of technology and
standardization. Yet Joel Salatin&rsquo;s farm makes the case for a very different sort of efficiency -
the one found in natural systems, with the coevolutionary relationships and reciprocal loops. For
example, in nature there is no such thing as a waste problem, since one creature&rsquo;s waste becomes
another creature&rsquo;s lunch.&rdquo;</p>

<p>mimic relationships found in nature instead of working against her. Both animals and humans gain
by letting them do what they naturally are disposed to do. It&rsquo;s not natural to cram hens in cages,
snipping their beaks, tail docking pigs, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Organic Food Myths Debunked]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/organic-food-myths-debunked/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/organic-food-myths-debunked</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>A follow-up to my post on the <a href="/2010/08/29/recalled-eggs-and-americas-food-problems">great salmonella-tainted-egg recall</a>.</em></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been skeptical of organic foods. &ldquo;What does &lsquo;organic&rsquo; really mean?&rdquo; I asked my friends
who went ga-ga for thistle milk at farmers&#8217; markets and bought labels like Kashi Go Lean. &ldquo;No
chemicals or synthetics,&rdquo; they said. But was that <em>really</em> true?</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the United States Department of Agriculture&rsquo;s (USDA) <a href="http://www.nal.usda.gov/afsic/pubs/ofp/ofp.shtml">definition of &ldquo;organic&rdquo;</a> as of
2007. But many companies who want to tap into the lucrative organic market no doubt hire lobbyists
and creatively interpret their way around standards to get that &ldquo;organic&rdquo; sticker slapped onto
their packages.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>An excerpt from Wikipedia on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Organic_certification">organic certification</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Critics of formal certification also fear an erosion of organic standards. Provided with a legal
  framework within which to operate, lobbyists can push for amendments and exceptions favorable to
  large-scale production, resulting in &ldquo;legally organic&rdquo; products produced in ways similar to
  current <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/07/02/AR2009070203365.html">conventional food</a>.</p>

<p>Manipulation of certification regulations as a way to mislead or outright dupe the public is a
  very real concern. Some examples are creating exceptions (allowing non-organic inputs to be used
  without loss of certification status) and creative interpretation of standards to meet the letter,
  but not the intention, of particular rules&hellip;</p>

<p>In December 2005, the 2006 agricultural appropriations bill was passed with a rider allowing 38
  synthetic ingredients to be used in organic foods. Among the ingredients are food colorings,
  starches, sausage and hot-dog casings, hops, fish oil, chipotle chili pepper, and gelatin. This
  allowed Anheuser-Busch in 2007 to have its Wild Hop Lager certified organic &ldquo;even though [it] uses
  <a href="http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/html/nationworld/2003741899_organic10.html">hops</a> grown with <a href="http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m3301/is_12_106/ai_n27863714">chemical fertilizers</a> and sprayed with pesticides.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>The truth is that &ldquo;organic&rdquo; does not mean no synthetics. The USDA allows the use of certain
synthetics after Congress passed a 2006 appropriations bill (you can see a <a href="http://www.opencongress.org/bill/109-h2744/show">summary</a> of it on
<a href="http://www.opencongress.org">OpenCongress.org</a>). Hard-core, earthy, stick-it-to-the-man organic food hippies were outraged,
while big organic food companies celebrated. This bill allowed the use of 38 synthetic items
without the loss of USDA organic certification. These items <a href="http://www.thedailygreen.com/healthy-eating/eat-safe/3980">include</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>celery powder</li>
<li>natural sausage casings</li>
<li>18 colors extracts from annatto seeds, beets, carrots, etc</li>
<li>fructo-oligosaccharides</li>
<li>hops</li>
</ul>


<p>My first reaction: these don&rsquo;t sound very synthetic. They sound&hellip;organic, natural. What&rsquo;s the fuss
about? It turns out these items are produced by non-organic means, i.e. chemical fertilizers and
pesticides. But still, it&rsquo;s not like the list contains tongue-twisting compounds that sound like
they&rsquo;d give you cancer. So is the <em>Seattle Times</em>&lsquo; headline for the article
&ldquo;&rsquo;<a href="http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/html/nationworld/2003741899_organic10.html">Organic&#8217; food rule could have up to 38 loopholes</a>&rdquo; overreacting?</p>

<p>After reading Michael Pollan&#8217;s <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143038583?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0143038583">Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma</a></em> I learned about the legislative and
social battles waged to define &ldquo;organic&rdquo; and the distinction between the organic food movement and
the organic food industry. The organic food movement dates back to the early 20th century in
response to industrial agriculture. The organic food industry manifests itself in large
corporations like Whole Foods.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll write more about this later. In the meantime, amuse yourself with the article
<a href="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/can-an-organic-twinkie-be-certified.pdf">&ldquo;Can an Organic Twinkie Be Certified?&rdquo;</a> And here&rsquo;s an <a href="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/nop-hr2744-summary.pdf">interesting summary</a> to Congress
written by this National Organic Program organization. I wonder what they&rsquo;re about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
