<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Spy Shit | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/spy-shit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-07T12:59:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Should All Care About Digital Privacy]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2015/05/why-we-should-all-care-about-digital-privacy/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2015/05/why-we-should-all-care-about-digital-privacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been reading and thinking a lot about digital privacy in the past two weeks. It&rsquo;s
disconcerting that so many AMericans are resigned about the current state of digital surveillance.
Before the Snowden leaks, one could plausibly deny the vast extent of mass digital surveillance,
but in this post-Snowden era, this is increasingly hard to do without appearing like you live under
a rock.</p>

<p>I recently watched two videos which explain the disturbing extent to which intelligence agencies
like the NSA have gone to subvert encryption algorithms and to sabotage critical Internet
infrastructure. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0SgGMj3Mf88" title="Jacob Appelbaum: Reconstructing narratives - transparency in the service of justice [31c3]">this video</a>, Jacob Appelbaum and Laura Poitras talk about how reading
through documents leaked by Snowden has led them to believe the spooks have compromised everything
including PPTP, IPSec, and even SSH. Everything except for PGP (implementations include GnuPG), OTR
(implementions include Pidgin and Adium), and ZRTP (implementations include the Signal and RedPhone
mobile apps).</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0SgGMj3Mf88?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The second video I watched was a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwcl17Q0bpk" title="NSA operation ORCHESTRA: Annual Status Report">talk by Poul-Henning Kamp</a> in which he pretends
to be an NSA officer giving a status report to NATO. Kamp talks about the various technical and
psychological operations the NSA and its associated intelligence agencies use to collect all
digital communications. I&rsquo;m not sure how much of what Kamp says is true as some parts are
deliberately tongue in cheek, but none of them seem impossible. Here are just a few:</p>

<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=5m48s">NSA spots a startup</a> that&rsquo;s developing a product that strengthens privacy and thus
makes the NSA&rsquo;s job harder. They send someone who poses as a venture capitalist. He invests money
in the startup and gets insider knowledge on what they&rsquo;re making. NSA looks through their
Rolodex of friendly companies for someone with a patent that&rsquo;s related to the startup&rsquo;s
product. They convince the company to let loose some patent lawyer trolls on the startup. The
startup folds or needs to work on something else under legal duress. The founders call the fake
VC back saying how sorry they were to waste the VC&rsquo;s money. The NSA bites its tongue trying not to
laugh and busts out the champange bottles.</li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=9m47s">Skype&rsquo;s encrypted VoIP product was a threat</a> to the NSA being able to listen in on all telephone
calls. Skype didn&rsquo;t use standard protocols, was closed-source, was outside the jurisdiction of
the FTC, and the NSA couldn&rsquo;t bribe the founders of Skype to stop. So the NSA pressured
eBay to acquire the company which eBay did. But eBay&rsquo;s lawyers bungled the deal and didn&rsquo;t
get access to the source code or control the infrastructure. So the NSA made eBay sell it back
to the founders at a loss. eBay wasn&rsquo;t too happy about this. And then the NSA had to spend a lot
more money making Microsoft acquire Skype. But it was worth it because this time Microsoft got
all of Skype and made the traffic <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/11/microsoft-nsa-collaboration-user-data" title="Microsoft handed the NSA access to encrypted messages">go through Microsoft servers</a> where it could be decrypted.</li>
<li>How the NSA regularly <a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=20m19s">derails and slows down open source work</a> by appealing to people&rsquo;s fear,
uncertainty, and doubt; playing the GPL vs BSD card; spawning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law_of_triviality" title="Parkinson's law of triviality">bikeshed discussions</a>; and
soaking up mental bandwidth with bogus crypto proposals.</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->




<iframe class="fill-width" width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fwcl17Q0bpk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I&rsquo;ve tried to verify for myself what Appelbaum and Poitras said. There&rsquo;s a lot of discussion on
what the intelligence agencies have cracked and what&rsquo;s still safe. Has the NSA compromised SSH in
general or only in targeted cases? But I wonder if this discussion is useful or if it misses the
point as Kamp inspiringly points out at the end of his talk.</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Poul-Henning Kamp <a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=30m8s">https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=30m8s</a> %}
So the standard reaction in the open source environment to Edward Snowden&rsquo;s disclosures have been,
&ldquo;We need to strengthen the protocols! We need to have SSL everywhere.&rdquo; And I think that misses the
point by a large margin. The things that have been published by the Snowden documents by now are
the things that the general public can understand reading their newspaper. The stuff we would be
interested in have not been published and maybe never will. And attempting to add more encryption
is most likely just going to have more broken encryption on the Internet.</p>

<p><strong>This is not a technical problem. This is a political problem. It must be solved by political means.</strong>
That means find politicians in your country who can understand this and make sure they understand
it. If you cannot find politicians, get you some politicians who can understand it. Political will
is a renewable resource. Use your pencil when you vote. Or run yourself.</p>

<p><strong>This is your children&rsquo;s and grandchildren&rsquo;s future society you&rsquo;re looking at. And we&rsquo;re the guys
who sort of missed the boat.</strong>
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>If a guy who&rsquo;s been committing to the FreeBSD kernel for over 15 years says he doesn&rsquo;t see a
technical solution to mass digital surveillance, he&rsquo;s probably got a point. He doesn&rsquo;t see a
technical solution because he cited the enormous amounts of money and manpower intelligence agencies
have compared with the measly resources of open source contributors. The Director of National
Intelligence, the overseer of all US intelligence agencies, requested $53.9 billion for the
National Intelligence Program&rsquo;s budget in 2016. Even if a small portion of that funded domestic spying
programs, that&rsquo;s still a lot of money. Meanwhile, <a href="http://www.propublica.org/article/the-worlds-email-encryption-software-relies-on-one-guy-who-is-going-broke" title="The World's Email Encryption Software Relies on One Guy, Who is Going Broke">up until recently</a>, Werner Koch who wrote GnuPG,
a crucial piece of the world&rsquo;s encryption software, was struggling to raise just $25,000 a year.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been struggling to understand why we Americans are either too apathetic or resigned to fight
for our privacy rights. I think it&rsquo;s because digital privacy is hard to understand and it&rsquo;s not
in-your-face spying like finding a camera in your bedroom or a GPS tracker underneath your car.
Some people believe the costs of giving up their privacy is outweighed by the supposed effectiveness
in stopping terrorism. In most of my conversations, people believe domestic spying is wrong
but think resistance is futile. They simply say &ldquo;I have nothing to hide.&rdquo;</p>

<p>This simple statement is pernicious and damaging to not just civil society as a whole but also
for our future generations. Mass surveillance isn&rsquo;t an individual problem. It&rsquo;s a collective
problem. I don&rsquo;t have anything to hide from the spooks, but that doesn&rsquo;t mean I&rsquo;m going to give my
government a free pass for spying on its citizens. Just because I&rsquo;m doing well as an individual
doesn&rsquo;t mean I throw the group to which I belong under the bus. We don&rsquo;t live in a vacuum, and
each of our actions or inactions affect those around us.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve drawn a flow chart of my argument of why we should stop mass surveillance below.</p>

<p><a href="https://i.imgur.com/athtKWxh.jpg">{% img center https://i.imgur.com/athtKWxh.jpg 640 480 %}</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter Frequency Analysis]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/letter-frequency-analysis/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/letter-frequency-analysis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This page analyzes a text&rsquo;s letter frequency and is an emulation of <a href="http://rumkin.com/tools/cipher/frequency.php">Tyler Atkin&rsquo;s page</a>. One
application is decoding a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caesar_cipher">Caesar cipher</a>. A Caesar or &ldquo;shift&rdquo; cipher is an encryption
technique in which each letter in the unencrypted message is shifted over a certain number of
positions. For example, A encodes into B and B into C. The cipher is named after Julius Caesar who
reportedly used a shift cipher of three to communicate with his generals.</p>

<p>So how do we break a Caesar cipher? One technique is to analyze its letter frequency. In English,
certain letters like E and T occur more frequently than others like Q and Z. By getting the shape
of the letter frequency distribution and comparing it to the known relative letter frequencies of
the English language, we can sometimes determine if a Caesar cipher was used.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Enter text into the box below to see its letter frequency. Click the plus and minus signs to alter
the plaintext by changing the amount the alphabet is shifted.
<span id="insert-sample">[Click here][3]</span> for a demo.</p>

<h3>Ciphertext</h3>

<p><textarea id="ciphertext" style="width:700px; height:100px;"></textarea></p>

<p><span id="shift-buttons">
  <a href="#" id="shift-up" style="text-decoration:none;font-size:22px;">+</a>
  <a href="#" id="shift-down" style="text-decoration:none;font-size:22px;">-</a>
</span></p>

<h3>Shifted plaintext</h3>

<div><span id="plaintext"></span></div>


<h3>Result</h3>

<p><span id="standard-freqs"></span><br />
<span id="output" style="position:absolute;top:0;z-index:-1;"></span>
</div></p>




]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wikileaks' Cablegate Tag Wordle]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/12/wikileaks-cablegate-tag-wordle/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/12/wikileaks-cablegate-tag-wordle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a frequency analysis on the tags of all 251,287 Wikileaks diplomatic cables and created a
Wordle word cloud. Size is positively related to frequency. You can download the basic data set
from <em>The Guardian</em> (sorry, no text included) <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/news/datablog/2010/nov/29/wikileaks-cables-data">here</a>, and create your own Wordle <a href="http://www.wordle.net/">here</a>. The
meanings of the tags are <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/pub?key=0Auo8KSVAc9r8dHdnMGhjOXhhNzY0LTE0M0NqNmNTRHc&amp;hl=en&amp;output=html">here</a>.</p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://lh3.ggpht.com/-DkELRSEMINg/TyB8ScldhKI/AAAAAAAAAAA/JXdRj5UZ_sg/s640/cablegate+tags+wordle.png">https://lh3.ggpht.com/-DkELRSEMINg/TyB8ScldhKI/AAAAAAAAAAA/JXdRj5UZ_sg/s640/cablegate+tags+wordle.png</a> 522 340 Wikileaks&#8217; Cablegate Tag Wordle %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Spy? No! Look at Her Hydrangeas!]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/06/a-spy-no-look-at-her-hydrangeas/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/06/a-spy-no-look-at-her-hydrangeas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recent news about FBI busting into suburban homes and handcuffing couples they accuse of being
Russian spies are quite intriguing and ridiculous. The <em>Times</em> has an <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/29/world/europe/29spy.html?fta=y">article</a> with a money
quote:</p>

<blockquote><p>Jessie Gugig, 15, said she could not believe the charges, especially against Mrs. Murphy. &ldquo;They
  couldn&rsquo;t have been spies,&rdquo; she said jokingly. &ldquo;Look what she did with the hydrangeas.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p>Investigators have accused the 11 individuals of penetrating American &ldquo;policy making circles.&rdquo; Huh?
Can we be more specific here? Regardless of what&rsquo;s true, this is some serious spy novel/Tom Clancy
stuff.</p>

<blockquote><p>But the network of so-called illegals — spies operating under false names outside of diplomatic
  cover — also used cyber-age technology, according to the charges. They embedded coded texts in
  ordinary-looking images posted on the Internet, and they communicated by having two agents with
  laptops containing special software pass casually as messages flashed between them.</p></blockquote>

<p>Meanwhile, Putin&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/30/world/europe/30lavrov.html?ref=global-home">not happy</a> about this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can We Please Get Some Qualified People?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2009/05/can-we-please-get-some-qualified-people/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2009/05/can-we-please-get-some-qualified-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you think of the CIA, you may envision an elite squad of the brightest and most daring
individuals in the country equipped with <a href="http://popsci.typepad.com/popsci/2006/12/the_15_best_bon.html" title="the 15 best Bond gadgets of all time">state-of-the-art gadgets and weapons</a>. You may
imagine them penetrating into the highest echelons of terrorist groups and working deep undercover
in the most hostile foreign nations. You may see them defending America&rsquo;s national security by
reporting invaluable intelligence procured by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zc9y7T8JIVE">deftly cultivating relationships with defectors</a>
and suavely deceiving the unsuspecting.</p>

<p>Forget whatever image of the CIA that Hollywood or Tom Clancy portray. The truth is a lot less
glamorous and a whole lot more disturbing.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Tim Weiner collected and analyzed more than 50,000 documents from the CIA archives; more than 2
000 oral histories of American intelligence officers, soldiers, and diplomats; and more than 300
interviews with those who&rsquo;ve worked at the Agency. The result was his latest book, <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/style/longterm/books/chap1/legacyofashes.htm" title="book excerpt - chapter 1"><em>Legacy of
Ashes: The History of the CIA</em></a> (200).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307389006/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0307389006&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=easiamus00-20" title="">{% img left http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/51qrPWpbewL.<em>SL160</em>.jpg &lsquo;Legacy of Ashes: The History of the CIA&rsquo; %}</a></p>

<p>Weiner begins with the creation of the CIA in 1947 as a civilian intelligence agency whose main
objective was to check the spread of communism during the Cold War. In the long run, the CIA was
meant to be the eyes and ears of the President, an intelligence organization informing executive
decision-making by collecting and analyzing intelligence of foreign events, politics, cultures,
and people. In short, it was supposed to speak truth to power. Weiner argues the CIA has failed to
live up to its mission from its very inception. It has left in its wake of failures, in the words
of President Dwight D. Eisenhower, a &ldquo;legacy of ashes.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The CIA&rsquo;s track record is quite appalling. It has a great reputation (well, maybe it once did) but
a terrible record. Abroad, they planned coups and assassinations, rigged elections, and
negligently left their own agents to be captured, interrogated, and executed by the regimes of
Stalin and Mao. Domestically, they told bald-faced lies presidents and, when they did tell the
truth, persuaded the Commander in Chief to lie to Congress to cover its ass. With all the billions
of dollars laundered to them through various means, you&rsquo;d think they&rsquo;d provide somewhat decent
intelligence on major world events. But the CIA was caught with their pants down for the Bay of
Pigs, Cuban Missile Crisis, the fall of the Soviet Union, and much more.</p>

<p>One of the Agency&rsquo;s biggest problems is attracting and recruiting the right kind of talent for its
work. All too often, incompetent careerists, provincial old boys who attended Groton then Yale
then Harvard Law, and vainglorious but myopic leaders are calling the shots whose stakes include
thousands of lives, disgusting amounts of tax-payer dollars, and America&rsquo;s reputation and values.
Eisenhower said it takes a &ldquo;strange kind of genius&rdquo; to run the CIA. Weiner writes this genius
requires, at the very least,</p>

<blockquote><p>men and women with the discipline and self-sacrifice of the nation&rsquo;s best military officers, the
  cultural awareness and historical knowledge of the nation&rsquo;s best diplomats, and the sense of
  curiosity and adventure possessed by the nation&rsquo;s best foreign correspondents.</p></blockquote>

<p>We have yet to consistently see officers of this caliber at the CIA.</p>

<p>The end of Legacy of Ashes is extremely infuriating and upsetting to read. It is about the years
leading up to September 11, 2001. Top leaders of the American intelligence community knew on
September 11, 1998 that if they didn&rsquo;t fix the CIA, they would have a &ldquo;catastrophic systemic
intelligence failure.&rdquo; That failure came exactly three years later. Weiner
writes,</p>

<blockquote><p>It was a systemic failure of American government – the White House, the National Security Council,
  the FBI, the Federal Aviation Administration, the Immigration and Naturalization Service, the
  congressional intelligence committees. It was a failure of policy and diplomacy. It was a failure
  of the reporters who covered the government to understand and convey its disarray to their reade
  But above all it was a failure to know the enemy. It was the Pearl Harbor that the CIA had been
  created to prevent.</p></blockquote>

<p>It is so frustrating to learn the CIA had numerous chances to kill Bin Laden before the day his men
steered their planes into the Twin Towers. But the CIA director at the time, George Tenet, had
lost confidence in his agency&rsquo;s ability to be right (for good reason too), so he called off the
strikes every time. Since 2001, the CIA has degenerated into the President&rsquo;s extra-constitutional
international police, arresting without warrants, setting up illegal prisons in third-world
countries, and committing acts of torture.</p>

<p>Weiner does not have an ax to grind with the CIA. He states he wants to see the CIA reformed so
that it can do its job correctly.</p>

<blockquote><p>I hope it may serve as a warning. No republic in history has lasted longer than three hundred
  years [Actually, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Marino" title="San Marino">Republic of San Marino</a> has been around since 301. Sorry, Mr. Weiner, you
  can&rsquo;t always be right], and this nation may not long endure as a great power unless it finds the
  eyes to see things as they are in the world. That once was the mission of the Central Intelligence
  Agency.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
