<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Nature & Outdoors | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/nature-and-outdoors/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-18T10:02:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mushroom Foraging in Waltham]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2021/08/mushroom-foraging-in-waltham/"/>
    <updated>2021-08-07T11:53:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2021/08/mushroom-foraging-in-waltham</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I collected mushrooms this morning with Gloria and my parents. It rained a lot last week in
Waltham, MA. Many mushrooms had sprung up in Prospect Hill Park nearby. The temperature forecast
for today said the highs would be 32°C. So I wanted to go out in the morning while it was not too
hot. Over the objections of my mother, Gloria, my father, and I picked different mushrooms and
carried them back to the car. Next time we&rsquo;ll bring a basket and a trowel. I took them back only to
identify them. I am definitely neither experienced nor confident enough to eat any wild mushrooms I
find.</p>

<p><strong>Do not use this post as any basis for consuming mushrooms yourself. Some mushrooms are extremely
poisonous and can be fatal if ingested.</strong></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s photos of what we found and my amateur guess at what they are.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/Ws1IRx1h.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/Ws1IRx1h.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Russula cremoricolor (Creamy Russula)</h2>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/PThequEh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/PThequEh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/rLu3aqCh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/rLu3aqCh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/bYureAHh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/bYureAHh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/lHr7464h.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/lHr7464h.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<h2>Russula brevipes (Short-Stemmed Russula)</h2>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/j9hEaxbh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/j9hEaxbh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/eO5MxIMh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/eO5MxIMh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/Fq66oRSh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/Fq66oRSh.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<h2>Russula albonigra</h2>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/6d88fa2h.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/6d88fa2h.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/y4vVfllh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/y4vVfllh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/kXXmR1Qh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/kXXmR1Qh.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<h2>Amanita bisporigera (Destroying angel)</h2>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/TdU6v0ih.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/TdU6v0ih.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/W2GwWT2h.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/W2GwWT2h.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<h2>some type of Grisette</h2>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/3xicjwZh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/3xicjwZh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/fA2LEbzh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/fA2LEbzh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/MNauz2Sh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/MNauz2Sh.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<h2>Boletus pseudosensibilis</h2>

<p>We saw what I think is a <a href="https://www.mushroomexpert.com/boletus_pseudosensibilis.html">Boletus pseudosensibilis</a>, but my mom snatched it out of my hands and
threw it away before I could take it home.</p>

<h2>Monotropa uniflora (Ghost pipe)</h2>

<p>Monotropa uniflora isn&rsquo;t a fungus but needs them. It has no chlorophyll and doesn&rsquo;t depend on
photosynthesis. It&rsquo;s a saprophyte that gets nutrients by tapping into the resources of trees,
indirectly through myccorhizal fungi.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/6Vaadzlh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/6Vaadzlh.jpg</a>&#8221;>
<img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/kEvKCqhh.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/kEvKCqhh.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Sailing Class]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-sailing-class/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-24T13:37:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-sailing-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend a bunch of Spotify collleagues and I took our first sailing classes at Manhattan Yacht
Club in Jersey City. I could get used to this sport. The sun was brutal though. I&rsquo;ll never get used
to that.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8hPEr4sa-YM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/g6jwSpXl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/g6jwSpXl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221;></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/rbyvOtml.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/rbyvOtml.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221; title=&#8221;I had to wear a hot and stuffy life vest on a 90-degree day.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>I had to wear a hot and stuffy life vest on a 90-degree day.</div></div></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/5cHxUtKl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/5cHxUtKl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221; title=&#8221;A great view of lower Manhattan.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>A great view of lower Manhattan.</div></div></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/ivnVCYXl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/ivnVCYXl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221; title=&#8221;Sailing close to the Statue of Liberty.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Sailing close to the Statue of Liberty.</div></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skydiving With Friends - Jumping Out of Planes Is Fun]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/skydiving-with-friends-jumping-out-of-planes-is-fun/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-28T10:59:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/skydiving-with-friends-jumping-out-of-planes-is-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On April 16, seven friends and I went skydiving at Skydive the Ranch in New Jersey. We rented
a black SUV (a Hyundai that had terrible acceleration and braking) and each did a tandem dive.
It was a first for many of us including me.</p>

<p>My takeaway was that tandem diving out of a plane at 14-thousand feet is easy. The instructor takes
care of everything. I just had to sit back and enjoy the view. If anything went wrong and I died,
I wouldn&rsquo;t feel that bad about it because I wasn&rsquo;t the one who screwed it up.</p>

<p>Driving seven of your friends out of and back into New York City is nerve-wracking, on the other
hand. I was personally responsible for everyone&rsquo;s lives. Trying to return the rental car on time
while driving through Union Square in Manhattan where
there&rsquo;s a pedestrian fair going on, ambulances and cop cars, and drivers double parking wherever
they want is very stressful.</p>

<p>Hopefully Avis doesn&rsquo;t notice the small white scratch on the mirror of their mint condition car
(18 miles when I got it) that was left when I managed to squeeze through two city buses before they
crushed me.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaSiFui6vt0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ice Climbing at Lake Placid]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/02/ice-climbing-at-lake-placid/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/02/ice-climbing-at-lake-placid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went ice climbing with some friends last weekend at Lake Placid, NY. Although it was physically
punishing, it was a lot of fun. We learned a lot of rope and climbing skills and will definitely
be applying them to our future spelunking or climbing trips.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UeuiadTx5KE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Started Taking Chinese Medicine Seriously]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/why-i-started-taking-chinese-medicine-seriously/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/why-i-started-taking-chinese-medicine-seriously</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Growing up, I scrunched my nose when my mom opened the kitchen cabinet housing our supply of
chinese medicine. Blackened twigs, pungent bark, shriveled roots, orange fungi, and miniature
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calabash">calabash</a> gourd-shaped bottles of black beads. This trove of potions and powders looked
medieval and mysterious. Enveloped during childhood by science books, I dismissed whatever didn&rsquo;t
have a scientific explanation, which included the seeming shamanism of Chinese medicine.</p>

<p>So what changed my mind? If it weren&rsquo;t for Chinese medicine, my birth could&rsquo;ve run into
complications. The chances were slim, but you don&rsquo;t want to mess around with the possibility of
brain and internal organ damage.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Several years ago, my mom told me the story of my birth. I&rsquo;d been hanging around in her womb for
seven months, enjoying free food, oxygen, and even waste disposal. Life was good. The best
position, or &ldquo;presentation&rdquo; if you&rsquo;re an obstetrician, for a fetus to be in during childbirth is
head first, crown outwards (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presentation_(obstetrics)#Classification">vertex, cephalic)</a>. This orientation is associated with the least
complications.</p>

<p>I, however, decided to go with a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breech_presentation">breech</a> or head-up presentation. The obstetrician noticed
this around the seven month period. Not a serious problem yet but not something to be cavalier
about either. She gave my mom some two-part advice about how to correct my position.</p>

<p>The first was to spend some time everyday tilting her head down and bottom up. I am imagining her
practicing a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adho_Mukha_Svanasana">downward dog yoga position</a>. The second was to fumigate the soles of her feet
with dried wormwood.</p>

<p>Okay, this requires some explanation. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_vulgaris">Common wormwood</a> or mugwort, not to be confused with
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_absinthium">grande wormwood</a> or the herb that college students think is the shit in the alcoholic drink
Absinth, is a perennial plant that has many uses in food and herbal medicine. In the middle ages,
mugwort was a protective plant. Today it is sometimes a seasoning ingredient in cuisines ranging
from Japanese to German. Don&rsquo;t eat too much though. Its oil apparently contains a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thujone">chemical</a>
that&rsquo;s toxic in large doses.</p>

<p>My mom bought some dried mugwort rolled into cigar-like tubes, lit them up, and let the smoke shroud
her big toes. Sounds like a bunch of hogwash right? So I did a bit of research and found this on
Wikipedia:</p>

<blockquote><p>In Traditional Chinese medicine there is a belief that moxibustion of mugwort is effective at
  increasing the cephalic positioning of fetuses who were in a breech position before the
  intervention. A Cochrane review in 2005 found that moxibustion may be beneficial in reducing the
  need for ECV, but stressed a need for well-designed randomised controlled trials to evaluate this
  usage. Since it also causes uterine contractions, it has been used to cause abortion.<strong> A study of
  260 Chinese women at 33 weeks of pregnancy demonstrated cephalic version within two weeks in 75%
  of fetuses carried by patients who were treated with moxibustion, as opposed to 48% in the control
  group.</strong> It has also been shown that acupuncture plus moxibustion slows fetal heart rates while
  increasing fetal movement. Two recent studies of Italian patients produced conflicting results. In
  the first, involving 226 patients, there was cephalic presentation at delivery in 54% of women
  treated between 33 and 35 weeks with acupuncture and moxibustion, vs. 37% in the control group.
  The second was terminated prematurely because of poor compliance with treatment, but found no
  difference between moxibustion and control groups.</p></blockquote>

<p>Oh, snap!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
