<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Internet | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/internet/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-02-05T14:13:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet Meme Role Models]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2018/01/internet-meme-role-models/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-07T11:29:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2018/01/internet-meme-role-models</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m compiling a list of Internet meme role models. Here&rsquo;s what I have so far. These people &mdash;
they must be real human beings &mdash; must have either gone out of their way to do the right
thing in a smart manner, something courageous with bonus points for being funny, or just be
ridiculous. And they must be memeified. Exceptions will be made for exceptional but not
memeified people like Hilde Lysiak.</p>

<p>Who else deserves to be on this list?</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b58mzz7mQpg">Snack Man</a> defused a violent fight on the subway between a couple before anyone got hurt. He did
it by standing in between them and munching on Pringles and Gummy Bears.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m9Md78SJO6s">Ben Innes</a> asked the EgyptAir Flight 181 hijacker who comandeered the airplane with a fake
explosive belt if he could take a selfie with him. &ldquo;I thought, why not? If he blows us all up it
won&rsquo;t matter anyway.&rdquo;</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/31/books/hilde-lysiak-child-reporter.html">Hilde Lysiak</a> is ten years old and the writer and publisher of Orange Street News.
She <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ShfNQOUeAY">doesn&rsquo;t take shit from anyone</a>.</li>
<li>Salt Bae is&hellip;well you just have to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xWMWJwXvzWk&amp;t=376s">see for yourself</a>.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Should All Care About Digital Privacy]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2015/05/why-we-should-all-care-about-digital-privacy/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2015/05/why-we-should-all-care-about-digital-privacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been reading and thinking a lot about digital privacy in the past two weeks. It&rsquo;s
disconcerting that so many AMericans are resigned about the current state of digital surveillance.
Before the Snowden leaks, one could plausibly deny the vast extent of mass digital surveillance,
but in this post-Snowden era, this is increasingly hard to do without appearing like you live under
a rock.</p>

<p>I recently watched two videos which explain the disturbing extent to which intelligence agencies
like the NSA have gone to subvert encryption algorithms and to sabotage critical Internet
infrastructure. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0SgGMj3Mf88" title="Jacob Appelbaum: Reconstructing narratives - transparency in the service of justice [31c3]">this video</a>, Jacob Appelbaum and Laura Poitras talk about how reading
through documents leaked by Snowden has led them to believe the spooks have compromised everything
including PPTP, IPSec, and even SSH. Everything except for PGP (implementations include GnuPG), OTR
(implementions include Pidgin and Adium), and ZRTP (implementations include the Signal and RedPhone
mobile apps).</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0SgGMj3Mf88?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The second video I watched was a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwcl17Q0bpk" title="NSA operation ORCHESTRA: Annual Status Report">talk by Poul-Henning Kamp</a> in which he pretends
to be an NSA officer giving a status report to NATO. Kamp talks about the various technical and
psychological operations the NSA and its associated intelligence agencies use to collect all
digital communications. I&rsquo;m not sure how much of what Kamp says is true as some parts are
deliberately tongue in cheek, but none of them seem impossible. Here are just a few:</p>

<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=5m48s">NSA spots a startup</a> that&rsquo;s developing a product that strengthens privacy and thus
makes the NSA&rsquo;s job harder. They send someone who poses as a venture capitalist. He invests money
in the startup and gets insider knowledge on what they&rsquo;re making. NSA looks through their
Rolodex of friendly companies for someone with a patent that&rsquo;s related to the startup&rsquo;s
product. They convince the company to let loose some patent lawyer trolls on the startup. The
startup folds or needs to work on something else under legal duress. The founders call the fake
VC back saying how sorry they were to waste the VC&rsquo;s money. The NSA bites its tongue trying not to
laugh and busts out the champange bottles.</li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=9m47s">Skype&rsquo;s encrypted VoIP product was a threat</a> to the NSA being able to listen in on all telephone
calls. Skype didn&rsquo;t use standard protocols, was closed-source, was outside the jurisdiction of
the FTC, and the NSA couldn&rsquo;t bribe the founders of Skype to stop. So the NSA pressured
eBay to acquire the company which eBay did. But eBay&rsquo;s lawyers bungled the deal and didn&rsquo;t
get access to the source code or control the infrastructure. So the NSA made eBay sell it back
to the founders at a loss. eBay wasn&rsquo;t too happy about this. And then the NSA had to spend a lot
more money making Microsoft acquire Skype. But it was worth it because this time Microsoft got
all of Skype and made the traffic <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/11/microsoft-nsa-collaboration-user-data" title="Microsoft handed the NSA access to encrypted messages">go through Microsoft servers</a> where it could be decrypted.</li>
<li>How the NSA regularly <a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=20m19s">derails and slows down open source work</a> by appealing to people&rsquo;s fear,
uncertainty, and doubt; playing the GPL vs BSD card; spawning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law_of_triviality" title="Parkinson's law of triviality">bikeshed discussions</a>; and
soaking up mental bandwidth with bogus crypto proposals.</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->




<iframe class="fill-width" width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fwcl17Q0bpk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I&rsquo;ve tried to verify for myself what Appelbaum and Poitras said. There&rsquo;s a lot of discussion on
what the intelligence agencies have cracked and what&rsquo;s still safe. Has the NSA compromised SSH in
general or only in targeted cases? But I wonder if this discussion is useful or if it misses the
point as Kamp inspiringly points out at the end of his talk.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>So the standard reaction in the open source environment to Edward Snowden&rsquo;s disclosures have been,
&ldquo;We need to strengthen the protocols! We need to have SSL everywhere.&rdquo; And I think that misses the
point by a large margin. The things that have been published by the Snowden documents by now are
the things that the general public can understand reading their newspaper. The stuff we would be
interested in have not been published and maybe never will. And attempting to add more encryption
is most likely just going to have more broken encryption on the Internet.</p>

<p><strong>This is not a technical problem. This is a political problem. It must be solved by political means.</strong>
That means find politicians in your country who can understand this and make sure they understand
it. If you cannot find politicians, get you some politicians who can understand it. Political will
is a renewable resource. Use your pencil when you vote. Or run yourself.</p>

<p><strong>This is your children&rsquo;s and grandchildren&rsquo;s future society you&rsquo;re looking at. And we&rsquo;re the guys
who sort of missed the boat.</strong></p><footer><strong>Poul-Henning Kamp <a href="https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=30m8s">https://youtu.be/fwcl17Q0bpk?t=30m8s</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>If a guy who&rsquo;s been committing to the FreeBSD kernel for over 15 years says he doesn&rsquo;t see a
technical solution to mass digital surveillance, he&rsquo;s probably got a point. He doesn&rsquo;t see a
technical solution because he cited the enormous amounts of money and manpower intelligence agencies
have compared with the measly resources of open source contributors. The Director of National
Intelligence, the overseer of all US intelligence agencies, requested $53.9 billion for the
National Intelligence Program&rsquo;s budget in 2016. Even if a small portion of that funded domestic spying
programs, that&rsquo;s still a lot of money. Meanwhile, <a href="http://www.propublica.org/article/the-worlds-email-encryption-software-relies-on-one-guy-who-is-going-broke" title="The World's Email Encryption Software Relies on One Guy, Who is Going Broke">up until recently</a>, Werner Koch who wrote GnuPG,
a crucial piece of the world&rsquo;s encryption software, was struggling to raise just $25,000 a year.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been struggling to understand why we Americans are either too apathetic or resigned to fight
for our privacy rights. I think it&rsquo;s because digital privacy is hard to understand and it&rsquo;s not
in-your-face spying like finding a camera in your bedroom or a GPS tracker underneath your car.
Some people believe the costs of giving up their privacy is outweighed by the supposed effectiveness
in stopping terrorism. In most of my conversations, people believe domestic spying is wrong
but think resistance is futile. They simply say &ldquo;I have nothing to hide.&rdquo;</p>

<p>This simple statement is pernicious and damaging to not just civil society as a whole but also
for our future generations. Mass surveillance isn&rsquo;t an individual problem. It&rsquo;s a collective
problem. I don&rsquo;t have anything to hide from the spooks, but that doesn&rsquo;t mean I&rsquo;m going to give my
government a free pass for spying on its citizens. Just because I&rsquo;m doing well as an individual
doesn&rsquo;t mean I throw the group to which I belong under the bus. We don&rsquo;t live in a vacuum, and
each of our actions or inactions affect those around us.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve drawn a flow chart of my argument of why we should stop mass surveillance below.</p>

<p><a href="https://i.imgur.com/athtKWxh.jpg"><img class="center" src="https://i.imgur.com/athtKWxh.jpg" width="640" height="480"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Troll Your Roommates With a Shared Router]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2015/01/how-to-troll-your-roommates-with-a-shared-router/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2015/01/how-to-troll-your-roommates-with-a-shared-router</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This article will show you how to troll your roommates or family by sending their browsers to
this <a href="http://heyyeyaaeyaaaeyaeyaa.com">amazing website</a> where He Man sings &ldquo;What&rsquo;s Up&rdquo; by 4 Non Blondes
(flash required) whenever they try to visit facebook.com.</p>

<h3>What you&rsquo;ll need:</h3>

<ul>
<li>administrative access to a router (I used a Netgear router with firmware WNR1000v3 leased from
Time Warner)</li>
<li>router firmware that lets you configure static routes, port forwarding, etc</li>
<li>a server connected to the router
(I used <a href="http://www.davidxia.com/2013/01/setting-up-my-new-home-server/">jarvis</a> which runs Ubuntu 12.04)</li>
<li>DNS software running on that server (I used <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIND">bind</a>)</li>
</ul>


<h3>What you won&rsquo;t need:</h3>

<ul>
<li>access to your victims&#8217; devices (we will be doing something more sophisticated than simply editing
<code>/etc/hosts</code>)</li>
</ul>


<h2>How the prank will work</h2>

<p>We will intercept the DNS queries unsuspecting devices make to the router for facebook.com and
reply back with the IP address for He Man. The router will send those DNS queries to your server
instead of legitimate DNS servers and your server will reply back with the IP for He Man. Your
roommates will be confused.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Configure your router</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re connected to the router, you can find the router&rsquo;s IP address with <code>ifconfig</code>. If you&rsquo;re
on a Mac, you can also go to Network settings -> [select the connection on the left hand side for
the router] -> Advanced -> TCP/IP -> find the &ldquo;Router&rdquo; IP address.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xfa1/v/t1.0-9/10917102_10101626154130882_4752830600148447470_n.jpg?oh=687ddbc7d54a8d49bc0a13c4f0f10fa0&amp;oe=55268EFA&amp;__gda__=1429886743_ed56c2e974636c894617c7c44ed7e783">https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xfa1/v/t1.0-9/10917102_10101626154130882_4752830600148447470_n.jpg?oh=687ddbc7d54a8d49bc0a13c4f0f10fa0&amp;oe=55268EFA&amp;__gda__=1429886743_ed56c2e974636c894617c7c44ed7e783</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;662&#8221; height=&#8221;560&#8221;></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/10919009_10101626154090962_4392777984770748593_n.jpg?oh=c43148c8d01b5086d56e0643f5a7e35e&amp;oe=5532E3B4&amp;__gda__=1428807330_9fd7f561242eddec6d850e5db16e1a56">https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/10919009_10101626154090962_4392777984770748593_n.jpg?oh=c43148c8d01b5086d56e0643f5a7e35e&amp;oe=5532E3B4&amp;__gda__=1428807330_9fd7f561242eddec6d850e5db16e1a56</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;619&#8221; height=&#8221;216&#8221;></p>

<p>Go to that IP address in a browser.</p>

<p>Most routers will show you an admin page that prompts for a username and password. The default is
usually admin/admin or admin/password.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xaf1/v/t1.0-9/10410155_10101626154095952_226725594218369342_n.jpg?oh=aed19b834fb767fa8f8663a4a01ac195&amp;oe=5535E796&amp;__gda__=1429460257_bff57da2e2ebcd4c0941690accd39b5a">https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xaf1/v/t1.0-9/10410155_10101626154095952_226725594218369342_n.jpg?oh=aed19b834fb767fa8f8663a4a01ac195&amp;oe=5535E796&amp;__gda__=1429460257_bff57da2e2ebcd4c0941690accd39b5a</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;700&#8221; height=&#8221;248&#8221;></p>

<p>Find the page that lists the devices connected to the router. Note down your server&rsquo;s IP address.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/10896944_10101626154844452_1876206850052900071_n.jpg?oh=7c9f32651e691da17a5e2013998082d0&amp;oe=55299B48&amp;__gda__=1428651870_0dff0a668214d8e15623be1039b8e646">https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/10896944_10101626154844452_1876206850052900071_n.jpg?oh=7c9f32651e691da17a5e2013998082d0&amp;oe=55299B48&amp;__gda__=1428651870_0dff0a668214d8e15623be1039b8e646</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;636&#8221; height=&#8221;161&#8221;></p>

<p>Set the DNS servers for your router to <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/public-dns/">Google&rsquo;s DNS servers</a>:
8.8.8.8, 8.8.4.4.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/10407390_10101626154879382_1002124578065929748_n.jpg?oh=5dc7af5bbbd53fd16698ce4924fb9b70&amp;oe=5529AD7D&amp;__gda__=1428557163_e985a42a159b9d85f10f20ddba5c1c64">https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/10407390_10101626154879382_1002124578065929748_n.jpg?oh=5dc7af5bbbd53fd16698ce4924fb9b70&amp;oe=5529AD7D&amp;__gda__=1428557163_e985a42a159b9d85f10f20ddba5c1c64</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;666&#8221; height=&#8221;128&#8221;></p>

<p>Setup a static route for each of these Google IPs that point to your server.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xap1/v/t1.0-9/10898174_10101626154794552_232860980624736509_n.jpg?oh=42ddf8144e919d83f73bfc0ce307ee7a&amp;oe=55420596&amp;__gda__=1430042031_93da6ec48766a9e2c1788c147c430eb6">https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xap1/v/t1.0-9/10898174_10101626154794552_232860980624736509_n.jpg?oh=42ddf8144e919d83f73bfc0ce307ee7a&amp;oe=55420596&amp;__gda__=1430042031_93da6ec48766a9e2c1788c147c430eb6</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;700&#8221; height=&#8221;93&#8221;></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://scontent-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpf1/v/t1.0-9/10270311_10101626154834472_5673943759150803695_n.jpg?oh=425580867e67451a7cb805159dc5052f&amp;oe=553CC1E6">https://scontent-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpf1/v/t1.0-9/10270311_10101626154834472_5673943759150803695_n.jpg?oh=425580867e67451a7cb805159dc5052f&amp;oe=553CC1E6</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;695&#8221; height=&#8221;266&#8221;></p>

<p>Install and configure DNS software on your server. I used bind9 and followed <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-configure-bind-as-a-private-network-dns-server-on-ubuntu-14-04">this tutorial by
Digital Ocean</a>.
I skipped the secondary DNS server and reverse zone files and anything after that.</p>

<pre><code class="plain /etc/bind/named.conf.options">acl "trusted" {
    localhost;    # ns1 - can be set to localhost
    192.168.254.1;  # apartment router
};

options {
    directory "/var/cache/bind";

    recursion yes;                 # enables resursive queries
    allow-recursion { trusted; };  # allows recursive queries from "trusted" clients
    allow-transfer { none; };      # disable zone transfers by default

    // Time Warner DNS to avoid infinite loop
    forwarders {
        209.18.47.61;
        209.18.47.62;
    };

    dnssec-validation auto;

    auth-nxdomain no;    # conform to RFC1035
    listen-on-v6 { any; };
};
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="plain /etc/bind/named.conf.local">//
// Do any local configuration here
//
zone "facebook.com" {
    type master;
    file "/etc/bind/zones/db.facebook.com"; # zone file path
};

// Consider adding the 1918 zones here, if they are not used in your
// organization
include "/etc/bind/zones.rfc1918";
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="plain /etc/bind/zones/db.facebook.com">;
; BIND data file for facebook.com zone
;
$TTL  604800
@ IN  SOA jarvis.davidxia.com. jarvis.davidxia.com. (
            3   ; Serial
       604800   ; Refresh
        86400   ; Retry
      2419200   ; Expire
       604800 ) ; Negative Cache TTL
;
; name servers - NS records
    IN      NS      jarvis.davidxia.com.

; name servers - A records
jarvis.davidxia.com.          IN      A       192.168.254.8

; 192.168.254/8 - A records
facebook.com.        IN      A      205.186.179.191
www.facebook.com.    IN      A      205.186.179.191
</code></pre>

<p>Make sure you use different DNS forwarders than the ones you specified in your router, otherwise
you&rsquo;ll create an infinite loop. I used Time Warner&rsquo;s DNS servers.</p>

<p>Check your server returns He Man&rsquo;s IP when asked for facebook.com.</p>

<pre><code>dig facebook.com @localhost +short
205.186.179.191
dig heyyeyaaeyaaaeyaeyaa.com @localhost +short
205.186.179.191
</code></pre>

<p>Add iptable rules to replace the router&rsquo;s incoming DNS query packets&#8217; destination IP with your
server&rsquo;s IP to make your server from actually respond to them. Add rules for both UDP and TCP for
both IP addresses for a total of four.</p>

<pre><code>sudo iptables -t nat -A PREROUTING -p udp -d 8.8.8.8 --dport 53 -j NETMAP --to 192.168.254.8
sudo iptables -t nat -A PREROUTING -p udp -d 8.8.4.4 --dport 53 -j NETMAP --to 192.168.254.8
sudo iptables -t nat -A PREROUTING -p tcp -d 8.8.8.8 --dport 53 -j NETMAP --to 192.168.254.8
sudo iptables -t nat -A PREROUTING -p tcp -d 8.8.4.4 --dport 53 -j NETMAP --to 192.168.254.8
</code></pre>

<p>Check you get the following output.</p>

<pre><code>sudo iptables --list -t nat

Chain PREROUTING (policy ACCEPT)
target     prot opt source               destination
NETMAP     tcp  --  anywhere             google-public-dns-a.google.com  tcp dpt:domain192.168.254.8/32
NETMAP     tcp  --  anywhere             google-public-dns-b.google.com  tcp dpt:domain192.168.254.8/32
NETMAP     udp  --  anywhere             google-public-dns-b.google.com  udp dpt:domain192.168.254.8/32
NETMAP     udp  --  anywhere             google-public-dns-a.google.com  udp dpt:domain192.168.254.8/32

Chain INPUT (policy ACCEPT)
target     prot opt source               destination

Chain OUTPUT (policy ACCEPT)
target     prot opt source               destination

Chain POSTROUTING (policy ACCEPT)
target     prot opt source               destination
</code></pre>

<p>Now check your router returns He Man&rsquo;s IP when asked for facebook.com.</p>

<pre><code>dig facebook.com @192.168.254.1 +short
205.186.179.191
dig heyyeyaaeyaaaeyaeyaa.com @192.168.254.1 +short
205.186.179.191
</code></pre>

<p>Use <code>tcpdump</code> to debug if this doesn&rsquo;t work.</p>

<p>And you&rsquo;re done! Kind of&hellip; There are a few things that still don&rsquo;t work. The IP address for He Man
is probably a server that hosts multiple domains and doesn&rsquo;t know which one to go to if only given
the IP. Bind can&rsquo;t return a domain name, so I made bind return an IP address which led to a static
page with some Javascript that simply redirects to heyyeyaaeyaaaeyaeyaa.com.</p>

<pre><code class="html">&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Redirecting...&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;

  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Redirecting...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
      window.location = 'http://heyyeyaaeyaaaeyaeyaa.com/';
    &lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The major wrinkle is that Facebook uses SSL/HTTPS so modern browsers will just show a warning and
not request the page. So you can really only redirect from HTTP sites to other HTTP sites, but
hopefully this prank is still worth something. I certainly had fun with it :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Setup Your Personal Website From Scratch]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/05/how-to-setup-personal-website-from-scratch/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/05/how-to-setup-personal-website-from-scratch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You want to have your own personal website, but you don&rsquo;t know where to begin. All this Internet
stuff just seems like a black box to you. You don&rsquo;t want to bother with complicated technical
stuff. You just want your website to work. Is this that much to ask?</p>

<p><strong>No.</strong></p>

<p>This tutorial<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> will get your own website up and running from scratch in under 1.5 hours. At the
end you&rsquo;ll be able to type &ldquo;myownwebsite.com&rdquo; into your browser to see a website you own and
receive e-mail at &ldquo;<a href="&#109;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#102;&#x69;&#x72;&#115;&#116;&#x6e;&#97;&#109;&#x65;&#x40;&#x6d;&#121;&#111;&#x77;&#110;&#x77;&#x65;&#x62;&#x73;&#105;&#x74;&#x65;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;">&#102;&#x69;&#114;&#x73;&#x74;&#x6e;&#97;&#109;&#x65;&#x40;&#x6d;&#x79;&#x6f;&#x77;&#110;&#119;&#x65;&#98;&#x73;&#105;&#116;&#x65;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a>&rdquo;. You&rsquo;ll learn how the Internet works on a basic
level, what domain name servers (DNS) are, and how to link your website to Google&rsquo;s free apps.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Read my explanation of <a href="/2012/01/how-the-internets-domain-name-system-works/">how the Internet&rsquo;s Domain Name System works</a></p></li>
<li><p>Register an available URL (or multiple ones) from a domain registrar like <a href="http://www.name.com">name.com</a><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p></li>
<li><p>Create a <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a> blog.</p></li>
<li><p>Setup DNS records with this <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/docs/en/custom_domains">Tumblr</a> guide.</p></li>
<li><p>Setup free <a href="http://www.google.com/apps/intl/en/group/index.html">Google Apps</a> to use Gmail, calendar, docs, etc with your new domain.</p></li>
</ol>


<hr />
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>There are many ways to setup a basic personal website. My method balances cost, ease, and control. You can also try out [about.me][6] to create a basic landing page or [Squarespace][7] to create a more extensive site.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>I don&rsquo;t take money for blog posts and wasn&rsquo;t asked to write this by Tumblr or name.com. I recommend them because I they&rsquo;re services I&rsquo;ve personally used and like.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Spotify Top Tracks Widget]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/04/new-spotify-top-tracks-widget/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/04/new-spotify-top-tracks-widget</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out the new Spotify Top Tracks Widget I made for Spotify.</p>

<iframe src="http://charts.spotify.com/embed/charts/most_streamed/us/latest" width="300" height="400" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
