<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Business | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-11-11T17:28:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confessions of a Noob Landlord IV - How to Buy a Co-op Unit]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-15T06:57:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a story of I jumped through countless complex bureaucratic, legal, and financial hurdles of
Murphy&rsquo;s Law and emerged with less liquidity and more debt. OK. I&rsquo;m being facetious, but what
happened to me is the easiest and most straightforward way to buy a property. Seriously.
The events below transpired in New York City. The buying process may be different in other areas,
but the most of the process such as contract of sale and mortgage application is the same across
the U.S.</em></p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG">https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG</a> 640 772 By RKO radio pictures (eBay item photo front photo back) [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons. Promotional photo of Cary Grant and Myrna Loy for the film Mr. Blandings Builds His Dream House (1948) %}</p>

<ul>
<li>My mother found an affordable co-op unit for sale while browsing StreetEasy on her iPad
during Christmas vacation in 2015.</li>
<li>We noticed the listing was made by the seller himself. I emailed him that night.</li>
<li>The seller promptly called me. I scheduled a viewing of the unit which is at the top
of a six-floor walk-up.</li>
<li>My parents and I climbed the six flights of stairs and met the seller who was a nice man named
Alan. We walked around and inspected his unit.</li>
<li>We asked Alan about the apartment&rsquo;s condition, the co-op&rsquo;s financials and rules, the property
manager, etc.</li>
<li>We sat down with Alan, chatted, and negotiated. My mother pointed out neither party has a broker
which is good because brokers take a 6% commission. We felt out Alan on how many offers he&rsquo;s
received and what they are.</li>
<li>My mother verbally offered Alan 94% of the listing price. He said he&rsquo;ll see. My mom seemed
confident he&rsquo;d take it. I was impressed by her ability to knock off over $20K right off the bat.</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>My parents and I started looking for a mortgage broker and an attorney who&rsquo;s good with co-op
purchases. (They were professional and competent. Contact me if you want a referral.)</li>
<li>We decided how much money we wanted to borrow and how long. I settled on a 15-year mortgage at a
great interest rate of 2.875%. I minimized closing and discount points in order to pay less money
up front.</li>
<li>My mortgage broker Deborah started collecting relevant documents from me to start the mortgage
approval process. These include but aren&rsquo;t limited to bank statements, pay stubs (W2), federal
income tax returns (1040). I didn&rsquo;t have to use a mortgage broker and could&rsquo;ve shopped around
myself simply by applying online at various commercial banks&#8217; websites. But I&rsquo;m pretty busy,
and the broker&rsquo;s fee would be paid by the lender in my case.</li>
<li>Alan accepted our verbal offer and sent over a contract of sale. This document is a major
checkpoint. It stated what, when, and how we would exchange property and money. Once I signed it
and included a contract deposit (10% of the purchase price), it meant Alan and I were in a
legally binding agreement and that he wasn&rsquo;t considering any other offers.

<ul>
<li>If I reneged, Alan could keep my contract deposit.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not sure what legal recourse or damages I could pursue if Alan reneged. The contract
vaguely stated:

<blockquote><p>In the event of a default or misrepresentation by Seller, Purchaser shall have such remedies
as Purchaser is entitled to at law or in equity, including specific performance, because
the Unit and possession thereof cannot be duplicated.</p></blockquote></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Our respective attorneys went back and forth modifying the contract of sale with riders that
protected each of us, respectively. For example, my attorney Andrew added a clause stipulating
the wall Alan built to divide the bedroom into two bedrooms was approved by the co-op board and
I would get a written approval letter at closing. Alan&rsquo;s attorney Michael added a clause stating
I couldn&rsquo;t back out of the sale if the maintenance increased after I&rsquo;d signed the contract.</li>
<li>I signed the contract on January 25, 2016. And I expected a counter-signed copy back shortly.</li>
<li>So I waited.</li>
<li>And waited.</li>
<li>And waited&hellip;</li>
<li>It seems that the more sellers there are on the contract, the more likely it there are to be
issues. In my case, there were a total of three sellers. Two of them were individuals:
Alan and his ex-wife. The third seller was the estate of Alan&rsquo;s deceased father. This estate
had two executors: Alan and his sister.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re not confused yet, you will be.</li>
<li>Alan told me his ex-wife wasn&rsquo;t being cooperative with the sale but that a court order would
help convince her as a last resort.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, my mortgage broker Deborah was busy securing a lender for me. I also needed to have
the unit appraised which depended on the contract being fully signed.</li>
<li>On February 4, Deborah tells me the co-op has an insurance policy that&rsquo;s shared with other
buildings. She said most lenders won&rsquo;t underwrite a mortgage in a building with a pooled policy.
She said she&rsquo;ll try other lenders.</li>
<li>After an entire month (March 5 to be precise), Alan successfully compelled his ex-wife to sign
with the issuance of a court order. This allowed me to schedule the appraisal.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, I still hadn&rsquo;t secured the mortgage. Guaranteed Rate, Citi, Chase, Wells and various
portfolio lenders all refused. With each lender that turned me down because of
the co-op insurance policy, the more likely it seemed that Deborah and I would have to somehow
convince the co-op board to buy a new individual policy. The property management company would
also have to complete lots of paperwork. I&rsquo;ve never met the board, and the management company
seemed like a tangled bureaucracy. I was seriously questioning how I&rsquo;d be able to pull this off.</li>
<li><em>To be continued&hellip;</em></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Worry About Forgetting to Cancel Your Subscription - Use a Virtual Credit Card]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/dont-worry-about-forgetting-to-cancel-your-subscription-use-a-virtual-credit-card/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-21T08:55:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/dont-worry-about-forgetting-to-cancel-your-subscription-use-a-virtual-credit-card</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost all of us have signed up for a free trial we then forgot to cancel
before getting charged for the next month or have felt uneasy entering credit card information
on a sketchy website. I discovered virtual credit card numbers several months ago and now use them
for both these cases.</p>

<p>Virtual credit card numbers (VCN) are credit card numbers that aren&rsquo;t associated with a physical
card. They are usually tied to your regular credit card account, and charges to the VCN will show
up on that credit card statement.</p>

<p>VCNs have two great features on top of regular credit card numbers. <strong>You can set the expiration and
maximum limit can be charged, and you can cancel them at any time.</strong> Let&rsquo;s say I want to try
<a href="https://www.spotify.com/premium/">Spotify Premium</a>. It&rsquo;s free for a month and $10 per month afterwards. I generate a VCN, set the limit
to $1 with an expiration of one month, enter that number into Spotify&rsquo;s website, and forget about
it. Use a VCN when you&rsquo;re wary that an online merchant might steal or is unable to protect your
card info as well.</p>

<p>So how does one get a VCN? The only free and bank-sponsored credit cards I know of that offer
them are <a href="https://www.bankofamerica.com/privacy/accounts-cards/shopsafe.go">Bank of America&rsquo;s ShopSafe feature</a> and <a href="https://www.cardbenefits.citi.com/products/virtual-account-numbers.aspx">Citibank&rsquo;s Virtual Account numbers</a>.
(<a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-did-American-Express-discontinue-their-one-time-use-virtual-credit-card-numbers">Amex seems to have discontinued theirs.</a>)</p>

<p>There are cases when using a VCN might create more hassle than it&rsquo;s worth. The two I can think of
are booking a hotel room and needing to show your card when you arrive in person and returning a
purchase and trying to get a refund.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confessions of a Noob Landlord III - How to Deal With a Difficult Tenant]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iii-how-to-deal-with-a-difficult-tenant/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-10T08:06:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iii-how-to-deal-with-a-difficult-tenant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s say your parents own and rent out a couple of condominium units in the greater Boston area.
The lease is about to expire for one of the units that&rsquo;s rented out to a young Polish woman who is
a student.</p>

<p>Your mother Nancy emails the tenant, who we&rsquo;ll call Ashley to protect her real identity
and also because we all know a crazy girl who happens to have that name, several months ahead of
time to ask if she&rsquo;d
like to renew for another year given a monthly rent increase of $50. According to your mom, Ashley
implied she would sign the new lease, but it&rsquo;s been a couple of months and she hasn&rsquo;t sent a
signed copy back yet.</p>

<p>A few days ago, Ashley wrote an email complaining of multiple problems with
the apartment that she&rsquo;s never mentioned before. So what should your parents do?</p>

<p>Luckily, this is a guide on exactly how they should handle the situation. Tell their unhinged
broker Joe to deal with the crazy tenant and watch the situation spiral out of control.
All emails below are copy-pasted verbatim.</p>

<p><em>My parents have learned from this experience and no longer work with either tenant or broker.</em></p>

<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Monday, June 22, 2015<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> signiture</p>

<p>Hi nancy,<br/>
 can we fax it next week? We are on a family trip in Niagara falls until Saturday. Have a good
weekend!</p>

<p> ashley</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Monday, June 22, 2015 10:14PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: signiture</p>

<p>Hi Ashley ,<br/>
When you will be back? I don&rsquo;t have the fax. But you can scan it and send it by email on next
week or mail to us.<br/>
Thanks!<br/>
Nancy</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 1, 2015 11:17AM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: signiture</p>

<p>Oh I&rsquo;m sorry i d</p>

<p>meant we will mail it to your home!</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: signiture</p>

<p>Nancy please help</p>

<p>The mice have taken over my house. I don&rsquo;t know how this happened. There are Many holes. I mean I
painted the whole house.i cleaned it for over 60 hours when I moved in . I tried to over up with
tape. I&rsquo;m sorry to be this way but most apartment don&rsquo;t have these issues. I googled the apartment
and they are all new so for 1400 in my building clean and nice but this is my home. I don&rsquo;t want
to move..just ask for help and help</p>

<ol>
<li>so much mildew I cough daily all over walls</li>
<li>I haven&rsquo;t been at peace with mice living with me. I clean daily.</li>
<li>bug problems I find at least 4 centipedes in my shower when window are closed.</li>
<li>the pipes of the shower are collapsing and the 1920 bathtub is gathering chemicals</li>
<li>I had the bathtub inspected and it has to be replaced due to cancer components  such as iron
and magnesium</li>
</ol>


<p>Ash</p>

<!--more-->




<hr />


<p>Ashley&rsquo;s father calls your parents and leaves a voicemail with the same list of complaints
and adds that they had inspections done in the apartment. So your mom calls his bluff.
She says she&rsquo;d like to see the inspection reports, and if they&rsquo;re true, can&rsquo;t let any tenants live
there until the problems resolved.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 8:??PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Voice Mail</p>

<p>Hi Ashley,<br/>
I am going to call the condo association about your report issuers. <br/>
Sorry we have to make the decision: we can not renew the new lease for next year. You lease will
be end by Augst 31, 2015.<br/>
We need to vacant the unit to do some works.<br/>
Joe&rsquo;s email is attached. You father can email to him if he want to talk to Joe.</p>

<p>Have a nice day!<br/>
Nancy</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 8:04PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Hi Ashley,<br/>
Would you please send me the Inspection report we will report it to the building manger.<br/>
Thanks!<br/>
Nancy</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 8:11PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Hi Ashley,</p>

<p>Please send any communications regarding your rental via email to me. Please advise your dad of
the same. These are sensitive issues so I want to make sure we are all on the same page and that
none of my communications to you are misconstrued. Not trying to be standoffish.<br/>
I do not have access to my voicemail right now, I see that you had left me one. Can you please
send me an email with the content of that voicemail? Much appreciated, have a great rest of the
night.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 8:35PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sorry for any miss communication. I left you guys voicemails but I don&rsquo;t want to be evicted. I
love my house and treat it like my own. Don&rsquo;t kick me out Nancy. There was NO inspection simply I
have a pest issue meaning mice are living in my sofa, bedroom, etc. I&rsquo;m a good tenant please don&rsquo;t
make me leave. Sorry I said there was mice I&rsquo;ll handle it on my own.</p>

<p>Ashley</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 8:36PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Also disregard my father he isn&rsquo;t paying my rent so he has no part of this.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:12PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I thought he was cosigning for you. Hypothetically speaking if you want to renew your lease we
would need to run your financials.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:12PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>My father is craZy man. I&rsquo;m sorry Nancy I called your origin communist mine is as well. My father
barely speaks English and hasn&rsquo;t given me a dollar since I graduated college. I got a job down the
street so I am very hurt.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:12PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voicemail</p>

<p>It is not an eviction if Nancy is simply not renewing your lease.</p>

<hr />


<p>Ashley starts a new email thread, but your mom is delegating everything to Joe at this point.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> (no subject)</p>

<p>Nancy,</p>

<p>Please don&rsquo;t kick me out because of my father. I have the money and means. Please. One more year
Nancy. Please I beg you and I respect my home. I won&rsquo;t complain. I&rsquo;m sorry this is my home.</p>

<p>  Ashley</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:18PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>Ashley, correction: it is Nancy&rsquo;s home. Don&rsquo;t blame this on your father, your email was
inflammatory and reflected everything he left in the voicemail to Nancy.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:24PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>Okay I&rsquo;ll leave it in the Same condition when I moved in :)</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:27PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>That sounds like a thinly-veiled threat to arbitrarily roll it back. Keep in mind you still have a
security deposit in place.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:36PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s ok joe the thousands I spent to clean it up don&rsquo;t compare. thanks!</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:48PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>You are really reaching now Ashley. Thousands of dollars? Really? Really, really??</p>

<p>First of all, we need the name and contact info of the plumber that you had come by.</p>

<p>Second of all, let&rsquo;s see the receipts for the thousands of dollars you say you spent to clean the
place up.</p>

<p>None of this came up on the apartment condition statement.</p>

<p>I have advised Nancy that we need to get in there ASAP to address all of the issues you are
outlining, no matter if you stay or if you go.</p>

<p>See you soon.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:53PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>Sweetie I got enough to feed the needy. I don&rsquo;t need to show you anything. You saw the shit hole
yourself. Sorry I took such good care of it. You&rsquo;ll get your realtor fee. Nancy you&rsquo;ll find a
really respectful tenant who cleans daily. sorry my shower is collapsing. Sorry I have mice. Sorry
the mildew is dripping from the wall. I would love people to come see it :)</p>

<p>Ash</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:55PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>Wow, did you do a 180 or what?</p>

<p>You used that &ldquo;enough to feed the needy&rdquo; statement out of context.</p>

<p>Have a great rest of your night and life.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:59PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>Enjoy being a bald headed realtor for communist China. The end. I will be out August 31st. Please
don&rsquo;t contact me unless needed. Thank you.</p>

<p>Ashley</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:07PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>You are baiting me into going over the line.</p>

<p>I will contact you whenever I feel like it if it involves this apartment and getting it rented.</p>

<p>China was never really communist. Same goes for the former Soviet Union.</p>

<p>Totalitarianism and Fascism is not communism.</p>

<p>Karl Marx is rolling over in his grave right now.</p>

<p>I never let the Sy Sperling commercials (google it) in the 1990&rsquo;s ever get to me, nor will I let
you try to shame me or my appearance.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:08PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>Dude come on with that text.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:14PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>You&rsquo;re going back and forth so many times.
Give it a rest girl!</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:15PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sorry I was a bad tenant and said the apartment was collapsing. I don&rsquo;t try to negotiate a
price on an apartment.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:??PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: (no subject)</p>

<p>How do you feel hurt? You are the one throwing barbs.</p>

<p>You did not Nancy anything about any these issues now you spring them on her last minute and
simultaneously try to renegotiate the rent.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:03PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Have I been a bad tenant for making a reasonable claim?</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:16PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Your dad speaks enough English to know what is up. Don&rsquo;t make excuses for your dad, do you know
what he says and does not speak in broken English. Your dad was from my totalitarian/fastest
nation, you should know that if you went to college. Don&rsquo;t even go there. Yes he has nothing in
common with your dad other than they are Homo sapiens.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:17PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Bro did u go to college even?</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:21PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>You are really reaching now and I advise on many levels that you stop.</p>

<p>You are not being evicted, your lease is not being renewed. That&rsquo;s the end of it. I will certainly
bring any of these emails to housing court if summoned as well as the apartment condition statement.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:22PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I was just writing an apology but ooooooo Joe u make me so nervous ;)</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:24PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Stick to that story.<br/>
Stick to the facts.<br/>
Excellent.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:28PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I thought you were a kind man. Sorry I got upset at you . Wasn&rsquo;t trying to ruin ur man ego. let&rsquo;s
just stop. I know my friend sent a barbaric email cause I can&rsquo;t even find it on my phone. This is
all so messed up. I&rsquo;ll get out cause also I&rsquo;m a slob who doesn&rsquo;t pay. I can&rsquo;t stand the herion
addict I call the police on once a week underneath me. Maybe this was all for the best.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:??PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I can hear the violins now.</p>

<p>I have no &ldquo;man ego&rdquo;, I am too well-adjusted for that kind of thing. You probably don&rsquo;t understand
because you falsely assume all men are alike.</p>

<p>Where is the &ldquo;barbaric email&rdquo; that your friend sent and who is it addressed to?</p>

<p>You call the police once a week and we don&rsquo;t even know about it?????????? Nor the management
company?????????????</p>

<p>I am 100% certain that my education served me well, I went to a wicked good university too.
And was smart enough to break away from the yoke they created.</p>

<p>No one is saying that you are/were a bad tenant,</p>

<p>You are trying to simultaneously negotiate your rent down and lay a laundry list of issues on
Nancy&rsquo;s lap.</p>

<p>My team member will be taking over for me regarding you and this issue. Fortunately, I will be
dealing with the rental part of it. I copied her on this email.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 10:??PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Joe,</p>

<p>I found the email. I know who sent it. Someone trying to ruin me. There is no cancerous bacteria
in my tub!!! Magnesium?! I understand why this all got into a fight. I&rsquo;m sorry for disrespecting
both of you with my words. I truly am sorry for taking it this far.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:01PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I will be out August 31st. I apologize for being rude and immature. I&rsquo;m very hurt someone took my
phone and said cancer is in my bathtub. I&rsquo;m sorry my hormones took over my mouth. We will be in
contact for financial reasons only.</p>

<p>Ash</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:03PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Took your phone? Cancer in the bathtub?
You lost me on that one.</p>

<p>I guess it is just that I am so decrepit, old, and bald, I certainly would not be able to use
hormones as an excuse.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:19PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m done with this conversation. Thanks for the new realtor.</p>

<p>Ashley</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:25PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>New realtor? Go to sleep please.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:30PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>I was wondering who Sara was and why this was forwarded.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:32PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Cool, she had suggested that she take over and I took her up on it temporarily.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 11:32PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>You need to be more specific joe.</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 9:12PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy, Sara<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Re: Voice Mail</p>

<p>Hi Ashley,</p>

<p>My team member, Sara, volunteered to take over my spot in this little spat we are having.<br/>
I acquiesced but then changed my mind.</p>

<p>A few days later Joe followed up with this last email.</p>

<p><strong>From:</strong> Joe<br/>
<strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, July 8, 2015 6:13PM<br/>
<strong>To:</strong> Ashley<br/>
<strong>Cc:</strong> Nancy<br/>
<strong>Subject:</strong> Dog Day Afternoon</p>

<p>Hi Ash,</p>

<p>I heard that you have a dog up there from time to time. There are no pets allowed, not even
temporarily. It is safe to say that Nancy and I are on the same page and we are the antithesis of
dog people. Nothing personal but there&rsquo;s no pet policy, that includes when your dad visits.</p>

<p>Also, I would appreciate you keeping your dad chilled out or I will have to, by any and all means
necessary.</p>

<p>I will be monitoring the pet situation and if I find there is a dog (or even a pet amoeba) for
more than half of a millisecond I will have to call animal control. I&rsquo;m not sensitive to their
feelings, only human feelings.</p>

<p>No pets means no pets. There are no special rights or Bill of Rights for animals and we have an
agreement that you would not have them up there. End of story. (Nancy saw the water bowl and
food.) if you sit the dog while your dad is away then I would seriously consider a local pet
hotel, I just rented a 10,000 square-foot facility for such a use and would be happy to refer you
to them.</p>

<p>Please be very careful about the language you use when you write back the obligatory responses you
have been delivering to me. I will be sending any and all correspondence to my in-house lawyer.
Not any type of threat at all, but you are a handful.</p>

<p>See you at 7 PM tonight. Everything will be calm and lovely but I have to follow up on the claims
you made a few days ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corporate Lingo]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2014/11/corporate-lingo/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2014/11/corporate-lingo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From elementary school through college, I learned standard English writing and speaking.
But when I started working, I noticed there was something different about the language
people spoke and wrote in the corporate world and the one I was taught in school. I couldn&rsquo;t
put my finger on it, but the jargon felt impersonal, verbose, bombastic, and loved nouns
rather than verbs.</p>

<p>Here are some examples of sentences I&rsquo;ve heard people utter with a straight face at work:</p>

<ul>
<li>What&rsquo;s the ask?</li>
<li>Our win of the week was&hellip;</li>
<li>After doing an A/B test, our learnings are&hellip;</li>
<li>The deliverable is forthcoming.</li>
<li>We are waiting for sign-off.</li>
</ul>


<p>Why do we pervert perfectly good verbs into dreadful nouns? What&rsquo;s wrong with</p>

<ul>
<li>What does he want?</li>
<li>Our achievement this week was&hellip;</li>
<li>After doing an A/B test, we learned&hellip;</li>
<li>I will send the result to you soon.</li>
<li>Do you approve?</li>
</ul>


<p>To fit into a corporate setting, be verbose and bombastic.</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;We can get the deck turned around tomorrow.&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;We can give you the updated deck tomorrow.&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;The layout will be leveraged for all other workstreams.&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;Everybody will use the same f**king layout.&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;Please flag anything you might want to escalate.&rdquo; vs &ldquo;Tell us if you&rsquo;re worried about anything.&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;Let&rsquo;s talk offline.&rdquo; (People have said this to me in person. What do they even mean?
Aren&rsquo;t we already offline?)</li>
</ul>


<p>Blatantly misuse words.</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Please revert with comments.&rdquo; vs &ldquo;Please comment.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>And finally, just make up words that sound like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newspeak">Newspeak</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Let&rsquo;s future-think our mobile design.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>How about &ldquo;buy-in&rdquo; or &ldquo;ideation&rdquo; or &ldquo;react&rdquo; as a noun? People also say &ldquo;we&rdquo; when they really mean
&ldquo;you&rdquo; as in &ldquo;We should do this.&rdquo; ie &ldquo;You should do this.&rdquo; This usually occurs when speaking to
subordinates.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m reminded of George Orwell&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.mtholyoke.edu/acad/intrel/orwell46.htm">&ldquo;Politics and the English Language&rdquo;</a> essay in which he
criticized political language for being vague and meaningless. He called this kind of language a
&ldquo;contagion&rdquo; and encouraged people instead to write and speak with concreteness and clarity.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also reminded of the Java programming language which loves nouns instead of verbs. Here&rsquo;s a fun
explanation by Steve Yegge titled <a href="http://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/2006/03/execution-in-kingdom-of-nouns.html">&ldquo;Execution in the Kingdom of Nouns.&rdquo;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the Big Short Inspired Me to Make a Risky Bet in Tesla]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/04/how-the-big-short-inspired-me-to-make-a-risky-bet-in-tesla/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/04/how-the-big-short-inspired-me-to-make-a-risky-bet-in-tesla</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% blockquote_nobr Leo Tolstoy, 1897 %}
The most difficult subjects can be explained to the slow-witted man if he has not formed any
idea of them already; but the simplest thing cannot be made clear to the most intelligent man if
he is firmly persuaded that he knows already without a shadow of a doubt, what is laid before him.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>In early February of this year, my roommate Ben recommended I read <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00ANYJ3NI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00ANYJ3NI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=easiamus00-20"><em>The Big Short</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B00ANYJ3NI" alt="" /> by
Michael Lewis. This book tells the story of individuals who foresaw the impending 2008 financial
crisis and made off like gangbusters by betting against the housing market.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The 10-20 people in the world to pull this off included Steve Eisman, an &ldquo;offensive&rdquo; and
&ldquo;obnoxious&rdquo; fund manager at Frontpoint Capital who was convinced the entire mortgage lending
market was a giant Ponzi scheme. Charles Ledley and Ben Hockett started a hedge fund in their
garage with $110,000 in a Schwab account. Being contrarian and using &ldquo;event-based investing,&rdquo; they
grew their fund to $120 million by the time the market crashed. Then there was Michael Burry an
ex-neurologist with Aspergers who discovered the absurdity of the market in isolation by looking
at data and human incentives.</p>

<p>After reading Lewis&#8217; sober and hard-bitten prose, my reaction was the exact opposite as Ben&rsquo;s.
Whereas he was indignant of our modern financial system&rsquo;s unfairness and misaligned incentives, I
was excited by the prospect of getting in on a piece of the action. <em>The Big Short</em> painted a
bleak picture of the excesses of corporate greed and the horribly misguided leveraging of
middle-class America, but it also showed that silver linings exist even in catastrophic events if
you can predict them. Ben wanted to fix the system. I was more interested in figuring it out and
exploiting it for personal
gain.</p>

<p>Lewis writes that financiers are marked by an &ldquo;animal impulse to see the world as it is, rather
than as it should be.&rdquo; Perhaps I&rsquo;ll write a future post about this darker side that we all have,
but for now I&rsquo;ll summarize what Ben and I were inspired to do.</p>

<p>We researched Tesla, an electric car company, for a week and became confident in the company&rsquo;s
ability to ship more cars than the market expected. Then I bought 500 shares at $38.30. After TSLA
went down to $35.10, I bought another 600 shares. This pushed me into margin by over $8,000. I
sold these 600 shares after Tesla increased to $36.43 and came away just about break-even. A few
weeks later, TSLA announced it expected to be profitable for the first time, and the market went
wild driving the stock up 22% in a couple of hours to $46.22. I cashed out the remainder of my
shares at $46 and had a total realized gain of $4,894.79. That was a good day, but if I had kept
those other 600 shares, I would&rsquo;ve made almost 12 grand.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not deluding myself by thinking this wasn&rsquo;t mostly blind luck. I&rsquo;ve made bad bets before, but
my track record has been slightly positive. Going forward I&rsquo;ll reread the notes I took on Benjamin
Graham&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060555661/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0060555661&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=easiamus00-20"><em>The Intelligent Investor</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0060555661" alt="" /> and do more thoughtful fundamental analysis.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
