<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Journalism | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/journalism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-10-28T12:11:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foreign Domestic Workers - Read This and Try Not to Cry]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/foreign-domestic-workers-read-this-and-try-not-to-cry/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T16:44:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/foreign-domestic-workers-read-this-and-try-not-to-cry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine you had to leave your family and the only world you knew to travel to a far and unfamiliar
land. You need to do this to make enough money to give your loved ones the life you want for them.
You&rsquo;ll be gone for years if not decades.</p>

<p>Despite having a college or graduate degree, you have to do manual labor and menial tasks you find
beneath you. You&rsquo;ll face isolation and loneliness. You only interact with your spouse through
occasional phone calls since dialing home isn&rsquo;t cheap. You wonder if
he or she is still faithful. You watch your children grow up, get married, and have kids of
their own through photos and video chats.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re lucky, you return to a home that still remembers and has a place for you. If you&rsquo;re
not, you die in an alien land.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t the job description of an extraterrestrial colonization mission. This is the life of
hundreds of thousands of migrant female workers from countries like the Philippines and Indonesia.
They work as maids and nannies all across the world including New York City.</p>

<p>This is how I feel after reading <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/04/11/the-sacrifices-of-an-immigrant-caregiver">&ldquo;The Cost of Caring&rdquo;</a> in last week&rsquo;s <em>New Yorker</em>
Read the article and try not to cry.</p>

<p>My mother worked briefly as a nanny when she first immigrated to the United States.
When she flew from China in 1989 to rejoin my father who had entered the University of Kentucky&rsquo;s
Ph.D. program in molecular biology, she didn&rsquo;t speak a word of English. She left me as a
one-year-old in the care of her parents. The plan was for me to rejoin them in a year
once my parents had set up their life in America.</p>

<p>My father picked my mother up from the airport, dropped her off at the rundown apartment building
where they shared a bathroom with another couple, and rushed back to work. She said she just
stayed at home and cried that day.</p>

<p>She tried to make money by babysitting other people&rsquo;s kids, but holding another toddler in her arms
reminded her of me. She quit and worked as a waitress instead.</p>

<p>It is a tragedy that countless women like Emma in the <em>New Yorker</em> article feel compelled to choose
between being with their children or providing for them. Emma said, &ldquo;I took my love for my own
children and I put it on these girls. I treated them as if they were my daughters.&rdquo; The author
Rachel Aviv describes how &ldquo;When the youngest boy [of another worker in the article named Ivy]
couldn&rsquo;t sleep, he sometimes crept upstairs and slipped into her bed. She said, &lsquo;The oldest
keeps asking me, &#8220;Ivy, do you really love me? When I&rsquo;m married, will you take care of my
children?&rdquo;&rsquo;&#8221;</p>

<p><blockquote><p>María Ibarra, a professor of Chicana and Chicano Studies at San Diego State University, calls
[foreign domestic workers] &ldquo;emotional proletarians&rdquo;: they &ldquo;produce authentic emotion in exchange
for a wage.</p><footer><strong>Emma <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/04/11/the-sacrifices-of-an-immigrant-caregiver">http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/04/11/the-sacrifices-of-an-immigrant-caregiver</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>If I had children and the choice, I wouldn&rsquo;t want to pay a stranger to give them care and
affection. For these reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li>I don&rsquo;t want to be complicit in yet another system that exploits gender and class differences.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m too proud and DIY to outsource such important work.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m selfish and would want my kids to love their biological parents more than anyone else.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the White House Correspondents' Association Dinner Is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/11/why-the-white-house-correspondents-association-dinner-is-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/11/why-the-white-house-correspondents-association-dinner-is-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over 200,000 people attended the Colbert-Stewart <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rally_to_Restore_Sanity_and/or_Fear">Rally to restore Sanity and/or Fear</a> last
month, but many people still haven&rsquo;t seen Stephen Colbert&rsquo;s speech at the 2006 White House
Correspondents Association Dinner. In what can only be referred to as a &ldquo;performance&rdquo; before 2,500
guests including Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Peter Pace, China&rsquo;s Ambassador Zhou
Wenzhong, model and tennis player Anna Kournikova, actor George Clooney, and of course President
George W. Bush himself, Colbert delivered a
&ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Colbert_at_the_2006_White_House_Correspondents'_Association_Dinner">controversial and searing routine targeting the president and the media</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Colbert roasted President Bush and everyone else in the room for 16 minutes and concluded with a
7-minute sketch comedy video of himself equivocating as a White House press secretary hounded by
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Thomas">Helen Thomas</a>. His speech received both support and criticism. I wonder what outgoing White
House Press Corps Association President Mark Smith was thinking when he invited Colbert to deliver
the keynote speech. Was he expecting something other than Colbert&rsquo;s usual scathing satire?
According to <a href="http://nymag.com/news/politics/22322/index3.html"><em>New York</em> magazine</a>,</p>

<blockquote><p>Smith later told the Times he hadn&rsquo;t seen much of Colbert&rsquo;s work.</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->




<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="366" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qa-4E8ZDj9s" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>




<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="366" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MOYZF3It848" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>




<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="366" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iAvFM4TYQKU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>


<p>At least Joe Wilson and his ex-CIA wife <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plame_affair">Valerie Plame</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iAvFM4TYQKU">got a laugh</a> out of Colbert&rsquo;s poke
at them.</p>

<p>As if he hasn&rsquo;t sufficiently proven his brazenness and the size of his cojones, Colbert recently
testified before Congress on the issue of migrant farm workers.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/k1T75jBYeCs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>While I&rsquo;m on the subject of the annual White House Correspondents&#8217; Dinner, here&rsquo;s Obama&rsquo;s speech
during the 2010 dinner.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JP5k4n6Wnc4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Some reasons why Obama&rsquo;s speech worked on a comedic level:</p>

<ul>
<li>He made fun of himself first. The initial self-deprecation paves the way for poking fun at
others.</li>
<li>His sudden modulations tone and graceful pivoting from seriousness to humor. E.g. while talking
about his love for Michelle, he suddenly brings up the topic of his birth certificate.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cheat Wall Street: Swindle Them With Oil]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/10/how-to-cheat-wall-street-swindle-them-with-oil/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/10/how-to-cheat-wall-street-swindle-them-with-oil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Originally appeared in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Saturday_Evening_Post">Saturday Evening Post</a> on April 25, 1964.</em></p>

<p><em>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salad_Oil_Scandal">soybean scandal</a>, one of the biggest swindles in American history, broke into the news
last fall and is still producing tremors. Losses came to some $150 million [$1.1 billion in 2008
dollars which is pretty hefty]. One large brokerage house was destroyed and 20 leading banks were
stuck with millions in bad loans. The man behind the uproar is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tino_De_Angelis">Anthony DeAngelis</a>, who in his
spare time donated bicycles to boys in his neighborhood. A onetime hog processor, De Angelis
became the biggest trader in fats and oils. Today, protesting his Innocence, he faces criminal
charges that could send him to prison for 185 years. Veteran Wall Street reporter
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norman_Charles_Miller">Norman C. Miller</a> reveals the behind-the-scenes story and raises some important questions that
still confront the U.S. Agriculture Department and the businessmen who trade in commodities worth
billions.</em></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>The Congressman and the Salad Oil Swindler</h2>

<p>By Norman C. Miller</p>

<p><div class='image left <a'><img  src="href="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMaGuszI/AAAAAAAAAsg/wUoa6oxyaxI/s400/tino1.jpg">http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMaGuszI/AAAAAAAAAsg/wUoa6oxyaxI/s400/tino1.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;242&#8221; height=&#8221;402&#8221; title=&#8221;A bland-faced enigma, Tino De Angelis stands amid steamy clouds in his New Jersey refinery.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>A bland-faced enigma, Tino De Angelis stands amid steamy clouds in his New Jersey refinery.</div></div></p>

<p>For years, Wall Street wheeled and dealed with Tino De Angelis, a slick operator with tanks full
of vegetable oil over in Jersey. Then someone looked in the tanks and found the biggest, stickiest
financial swindle of our time.</p>

<p>About 6:30 one evening last November, managing partner Morton Kamerman of the New York brokerage
firm of Ira Haupt &amp; Co. was leaving the office for the day when he noticed a group of subordinates
working late – and talking excitedly – in one of the conference rooms. Kamerman dropped in to see
what was going on. It had something to do with a complicated deal in commodities, a branch of the
brokerage business Kamer man had little interest in and was not too familiar with. A Haupt
commodities man was talking on the phone to a Mr. Anthony De Angelis, whom Kamerman had never met,
even though De Angelis was the firm&rsquo;s biggest customer. At the other end of the line, De Angelis
was shouting that Haupt was putting him out of business and putting itself out of business too. A
Haupt partner was on another phone attempting to locate someone who would buy huge quantities of
soybean oil in a hurry. Still other Haupt officials were riffling worriedly through the firm&rsquo;s
books, adding up figures. Kamerman decided to stay.</p>

<p>By the next morning Kamerman had learned a great deal about the commodities business, along with a
bitter truth. His own firm was insolvent – obligated for some $18.6 million of debts incurred by
De Angelis, who now appeared to be bankrupt.</p>

<p>It was the first shock wave of one of the biggest financial swindles in American history,
involving losses of some $150 million by many pillars of the business community. The Great Soy
Bean Scandal, which struck Wall Street last fall, destroyed Haupt and forced another prominent
brokerage (J. R. Williston &amp; Beane, Inc.) into a merger. Some 20 major banks, ranging from the
Bank of America to the Bank Leumi leIsrael, were stuck with bad loans. A dozen international
trading companies were placed in the position of financing a fraud against themselves, and the
warehousing subsidiary of the prestigious American Express Co. is hopelessly insolvent with
staggering claims of more than $100 million against it.</p>

<p>All of these companies had one thing in common-they loaned money against or otherwise accepted at
face value innumerable slips of paper representing the assets of the Allied Crude Vegetable Oil
Refining Corp., controlled by Anthony De Angelis. On paper, Allied&rsquo;s assets consisted of enormous
quantities of soybean, cottonseed and other oils, which it kept in tanks at Bayonne, N.J., across
New York harbor from Manhattan. Allied, on paper, looked to be a solid credit risk in a messy but
profitable business-moving oil from the U.S. farm belt into world markets, where it is used to
pack sardines and make things such as salad dressing, margarine, plastics and paint. Inside the
gray-green storage tanks at Bayonne, however, things looked considerably different. Here,
according to charges brought by a federal grand jury, Allied employees were fattening up the
assets by turning out warehouse receipts for oil that wasn&rsquo;t there at all.</p>

<p>For more than five years Allied created fictitious commodities which could be traded on paper and
pledged as security against loans. For more than five years, unwitting financiers wheeled and
dealed with ever vaster amounts of nonexistent oil in an outsized version of the old Hong Kong
sardine dodge. During a famine in China, a Hong Kong merchant sold a sardine can fill with mud to
another merchant, who sold it at a profit to a third merchant who sold it at a profit to a fourth
When merchant No. 5 discovered the fraud and complained, No. 4 had a comeback: &ldquo;Why did you open
the can?&rdquo;)</p>

<p>In Allied&rsquo;s case, there was interest for the bankers, commissions for brokers and profits for
everyone in the blizzard of hypothecated paper, as long as no one thought to take a close look.
When the lid did come off, almost by chance, financiers holding receipts for 1.8 billon pounds of
vegetable oil found only about 100 million pounds of oil, fats, petroleum, sludge and some
still-unidentified substances in the tanks. (In fact, the total capacity of all of Allied&rsquo;s tanks
was only about one third of the amount of the imaginary oil.)</p>

<p>There is evidence that various degrees of carelessness, stupidity or greed among the victims
themselves helped bring on the debacle. No one can yet assess the full damage or the full blame,
however, since the swindle is incredibly complicated and still not wholly dismantled; further
revelations, chunks of litigation and other debris keep dropping into the ruins every week or so.</p>

<p>Standing in the middle of the ruins with an air of injured innocence is the only man who could
possibly know the full story – the incredible figure of Anthony De Angelis, &ldquo;Tino&rdquo; to his pals
around Hudson County, N.J. He faces trial next fall, along with four employees, on charges of
conspiracy and transporting forged warehouse receipts across a state line, and he could
conceivably be sentenced to prison for 185 years. The state line in question between Bayonne and
Manhattan is the one Jay Gould and Jim Fiske carried watered stock across a century ago-and as the
grand jury sees it, Tino is the all-time champion of the long line of financial con men extending
from the Erie Gang to Billie Sol Estes.</p>

<p>In some ways, Tino hardly fits the part. He is a fat little man of 48, with a bland moon face and
a somewhat squeaky voice, a hard working, quiet living, Godfearing son of Italian immigrants. He
crams his 250 pounds into rumpled, ready-made suits, wears no jewelry, and is outwardly almost
totally unpretentious. His nominal home is still the six-room apartment in his father-in-law&rsquo;s
redbrick house in the Bronx, where Tino and his wife Virginia moved in right after the wedding 25
years ago. (He has been staying in a New York hotel since a recent separation.) His avocation is
donating bicycles and sponsoring races for boys&#8217; bike clubs. &ldquo;Bicycle racing developed me
physically. I possess exceptional strength in my hands and legs,&rdquo; Tino will say, eagerly grasping
your hand in a crunching grip to prove it.</p>

<p>Under this folksy exterior, however, lie the vast self-confidence and the fierce ambition of a
Caesar. Tino set out single mindedly to make himself the biggest fats and oils operator in the
U.S. When he succeeded, he relished the power it gave him to move oil and men, and lusted for even
greater coups. It pleased him to distribute largess among his retinue of lieutenants and
hangers-on, often in the form of cash. As Tino puts it, in his oblique, dignified way: &ldquo;With fifty
of my boys, at least, I was engaged in seeing that they were settled in a solid way in New Jersey
communities.&rdquo;</p>

<p>There is something contagious about Tino&rsquo;s guileless, open-handed manner when he boasts of giving
$500 to a man he hadn&rsquo;t met for 15 years and spending &ldquo;a couple of thousand&rdquo; on florists&#8217; bills in
one month because &ldquo;people are always dying.&rdquo; It infected people far outside of his usual social
circles. A variety of big businessmen were happy to have a part in Tino&rsquo;s expansion plans, and
Tino, for his part, was tremendously proud of the connections and prestige his money gave him.
Talking about himself, he will occasionally shift into the majestic third person. &ldquo;Here we have a
man born and raised in the poor section of Nevi York, rises to the point where he runs ten,
fifteen businesses or plants around the country,&rdquo; he recalled not long ago.</p>

<p>Tino got his start in business as an apprentice butcher in a Bronx meat market. He was a
go-getter, quickly moving on to a foreman&rsquo;s job with a hog-processing firm and setting new records
for the dismemberment of swine. &ldquo;I had an exceptional ability in knowing how to process hogs,&rdquo; he
allows. &ldquo;Some of my methods, like cutting hogs while moving, cut the cost of processing hogs
enormously.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Still in his early 20′s, Tino opened his own hog-meat firm with $2.000 in savings and a $10,000
loan. He claims he made a profit of $100,000 in the first year and tripled this within three
years. By the late 1940′s, Tino had the capital to buy stock control of Adolf Gobel, Inc., a big
publicly held meat-packing firm in North Bergen, N.J., and this venture, too, seemed to be a
smashing success.</p>

<p>At this point the De Angelis career begins to depart from the Horatio Alger script. In 1952 the
Agriculture Department charged that Gohel had sold the Government poor qualits meat for the
federal school-lunch program. Less than a year later, the Securities and Exchange Commission
accused him of understating the Gobel Company&rsquo;s 1952 losses by $145,000, in a report to
stockholders. In July, 1953, Tino took Gobel into bankruptcy court.</p>

<p><div class='image right <a'><img  src="href="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMROEOBI/AAAAAAAAAsk/Q5GS6tZJx1Y/s400/tino3.jpg">http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMROEOBI/AAAAAAAAAsk/Q5GS6tZJx1Y/s400/tino3.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;210&#8221; height=&#8221;402&#8221; title=&#8221;Oil and water mixed at Bayonne, where a maze of pipes and interconnected tanks made almost anything possible at inventory time.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Oil and water mixed at Bayonne, where a maze of pipes and interconnected tanks made almost anything possible at inventory time.</div></div></p>

<p>Tino eventually paid $100,000 in damages to clear up the school-lunch business. It took him five
years to get Gobel out of bankruptcy-but in the meantime he had spotted something more promising
than hog butchering. American farmers&#8217; production of vegetable oils had begun to run ahead of
consumption in the mid&#8217;50′s. Huge surpluses of oil had begun to pile up, and the Government was
eager to develop markets abroad.</p>

<p>Tino borrowed money to set up Allied, building a three-million-dollar refinery at Bayonne and
leasing a number of storage tanks there. He would buy raw vegetable oil from the big &ldquo;crushers&rdquo;
that squeeze soybeans and cottonseed in the South and Midwest, ship it to Bayonne, refine it, and
sell it-usually to exporting companies. His two biggest customers were Continental Grain Co. of
New York and Bunge Corp., a firm headquartered in Buenos Aires. Tino&rsquo;s services and storage
facilities were so valuable to Continental and Bunge, who together sell about two billion dollars&#8217;
worth of commodities around the world each year, that they and other exporting firms helped to
finance him. While some of these companies apparently charged as much as 15 percent for credit, it
was worth it to Tino, who could borrow far more from his customers than he could from banks. He
would pledge warehouse receipts for oil as security, ostensibly use the money to buy more oil and
pledge that for still more money.</p>

<p>Tino became a big operator in the Government&rsquo;s Food for Peace program, in which the Agriculture
Department would sell surplus oil to various needy countries for their currency and pay off the
American exporter in dollars. In such deals, Tino was far more than a middleman supplying the
exporters. Leaving his modest office in Bayonne, he would make swings through foreign markets,
talking to government officials to line up sales for his exporter customers. He became a familiar
figure in such places as Karachi, Istanbul and Madrid, and foreign buyers would often visit him at
Bayonne. Only last September, Tino recalls, a Pakistani businessman dropped by to discuss a damage
claim on an oil shipment, and Tino slipped him &ldquo;a few thousand&rdquo; in an envelope to forget about it.
&ldquo;That&rsquo;s the petty-larceny way you have to do business in some parts of the world,&rdquo; Tino says.</p>

<p>In 1960 the Justice Department sued Tino for fraud in a 1958 shipment of oil to Spain via the
Isbrandtsen shipping line, whose exporting subsidiary did considerable business with Allied and
loaned Allied money. The charge claimed Tino had falsified sale dates in order to qualify for
government financing. Allied and lsbrandtsen paid $1.5 million damages to the Government to settle
the matter. Tino now declares that all this was part of a &ldquo;plot&rdquo; by the Agriculture Department to
&ldquo;get&rdquo; him. &ldquo;While I was brilliantly moving and selling all over the world, I had a very powerful
force working against me,&rdquo; he says darkly. For all this, his customers continued to get licenses
to export and continued to get their oil from Tino. If the name &ldquo;Allied&rdquo; did raise red flags in
Agriculture, Tino blurred the picture somewhat by doing business under a variety of other names,
such as Shortening Corp. and Trans World Refining. In fact, Allied was merely the apex of a
complex of a dozen companies controlled by Tino and handling various aspects of his sprawling
operations.</p>

<p>Nothing about Tino&rsquo;s reputation seemed to bother the businessmen he dealt with, so long as his
patronage was profitable. Besides his previous involvements with the law, there was a rumor on
Wall Street that he was bankrolled by the Cosa Nostra, based on his minority interest in a Chicago
shortening firm which employed known hoodlums. The rumor didn&rsquo;t hurt him in business. In fact,
says a trader for a major vegetable-oil firm, &ldquo;we figured Tino might have planted the rumor
himself. If he were backed by that kind of money, we would have known he was good for all he owed
us.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In any case, Tino&rsquo;s business and his debts expanded apace. The sales of his companies mounted to
some $250 million a year, and at one point he was supplying 75 percent of U.S. exports of
cottonseed and soybean oil. Customers found that Allied could usually quote prices below its
competitors, which seemed to reflect a highly efficient operation.</p>

<p>But something more than efficiency was involved, according to the charges now filed against Tino.
For a significant fact apparently struck him almost at the moment he got into the oil business in
a big way in 1958. He realized that he always had more oil stored than he needed to satisfy
customers&#8217; immediate demands, and it was inconceivable that all customers with calls on oil would
ask for delivery at the same time. As long as he could meet daily withdrawals, he might have
almost any amount of oil in storage, for all the world knew.</p>

<p>At this point it is advisable to take a closer look at the epicenter of the De Angelis operations
in Bayonne-a bleak and grimy region of docks, rail sidings, bleach cries, warehouses and tank
&ldquo;farms&rdquo; within sight of Wall Street. Allied leased a group of some 100 tanks at a big Bayonne tank
farm, with a capacity of some 500 million pounds of vegetable oil. To meet legal requirements of
the business, it then subleased the tanks to a storage company, for a token fee of one dollar a
year, and the storage firm assumed responsibility for the tanks&#8217; contents. The storage firm took
regular inventory and issued the warehouse receipts, affirming the existence of Allied&rsquo;s stored
commodities, and acted as a kind of &ldquo;third party&rdquo; between Allied and its creditors. The company
Tino selected for this chore, Arerican Express Warehousing, Ltd., had a name calculated to still
any doubts creditors might have had. Its warehouse receipts looked every bit as unimpeachable as
the traveler‚Äôs checks issued by its parent firm, American Express.</p>

<p><div class='image left <a'><img  src="href="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjYajIRPtI/AAAAAAAAAs4/F5nOV1KYdc8/s800/tino7.jpg">http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjYajIRPtI/AAAAAAAAAs4/F5nOV1KYdc8/s800/tino7.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;252&#8221; height=&#8221;333&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;Out on bail at his hotel, Tino boasts that &#34;My friends will give me their business as soon as I rehabilitate myself.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino boasting while out on bail&rdquo;&#8221; alt=&#8221;&ldquo;Out on bail at his hotel, Tino boasts that &#34;My friends will give me their business as soon as I rehabilitate myself.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino boasting while out on bail&rdquo;&#8221;><div class='caption'>&ldquo;Out on bail at his hotel, Tino boasts that &#34;My friends will give me their business as soon as I rehabilitate myself.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino boasting while out on bail&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>Allied paid Amex Warehousing up to $20,000 a week, and by all indications got more than its
money&rsquo;s worth in the form of an extraordinarily tolerant attitude by the company supposedly
monitoring its inventories. On Tino&rsquo;s recommendation, Amex hired several Allied employees as
custodians, including Joseph Lomuscio, a good friend of Tino&rsquo;s, and John Bongardino,
brother-in-law of Tino&rsquo;s secretary. The storage firm often left the inventory job to Allied,
merely sending a custodian along to jot down the figures.</p>

<p>Taking inventory at Bayonne, as it turned out, was something like counting bubbles in a glass of
beer. Allied&rsquo;s tanks were interconnected by a maze of underground and overhead pipes, and were
connected to other tanks that didn&rsquo;t belong to Allied at all. Soybean oil in three or four tanks
could be concentrated in one tank or spread all over the farm, as circumstances required.</p>

<p>Allied plant manager Frank Vivenzio has testified that Allied men were instructed to &ldquo;grab as much
oil as we could get&rdquo; by opening valves and manipulating tape measures to pad the inventory figures
(the instructions, he said, came from Leopold Bracconeri, Tino&rsquo;s brother-inlaw and Alhed general
manager at Bayonne). Since the contents of a tank were computed by measuring the distance from the
top of the tank to the top of the oil, large gains could be chalked up by pumping water under a
thin layer of oil. On other occasions, said Vivenzio, an Allied man taking inventory would stop
the tape measure ten or twenty feet above the surface of the oil and shout out the false figure to
the custodian.</p>

<p>Federal authorities charge that the first warehouse receipt for nonexistent oil moved into Wall
Street&rsquo;s money markets in October 1958 as collateral for an Allied loan. By 1960, with business
booming, Tino felt the need for more storage space, or at least the appearance of more storage
space. He persuaded another storage firm called Harbor Tank Storage to operate tanks at Bayonne
for Allied and to appoint his friend Lomuscio as custodian. What happened next shouldn&rsquo;t happen to
a storage company. According to a suit brought recently by Harbor Tank&rsquo;s bankruptcy trustee
against Tino, Lomuscio began signing warehouse receipts for oils that Harbor Tank didn&rsquo;t have.
In&#8217;a series of transactions, Allied &ldquo;leased&rdquo; 41 tanks to Harbor Tank – only 10 of which it had a
right to lease. The rest belonged to petroleum companies operating at Bayonne, or were dismantled
or didn&rsquo;t exist. When Allied collapsed, there were $46.5 million in Harbor Tank receipts
outstanding and only about one million dollars&#8217; worth of commodities.</p>

<p>It was a good deal for Joe Lomuscio, who was paid $160,000 by Allied and Harbor Tank over a
three-year period. Joe bought himself a $38,000 ranch house with a swimming pool, a white Lincoln
Continental and even organized his own personal corporation, called Bulk Weighers and Samplers,
Inc., the assets of which included a show horse named King Tudor. It was, in fact, a good deal for
all the &ldquo;young boys&rdquo; Tino credits with being key men in his business. Salaries averaged $20,000,
Cadillacs were the preferred cars, and there were other benefits. Explaining a personal check for
$8,800 made out to Thomas Clarkin, who helped keep Allied&rsquo;s inventory records and worked for Amex
Warehousing, Tino says matter-of-factly, &ldquo;He told me he needed a house for his wife and kiddies so
I said, &#8220;Tommy I&rsquo;ll give you the money for your house.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tino&rsquo;s own taxable income amounted to $100,000 annually, although it is alleged that he withdrew
three million dollars from Allied&rsquo;s &ldquo;petty cash fund&rdquo; over the years to meet &ldquo;expenses.&rdquo; Even
these sums were small, of course, compared with the torrent of borrowed funds now pouring through
Allied, generated by the growing torrent of warehouse receipts. According to Tino&rsquo;s secretary,
Josephine Salto, it got to the point where Tino would carry her typewriter into a private office,
hand her a blank Amex Warehousing receipt and dictate a figure to be typed in – a figure
apparently unrelated to anything except Allied&rsquo;s need for cash.</p>

<p>Despite all this, Allied&rsquo;s business began to run into trouble. Tino claims it began with the 1960
Justice Department suit over his disputed shipments to Spain, which he says eventually cost him
orders for 150,000 tons of soybean oil he had lined up in Madrid. Later, he claims, Agriculture
began pressuring exporters to stop giving Allied contracts. Whatever the case, while he had once
borrowed heavily to build up volume in the oil business, it appears he was now borrowing even more
heavily just to pay off debts already incurred.</p>

<p>While the financial details are still lost in the chaos of Allied&rsquo;s books, investigators have
determined that by mid-1963 the company desperately needed cash and was in fact on the brink of
disaster, with liabilities outweighing assets by $34 million. In June, Tino dispatched an aide,
Gerald Gittleman, to look for loans in Switzerland. Gittleman located a wealthy Egyptian in Geneva
named Aboud Pasha, and made a pitch for a loan of &ldquo;one milhon to two million dollars.&rdquo; Aboud Pasha
was not impressed by Allied&rsquo;s warehouse receipts, and turned the deal down.</p>

<p><div class='image right <a'><img  src="href="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjZLrO1jUI/AAAAAAAAAs8/2P5iBbaOXjQ/s800/tino8.jpg">http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjZLrO1jUI/AAAAAAAAAs8/2P5iBbaOXjQ/s800/tino8.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;353&#8221; height=&#8221;317&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;A big man for bicycles, Tino poses with state championship team at Flushing Meadow, N.Y. He was judge and sponsor at the races.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino donated bikes&rdquo;&#8221; ><div class='caption'>&ldquo;A big man for bicycles, Tino poses with state championship team at Flushing Meadow, N.Y. He was judge and sponsor at the races.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino donated bikes&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>Tino had decided to try to recoup with a still wilder pyramiding scheme, this time in commodity
&ldquo;futures.&rdquo; These are contracts to bu, or sell a given amount of commodities at a specified future
date but at the price which now prevails on the exchanges. The man who buys one future contract on
soybean oil commits himself to accept 60,000 pounds of oil on the delivery date, at today&rsquo;s
prices. He is thus betting that the price of oil will rise, and that he will be able to sell the
oil at a profit. A man who sells a futures contract commits himself to deliver oil, and makes his
profit only if the price drops in the meantime. Speculators buy and sell futures furiously on
paper and seldom lay eyes on the warehoused goods involved. But grain dealers, soap companies and
other firms also trade in futures as a part of their regular business, to hedge against price
drops-or price increases-in the commodities they deal with. Tino De Angelis was such a traderand
one of the biggest.</p>

<p>Futures trading had one advantage over the ordinary cash oil business for Tino. Exchange rules
permitted a member of the trade, such as himself, to buy contracts by putting up as little as five
percent of the market value, far less than the cash requirements imposed on outsiders speculating
in commodities. All through last year, Tino bought oil futures, putting up little cash (and often
none at all). He worked through a numher of brokers to disguise his heavy purchases, and at one
point was suspended briefly by the Chicago Board of Trade for trading with himself, through
various dummy companies. Tino had reason to avoid attracting attention. He was committing himself
to accept vast quantities of oil in the future-which was illogical trading behavior for a trader
who was already presumably loaded with oil supplies.</p>

<p>In fact, Tino was abusing his trader&rsquo;s privileges to embark on what can only be explained as a
rank speculation-a reckless gamble to monopolize the vegetable oil supplies in the hope that some
sudden upturn in the demand for oil would turn his hair-raising position into gold.</p>

<p>Despite his efforts at secrecy, his buying spree became common knowledge. Neither exchange
officials nor the Commodity Exchange Authority, the government agency which regulates commodity
trading, exhibited too much concern. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re delighted,&rdquo; executive director C. Robert Berg of the
New York Produce Exchange told a group of worried traders. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s good business.&rdquo; CEA administrator
Alex Caldwell claims he was worried about the De Angelis position but didn&rsquo;t have the authority to
interfere. (Exchange officials say Caldwell never even informally notified them of his worries.)</p>

<p>Then in September, there came news of a big failure in the Soviet Union&rsquo;s sunflower crop, and many
commodity traders believed the Russians would soon be in the market for huge quantities of
cottonseed and soybean oil to make up their loss of sunflower-seed oil. Russia already was trying
to buy American wheat-and there seemed a good chance that it would buy vegetable oil as well. Here
was Tino&rsquo;s chance – it seemed. If he could get a stranglehold on oil futures, the Communists would
have to come to him. All he needed was a broker willing to run the risk of increasing his already
enormous futures position.</p>

<p>The firm of Ira Haupt, one of his four brokers at the time, had accepted the Allied account in May
on the recommendation of a big New York bank. Haupt did have some misgivings; it limited Allied
borrowings to $2.5 million, secured by warehouse receipts and evidence of contracts to export oil.
Fred Barton, senior employee in the commodities department, maintained a clamp on Tino&rsquo;s buying
through the firm at the level o1′ 2,500 futures contracts. Then, on September 27, Barton entered
the hospital for a six-week stay: about the same time, Tino began switching Allied&rsquo;s futures
contracts from his other brokers to Haupt. The clamps, for some reason, came off. Within the next
six weeks, Tino increased his position with Haupt from 2,500 to 15,000 contracts with a paper
value of $95 million. It was fairly easy for Tino to accomplish this, since Haupt now seemed
willing to loan him all he needed to &ldquo;pay&rdquo; the five percent margins, as long as he could put up
warehouse receipts as collateral. And by this time, according to the indictment, Miss Salto&rsquo;s
typewriter was turning out receipts and export contracts with remarkable dispatch.</p>

<p>To finance Tino&rsquo;s trading, Haupt in turn used the receipts as security for hank loans and poured
this money into Allied&rsquo;s oil buying. Prices rose fast, due as much to Tino&rsquo;s heavy buying as to
the Russian rumors. Soybean oil went from 9.2 cents a pound to 10.3 cents between the first of
October and mid-November, and cottonseed oil from 13.25 cents to 13.86 cents, both sizeable
increases. By early November, Tino was obligated to accept delivery of 1.2 billion pounds of
vegetable oil, or almost as much as the United States exports in a year.</p>

<p><div class='image right <a'><img  src="href="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMXp-tKI/AAAAAAAAAso/_kHDsABtq2g/s800/tino4.jpg">http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMXp-tKI/AAAAAAAAAso/_kHDsABtq2g/s800/tino4.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;252&#8221; height=&#8221;265&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;Pondering a question, Tino shows strain. He won&rsquo;t discuss the charges against him.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino shows strain&rdquo;&#8221; ><div class='caption'>&ldquo;Pondering a question, Tino shows strain. He won&rsquo;t discuss the charges against him.&rdquo; &ldquo;Tino shows strain&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>Then, as Russia showed no sign of wanting to buy oil and some key U.S. senators opposed the wheat
deal, the market began wavering. On November 15, the Senate suspended negotiations on the wheat
deal. Panic swept the vegetable oil market, and prices fell: in two days, soybean oil dropped to
7.6 cents and cottonseed oil to 12.32 cents. As the value of his futures contracts dropped, Tino
was automatically required to put up more cash to guarantee his ability to meet his
commitments-and each onecent drop in oil prices reduced the value of Allied&rsquo;s contracts by some
$12 million.</p>

<p>Haupt called on Tino for $5.1 million. Tino failed to meet this &ldquo;margin call.&rdquo; On Nov. 18 Haupt
demanded an additional nine million dollars, and Tino again failed to produce. The exchanges were
pressing Haupt for the money, and someone in the firm, without the knowledge of managing partner
Morton Kamerman, began a frantic juggling act. A number of 24-hour &ldquo;day loans&rdquo; which brokers
routinely get from banks to stabilize stock trading were used – or misused – to pay commodity
debts. To pay these off, stock deposited with Haupt by its customers was pledged for $13.5 million
in longer-term loans, in violation of New York Stock Exchange rules. On November 19, Haupt got
more day loans and recovered its customers&#8217; stock – but it also paid out $11 million for Alhed
margin calls, which the banks never got back. Just who at Haupt was responsible for this the firm
has dechned to say.</p>

<p><div class='image left <a'><img  src="href="http://lh3.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXM4UfR0I/AAAAAAAAAss/yciOh6EZ_20/s800/tino5.jpg">http://lh3.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXM4UfR0I/AAAAAAAAAss/yciOh6EZ_20/s800/tino5.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;252&#8221; height=&#8221;413&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;From Allied&rsquo;s modest office, a stream of fraudulent paper poured into Wall Street.&rdquo; &ldquo;Allied office&rdquo;&#8221; ><div class='caption'>&ldquo;From Allied&rsquo;s modest office, a stream of fraudulent paper poured into Wall Street.&rdquo; &ldquo;Allied office&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>The juggling could not keep up with plunging oil prices. On the night that Haupt officials finally
faced their predicament, they decided to try to sell Tino&rsquo;s futures contracts to pay loans falling
due next day and recoup as much as they could. Tino was wild when they told him. &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t try to
sell oil tonight-it will be a sign of weakness,&rdquo; he screamed. He promised them a warehouse receipt
next day to cover part of his debt-failing to inform them that his lawyers were already preparing
a bankruptcy petition for Allied that would leave Haupt holding a large, empty bag.</p>

<p>While Haupt tried to sell Tino&rsquo;s contracts, it sent a messenger to pick up an Allied receipt for
$5.4 million the next day. It was a forged receipt, the U.S. attorney alleged later, but it came
too late in any case. The firm&rsquo;s partners had failed to sell any oil despite a night of telephone
calls offering it to traders, soap companies and margarine makers at a discount: by morning it was
clear that Haupt&rsquo;s net assets were below the minimum required by the New York Stock Exchange. Even
as Kamerman was reporting this to the exchange, he got the shocking news of Allied&rsquo;s bankruptcy.</p>

<p>Successive waves of panic then swept through Wall Street, in roughly this order:</p>

<ul>
<li>The banks, learning that Haupt had been misusing their loans, stopped payment on all Haupt&rsquo;s
checks. The Produce Exchange finally took some firm action, closing down trading and settling all
oil contracts at a compromise price.</li>
<li>Haupt and Williston &amp; Beane-which was in the hole for a comparatively paltry $600,000-were both
suspended from trading on the stock exchange, and were deluged with frantic phone calls from their
customers whose stock and money on deposit were now frozen. In Haupt&rsquo;s case, there was a good
chance that innocent customers would be wiped out, a development that would deal a devastating
blow to investors&#8217; confidence in Wall Street. Over the weekend, stock exchange officials drafted a
liquidation plan, and eventually made up the shortage in Haupt&rsquo;s accounts by raising the sum of
$9.5 million among other Wall Street firms.</li>
<li>A phalanx of anxious creditors descended on the Bayonne tank farm, seeking vegetable oil. Two
Haupt attorneys went over, only to be turned back at the gatehouse by guards posted by the
courtappointed bankruptcy trustee in charge of Allied affairs. Bunge Corp. announced that 161
million pounds of its soybean oil supposedly held by Amex Warehousing to secure an Allied debt,
was &ldquo;missing.&rdquo; A group of London merchant banks hired a surveying team to find 21 million pounds
of fish oil held for them by Harbor Tank Storage, but the surveyors couldn&rsquo;t even find the tanks.
The bankruptcy examiner, soon aware that he was over his depth, notified the FBI.</li>
</ul>


<p>The legal tangle created by the collapse of Tino&rsquo;s empire has been monumental. Hundreds of lawyers
and accountants have examined thousands of documents and asked thousands of questions. Tino
himself has been on the stand a dozen times in bankruptcy hearings, sometimes taking the Fifth
Amendment, sometimes acting as though the whole affair were caused by a misunderstanding. In all
that time, none of the essential questions has been answered. The mysteries of (1) where the money
went, (2) why Tino behaved the way he did and (3) how he got away with it for such a long time are
as mysterious today as they were in November. Many of the victims, moreover, act as though they
would like to keep it that way.</p>

<p><div class='image right <a'><img  src="href="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMybqDeI/AAAAAAAAAsw/rlPK37Gf7ow/s800/tino6.jpg">http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TKjXMybqDeI/AAAAAAAAAsw/rlPK37Gf7ow/s800/tino6.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;252&#8221; height=&#8221;414&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;Selling out Tino&rsquo;s bankrupt company, auctioneer A.C. Willner asks for bids on pumps, valves, office furniture and what few other assets remain.&rdquo; &ldquo;auctioning off Tino&rsquo;s assets&rdquo;&#8221; ><div class='caption'>&ldquo;Selling out Tino&rsquo;s bankrupt company, auctioneer A.C. Willner asks for bids on pumps, valves, office furniture and what few other assets remain.&rdquo; &ldquo;auctioning off Tino&rsquo;s assets&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>Take the missing money, too huge a sum for Tino to have squandered it all on operating expenses or
in the futures market. (Tino may have even made money in his futures spree, since he was putting
up hardly any cash and, according to testimony by one of his aides, was getting cash kickbacks on
commissions from brokers.) Tino finally did admit to having $500,000 in a Swiss bank account after
telling the court he was penniless, and was convicted of contempt as a result. Authorities also
learned that a woman friend of Tino visited her safedeposit box after the crack-up. But that is
all they have learned. Accountants are now looking for clues in a mountain of Allied records in a
Jersey City loft, but Allied&rsquo;s chaotic bookkeeping and Tino&rsquo;s propensity for distributing money in
cash make it look hopeless.</p>

<p>The swarm of creditors are putting most of their hopes for recovery on American Express, waiting
patiently for an offer to settle the $100 million in claims against its warehousing subsidiary.
But no one is pressing, and things are proceeding with glacial deliberation. According to
executives of export companies that passed the receipts along, the banks plan to let American
Express off the hook by accepting compromise payments over a period of several years, and avoid a
court contest that would further embarrass finahcils. &ldquo;An investigation would only increase the
scandal,&rdquo; says the head of one export company. &ldquo;What we need is a settlement so we can get back to
business as usual.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The &ldquo;business as usual&rdquo; attitude explains the curious reluctance of any of the victims to explain
how all this could have happened. Since the whole swindle depended on the tolerance of the
victims, exploiting their desire for bigger commissions and more business on any terms, any probe
that strikes too deep may upset things and even force some changes in procedure. Thus, the Chicago
Board of Trade, which waited until midDecember before it bothered to suspend Tino as a &ldquo;member in
good standing,&rdquo; appointed a committee of its own members to look into the fiasco. The New York
Produce Exchange conducted a similar investigation. Spokesmen for both exchanges have found no
need to make any significant change in the rules governing the market. They blame the whole mess
on the Government&rsquo;s failure to provide warning, but insist that there is no need for more
government involvement in futures trading.</p>

<p>They may get a chance to explain this logic before congressional committees later this year. The
Agriculture Department intends to ask Congress for power to set high margins on commodity trading
and injunction powers to stop anyone from dominating the market as Tino did.</p>

<p>Today Tino seriously seems to believe that his biggest days are still ahead of him. He strides
cockily from courtroom to courtroom, acting as if his only worry were his publicity image. He
sucks in his paunch at the sight of a TV camera and keeps close track of reporters following him
on his rounds. He still talks eagerly of his vast plans in the commodities business. &ldquo;If I had
anything to do with it,&rdquo; he tells anyone who&rsquo;ll listen, &ldquo;you wouldn&rsquo;t have a surplus of anything.
I&rsquo;d sell it. I&rsquo;d take the surplus of oil in this country and make particular products. I&rsquo;d make
ghee – that&rsquo;s spelled g-h-e-e – for the Pakistanis.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tino even has a solution for his creditors. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not beyond the realm of possibility for me to
make up these losses,&rdquo; he declares. &ldquo;If given the opportunity, I could make a million or five
million dollars a year, simple as anything.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Manipulate Statistics and Create Organizational Dysfunction]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/how-to-manipulate-statistics-and-create-organizational-dysfunction/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/how-to-manipulate-statistics-and-create-organizational-dysfunction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mark Twain once said, &ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies and statistics.&rdquo; This is
wonderfully exemplified in <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/414/right-to-remain-silent">last week&#8217;s radio program</a> from <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/">This American Life</a>. The show
described how the New York Police Department&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.nyc.gov/html/nypd/html/precincts/precinct_081.shtml">81st Precinct</a> distorted crime statistics. So
what did police officer Adrian Schoolcraft do when his supervisors told him to downgrade real
crimes into lesser ones? He began secretly recording his commanding and fellow officers on the job
– for 17 months. Ever since Schoolcraft blew the whistle on these abuses (helped by this
<a href="http://www.villagevoice.com/2010-05-04/news/the-nypd-tapes-inside-bed-stuy-s-81st-precinct/">five-part series</a> in the <em>Village Voice</em>), the NYPD&rsquo;s 81st has been hit with four
investigations and numerous class action lawsuits.</p>

<p>But this is more than just a story of unscrupulous police and careerist commanding officers. It&rsquo;s
a story of how workplace statistics and performance metrics can create pervasive organizational
dysfunction. <a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=compstat">CompStat</a> is the name of the NYPD&rsquo;s accountability process. According to the
<em><a href="http://www.policechiefmagazine.org/magazine/index.cfm?fuseaction=display&amp;article_id=998&amp;issue_id=92006#2">Police Chief Magazine</a></em>, CompStat&rsquo;s purpose is to</p>

<!--more-->


<blockquote><p>Collect, analyze, and map crime data and other essential police performance measures on a
  regular basis, and hold police managers accountable for their performance as measured by these
  data.</p></blockquote>

<p>After the NYPD adopted CompStat in 1995, crime dropped by a whopping 60%. But despite CompStat&rsquo;s
goal of holding individuals accountable, like any human system, there are loopholes. Police
departments have partially manipulated it into a huge numbers game. Adrian Schoolcraft&rsquo;s
recordings reveal how commanding officers in the 81st Precinct pressured police to downgrade
serious crimes and manufacture petty ones. Rapists became trespassers while Halloween
trick-or-treaters became suspicious &ldquo;roving bands.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Why did this happen? Police supervisors began to expect a continuous decrease in crime
year-over-year. Otherwise their personal performances wouldn&rsquo;t look so hot, especially when
they&rsquo;re explaining to their own bosses. You try explaining to your boss that despite lousy stats,
you&rsquo;re actually doing a better job than your predecessor because this time you&rsquo;re being honest.
This would work in an ideal world where people are rational and everyone&rsquo;s incentives line up. But
let&rsquo;s face it, many people will choose immediate, selfish gratification over prudent, long-term
stewardship.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know enough about CompStat to say whether it&rsquo;s more beneficial than harmful. But I do know
from personal experience and David Simon&rsquo;s <em>The Wire</em> (only the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/09/10/AR2010091002676.html?wprss=rss_opinions">best TV series ever</a>) that
metrics are only good <em>to an extent</em>. Individual accountability and organizational performance
should be based on numbers <em>to a degree</em>. Focus solely on the numbers, and you&rsquo;ll oversimplify a
complex system and blind yourself to unmeasurable factors like trust, morale, and happiness.</p>

<hr />

<p>Ira Glass hosts <em>This American Life</em> on Chicago Public Radio. <em>TAL</em> is a terrific work of
journalism, public service, and authentic human stories rolled into one hour of pure awesomeness.
Incredibly, all their shows are archived and free to anyone who has Internet access. This requires
a shit load of bandwidth, and bandwidth does not grow on trees. So please donate money to them
<a href="https://secure2.convio.net/wbez/site/Donation2?df_id=5741&amp;5741.donation=form1">here</a>. I have.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recalled Eggs and America's Food Problems]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/08/recalled-eggs-and-americas-food-problems/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/08/recalled-eggs-and-americas-food-problems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Follow-up post: &ldquo;<a href="/2010/09/13/organic-food-myths-debunked" title="organic food myths debunked">Debunking Organic Food Myths</a>.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Tom Ashbrook&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.onpointradio.org/2010/08/tainted-eggs-and-food-safety">On Point</a>&rdquo; program on <a href="http://www.npr.org/">National Public Radio</a> several nights ago discussed
the current nation-wide effort to recall half a billion eggs suspected of being tainted with
salmonella. I&rsquo;m usually skeptical of Ashbrook&rsquo;s Chicken Little routine (grab attention by making a
situation sound like the sky&rsquo;s falling) but this time I agreed. The US industrial food system is
in serious need of reform.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Take this latest recall for example. The Iowa egg company that first <a href="http://www.fda.gov/Safety/Recalls/ucm222501.htm">issued the recall</a> on
August 13, 2010 has since <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/08/19/business/19eggs.html?scp=9&amp;sq=&amp;st=nyt">expanded </a>it to 380 million eggs. Wright County Egg, the company
behind the recall is one of the biggest egg producers in the US. It&rsquo;s owned by a man named Jack
DeCoster. I&rsquo;ve heard he&rsquo;s a guy without scruples. According to the <em><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/08/19/business/19eggs.html?scp=9&amp;sq=&amp;st=nyt">Times</a></em>, &ldquo;DeCoster&hellip;has had
run-ins with regulators over poor or unsafe working conditions, environmental violations, the
harassment of workers and the hiring of illegal immigrants.&rdquo;</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s plenty of blame to go around, of course. A news analysis piece by the <em><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/08/25/business/25eggs.html?_r=1">Times</a></em>,
describes how the task of food safety regulation is split between the Department of Agriculture
and the Food and Drug Administration in such an absurd way that even government bureaucrats are
calling for reform:</p>

<blockquote><p>The responsibility for food safety remains split primarily between the Agriculture Department
and the Food and Drug Administration. But the way the responsibilities and resources are divided
up can seem so illogical that some of the bureaucrats themselves have called for change.</p>

<p>There are few places where that is more evident than in the regulation of eggs. The F.D.A.
oversees the safety of eggs still in their shells, but the Agriculture Department regulates liquid
eggs that are used in industrial food production, while also being responsible for chickens and
the grading of eggs for quality.</p></blockquote>

<p>Eggs are not the only problem, however. Just look at this list of FDA recalls over the month of
August. There&rsquo;s almost one every other day. If you have a website, you can even install this
<a href="http://www.foodsafety.gov/widgets/index.html">widget</a> that displays the most recent recall for all your web visitors&#8217; comfort. I don&rsquo;t know
if the US food system was always like this. I suspect that as a result of the increasing
market-share of a handful of corporate food producers, recalls have become bigger. Whether recalls
have decreased or food safer is a more difficult question to answer. But when chicken shit does
hit the fan, the problem is harder to track down and affects more people.</p>

<p>This brings me to the book I&rsquo;m currently reading. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143038583?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0143038583">Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma</a></em> by Michael Pollan. I
highly recommend this book to anyone who appreciates a good personal narrative, news junkies who
can recognize quality investigative reporting, and anyone who gives a damn about what they put in
their bodies. Pollan tells us how all our food is made from corn and soy; how the low cost of food
to consumers doesn&rsquo;t reflect the true cost to taxpayers, society, and our environment; and how the
unnatural and unsustainable way we feed ourselves has disconnected us from nature with inevitable
future consequences on the health of our bodies and our planet.</p>

<p>To measure the percentage of corn in his McDonald&rsquo;s meal, Pollan used a mass spectrometer to
measure the amount of carbon atoms originating from corn. Now that&rsquo;s badass.</p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/THqlf4QSclI/AAAAAAAAAfU/07ILH-iA6CE/s400/Picture-2.png">http://lh4.ggpht.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/THqlf4QSclI/AAAAAAAAAfU/07ILH-iA6CE/s400/Picture-2.png</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;482&#8221; height=&#8221;287&#8221; title=&#8221;&ldquo;That&rsquo;s a lot of corn!&rdquo; &ldquo;Corniness of McDonald&rsquo;s&rdquo;&#8221; ><div class='caption'>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s a lot of corn!&rdquo; &ldquo;Corniness of McDonald&rsquo;s&rdquo;</div></div></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s Pollan&rsquo;s critique of the inefficiencies of an industrial food system based on a monoculture
of corn. It&rsquo;s so good I cannot do it justice with a summary:</p>

<blockquote><p>So what? Why should it matter that we have become a race of corn eaters such as the world has
  never seen? Is this necessarily a bad thing? The answer all depends on where you stand.</p>

<p>If where you stand is in agribusiness, processing cheap corn into forty-five different McDonald&rsquo;s
  items is an impressive accomplishment. It represents a solution to the agricultural contradictions
  of capitalism, the challenge of increasing food industry profits faster than America can increase
  its population. Supersized portions of cheap corn-fixed carbon solves the problem of the fixed
  stomach&hellip;Judith, Isaac, and I together consumed a total of 4,150 calories at our [McDonald&rsquo;s]
  lunch&hellip;To grow and process those 4,510 food calories took at least ten times as many calories of
  fossil energy, the equivalent of 1.3 gallons of oil.</p>

<p>If where you stand is on one of the lower rungs of America&rsquo;s economic ladder, or cornified food
  chain offers real advantages&hellip;cheap calories in a variety of attractive forms. In the long run,
  however, the eater pays a high price for these cheap calories: obesity, type II diabetes, heat
  disease.</p>

<p>If where you stand is at the lower end of the <em>world&rsquo;s</em> economic ladder, however, America&rsquo;s
  corn-fed food chain looks like an unalloyed disaster&hellip;There&rsquo;s a limit to how many calories the
  world&rsquo;s arable land can produce each year, and an industrial meal of meat and processed food
  consumes – and wastes – an unconscionable amount of that energy. To eat corn directly&hellip;is to
  consume all the energy in that corn, but when you feed that corn to a steer or a chicken, 90
  percent of its energy is lost – to bones or feathers or fur&hellip;What this means is that the amount of
  energy lost in the making of something like a Chicken McNugget could feed a great many more
  children than just mine, and that behind the 4,510 calories the three of us had for lunch stand
  tens of thousands of corn calories that could have fed a great many hungry people.</p>

<p>And how does this corn-fed food chain look if where you stand is in the middle of a field of
  corn?&hellip;For the corn farmer, you might think that the cornification of our food system would have
  redounded to his benefit, but it has not. Corn&rsquo;s triumph is the direct result of its
  overproduction, and that has been a disaster for the people who grow it. Growing corn and nothing
  but corn has also exacted a toll on the farmer&rsquo;s soil, the quality of the local water and the
  overall health of his community, the biodiversity of his landscape, and the heatlh of all the
  creatures living on or downstream from it. And not <em>only</em> those creatures, for cheap corn has also
  changed, and much for the worse, the lives of several billion food animals, animals that would not
  be living on factory farms if not for the ocean of corn on which these animal cities float.</p>

<p>&hellip;</p>

<p>These, at least, were my somewhat fevered speculations, as we sped down the highway putting away
  our fast-food lunch. What is it about fast food? Not only is it served in a flash, but more often
  that not it&rsquo;s eaten that way too: We finished our meal in under ten minutes. Since we were in the
  convertible and teh sun was shining, I can&rsquo;t blame the McDonald&rsquo;s ambiance. Perhaps the reason you
  eat this food quickly is because it doesn&rsquo;t bear savoring. The more you concentrate on how it
  tastes, the less like anything it tastes. I said before that McDonald&rsquo;s serves a kind of comfort
  food, but after a few bites I&rsquo;m more inclined to think they&rsquo;re selling something more schematic
  than that  - something more like a signifier of comfort food. So you eat more and eat more
  quickly, hoping somehow to catch up to the original idea of a cheeseburger or French fry as it
  retreats over the horizon. And so it goes, bite after bite, until you feel not satisfied exactly,
  but simply regrettably full.</p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be posting more about <em>Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma</em> and how reading this book has made me rethink what
I eat. I come a family and a culture that places a high premium on food&rsquo;s healthfulness,
freshness, and authenticity. I&rsquo;ve been to rural farming villages in China that serve produce and
meats grown and hunted locally. The difference exists in the food&rsquo;s taste, look, and feel.</p>

<p>Further reading for those with way too much time on their hands:</p>

<p>Pollan cites <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307408922?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0307408922">A Consumer&rsquo;s Dictionary of Food Additives</a></em> to write how food processors, to
&ldquo;preserve freshness,&rdquo; spray chicken McNuggets with a form of lighter fluid called TBHQ, five grams
of which can kill. Also check out the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1934764000?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1934764000">Handbook of Food Additives</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
