<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Startups & Entrepreneurism | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/startups-and-entrepreneurism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-12-25T20:36:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do Venture Capitalists Do All Day?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/what-do-venture-capitalists-do-all-day/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/what-do-venture-capitalists-do-all-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just listened to a great episode of Stanford Technology Ventures Program&rsquo;s Entrepreneurship
podcast. <a href="http://ecorner.stanford.edu/authorMaterialInfo.html?mid=2787">This one</a> has Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp; Byers partner Dana Mead explaining what
venture capitalists do as an industry, as individuals in their day to day life, and how he decides
where to invest.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Mead&rsquo;s talk is very informative. Here are some of my biggest takeaways. He said <a href="http://ecorner.stanford.edu/authorMaterialInfo.html?mid=2841">VC were
originally</a> a small, boutique industry but are now an asset class. The change from 1980 to 2006
has been more than a ten-fold increase. Mead said this was driven by university endowments,
Stanford and Yale in particular, putting part of their portfolios into venture capital. Stanford&rsquo;s
Mike McCaffrey and Yale&rsquo;s Chief Investment Officer <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_F._Swensen">David Swensen</a>. He doesn&rsquo;t go into why this
was the case, and I&rsquo;m curious whether this model of investing produces better long-term returns
than other methodologies.</p>

<table>
  <tr>
    <th></th>
    <th>1980</th>
    <th>2006</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>VC firms</td>
    <td>89</td>
    <td>798</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>VC professionals</td>
    <td>1388</td>
    <td>9257</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>VC capital raised</td>
    <td>$2.1B</td>
    <td>$29.9B</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>VC capital under mgmt</td>
    <td>$3.7B</td>
    <td>$235.8B</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>avg VC capital under mgmt</td>
    <td>$29.4M</td>
    <td>$175.6M</td>
  </tr>
</table>


<p>Source: Mead&rsquo;s talk</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A9oojO6ztKk"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The other takeaway, which I hope provides insight to some of my friends who are interested in VC,
is a <a href="http://youtu.be/A9oojO6ztKk?t=11m53s">breakdown of the common paths</a> to being a VC partner.</p>

<table>
  <tr>
    <th>2-4 yrs practical experience</th>
    <th>10 yrs operating exp</th>
    <th>20+ yrs operating exp</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>M.D./PhD</td>
    <td>M.D./PhD</td>
    <td>M.D./PhD</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>PhD</td>
    <td>PhD</td>
    <td>PhD</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>MBA</td>
    <td>MBA</td>
    <td>MBA</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>MS</td>
    <td>MS</td>
    <td>MS</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td></td>
    <td>Dir/GM level</td>
    <td>CEO/CFO level</td>
  </tr>
</table>


<p>And my last takeaway was Mead&rsquo;s explanation of <a href="http://youtu.be/A9oojO6ztKk?t=14m38s">what KP VCs do on a daily basis</a>. In order of
time spent:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>10%</strong> discovering, evaluating, and investing in new ventures</li>
<li><strong>20%</strong> networking with talent, other VCs, company execs</li>
<li><strong>70%</strong> supporting portfolio companies in recruiting, raising money, strategy</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Difference Between New York and Silicon Valley Startups?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/12/a-difference-between-new-york-and-silicon-valley-startups/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/12/a-difference-between-new-york-and-silicon-valley-startups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just talked with a Silicon Valley friend who&rsquo;s written code since middle school and has lots of
startup experience. This friend recently moved to New York and told me the differences between New
York and Silicon Valley startup mentality.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The thing that struck me most was his description of how the average Silicon Valley startup
perceives itself and how that differs a lot from the average New York startup. Here&rsquo;s his lengthy
description boiled down. This is grossly generalized. I&rsquo;m sure not <em>every</em> startup in New York is
A and every West Coast startup is like B. I&rsquo;m only reporting back what I heard hoping this may
provide my East Coast peers with food for thought.</p>

<p>New York startups think they&rsquo;re hot shit. They think they&rsquo;re God&rsquo;s gift to Earth. This might be
because NY tech startup culture is still in its nascent stages and that there are relatively few
of them compared to Silicon Valley. I&rsquo;m not familiar with the West coast startup scene, but I see
the tendency of some New York startup founders and employees treating startup work as more of a
lifestyle than a business endeavor. I know from personal experience that this is a tempting
pitfall. Who doesn&rsquo;t want to go to exclusive, niche parties and treat working at a startup as a
glamorous job.</p>

<p>Good candidates interviewing for West Coast startups do their due diligence and interview their
prospective employers as much as they are interviewed themselves. Some New York startups are put
off by candidates asking tough questions or suggesting business/tech improvements. They think &ldquo;who
are you to tell me how to run my business?&rdquo; or even worse, &ldquo;you should feel glad to work at our
hot startup.&rdquo; In Silicon Valley there are so many seemingly legit startups that candidates learn
to cut through the bullshit and swagger and ask the hard questions that will show where&rsquo;s the best
place they can work. To me, a candidate that interviews me as much as I interview them and one
that asks hard questions that make me confront the reality of my business instead of just being a
yes-man is a candidate I&rsquo;ll respect and want on my team.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad I learned of this contrast between West Coast and New York startups. And I wanted to
share it for what it&rsquo;s worth. It&rsquo;s antithetical for a startup to think of itself as hot shit.
Sure, it&rsquo;s important to be proud of what one&rsquo;s accomplished, but becoming arrogant and complacent
is something else. Startups are underdogs. We need to be scrappy and err on the side of
overestimating our competitors. To do the opposite and end up being wrong could mean the death of
our startup.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned From Chris Dixon's Skillshare Class]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/what-i-learned-from-chris-dixons-skillshare-class/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/what-i-learned-from-chris-dixons-skillshare-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I attended <a href="http://www.skillshare.com/profile/Chris-Dixon/4187381">Chris Dixon&rsquo;s</a> Skillshare class &ldquo;<a href="http://www.skillshare.com/Planting-the-Seed-How-to-Raise-Your-First-Round/1124114253">How to Raise Your First Round</a>&rdquo; earlier this
week. It was my first time meeting the entrepreneur and investor. I learned a lot from his class.
Here&rsquo;s a summary.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>Whether to Raise Money</strong></p>

<p>Avoid taking money if you can. Some businesses are not suitable for VC funding. This includes mom
and pop stores and companies that can&rsquo;t scale up to have revenue in at least the hundreds of
millions.</p>

<p>I asked whether our current culture of celebrating fundraising as a mark of success is a recent
trend or had existed before. A former journalist sitting in front of me quipped that
congratulating someone on raising money is like saying &ldquo;Congrats on your student loan.&rdquo; Dixon
liked this analogy.</p>

<p><strong>How Much to Raise</strong></p>

<p>Raise enough money to reach the company&rsquo;s next milestone. Then add fifty percent for a margin of
error. The type of milestone depends on the type of startup. Potential milestones for technology
security, B2B software, and consumer Internet companies are building the technology itself,
closing five customers, and hitting 100,000 users, respectively. Running out of money puts
companies in an awkward position of having to raise a bridge round. Raising too much dilutes the
team&rsquo;s equity and inflates investors&#8217; expectations.</p>

<p>Dixon thought it was &ldquo;unfortunate&rdquo; that the amount raised is often heavily influenced by the
external early stage investing market.</p>

<p><strong>The Right Way to Pitch an Early Stage Company</strong></p>

<p>For the first round, pitch the upside of your business not the average scenario. Pitch with
showmanship and bravado. Frame the product in a compelling narrative that answers questions like
&ldquo;why now?&rdquo; Appeal to investors&#8217; emotions as much as their rationality if your company is at an
early stage.</p>

<p>The pitch deck should have about eight slides. Show how the team has extensive knowledge and
experience in the industries related to its product.</p>

<p>When I asked him how the early state investing climate is correlated with the macroeconomy, Dixon
said he thought it was weird how right now the two seem to have &ldquo;decoupled.&rdquo; He added that he
didn&rsquo;t know how much longer it would last. &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t keep selling iPads to people who don&rsquo;t have
jobs.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Personal Career Development</strong></p>

<p>Some people in the packed room asked about personal career decisions. One woman wondered if her
friends&#8217; advice to break into the startup world by first working in larger corporations was right.
Dixon answered that the most direct path to working in a startup or becoming an entrepreneur is to
just go for it without taking detours through tangentially related fields.</p>

<p><strong>Do not:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Bring bankers or lawyers to the VC meeting.</li>
<li>Mention your law firm in your deck</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>VC Translations</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Come back in a month&rdquo; = not interested</li>
<li>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s a small idea&rdquo; = not interested</li>
<li>Investors often ask &ldquo;who else is investing?&rdquo; because the opinions of other investors counts a lot.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>How to Save Money on Legal Services</strong></p>

<p>Use boilerplate legal documents to save money on legal fees. Law firms often discount their fees
for young companies in the hopes of return business and market rates in the future. Stipulate a
cap on legal fees because lawyers will always max it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wild, Wild West of Startups]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/the-wild-wild-west-of-startups/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/the-wild-wild-west-of-startups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The tech startup industry is more of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfect_competition">perfect competition</a> than industries like airplane
manufacturing or steel-making. It&rsquo;s the wild, wild west of our age. Low barriers to entry. Lots of
competitors. Lots of hype and perceived glory.</p>

<p>If someone tells you they&rsquo;re quitting his/her job to found a startup, and you don&rsquo;t really
understand what that means, pretend you&rsquo;re in the 1800s and that person has just told you they&rsquo;re
going West because gold was just discovered in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Klondike_Gold_Rush">Klondike</a>.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It&rsquo;s one of today&rsquo;s frontier industries. With the disappearance of America&rsquo;s geographic frontier,
enterprising people venture into other types of new territory to stake their claims. It&rsquo;s a long,
hard road. I&rsquo;ve heard war stories of people sleeping on their friends floor, sleeping in the
office, living on shoestring budgets in pursuit of a dream. Despite setbacks, we think that we&rsquo;ll
strike gold or our pan will reveal an ingot the next time. Success is just around the corner.
We&rsquo;re hopeful, we&rsquo;re delusional.</p>

<p>This sort of opportunity attracts all types of people. There are snake oil salesmen, wannabes, and
have-beens. But there are also real pioneers and frontiersmen.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
