<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tv & Movies | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/tv-and-movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-11-11T17:28:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts About if You Are the One 1 & 2]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/some-thoughts-about-if-you-are-the-one-1-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/some-thoughts-about-if-you-are-the-one-1-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just watched the Chinese movie <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001QW5704/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373&amp;creativeASIN=B001QW5704"><em>If You Are the One</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001QW5704&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373" alt="" /> and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/7798978127/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373&amp;creativeASIN=7798978127">its sequel</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=7798978127&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373" alt="" />. I&rsquo;m
disappointed by the first and confused by the second. The two films tell the story of a nearly
50-year-old bachelor looking to get married and a single woman 20 years his younger whose heart is
hung up on another married man. These two characters are played respectively by Beijing&rsquo;s Ge Yo
and Taiwan&rsquo;s Shu Qi<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, two well-known celebrities.</p>

<p>Shu Qi&rsquo;s character Xiao Xiao is an attractive late-twenties flight attendant who is in love with a
married man. This guy promised her that he&rsquo;d leave his wife and marry her. But guess what? He
renegs and leaves her hanging. Heartbroken but still not over him, she continues to wait for him
to change his mind. But while she&rsquo;s waiting, why not broadcast an online personal? That&rsquo;s how she
meets Qin Fen who did the same.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Here&rsquo;s Qin Fen&rsquo;s personal both in Chinese and English because it&rsquo;s that funny. It&rsquo;s a good example
of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ge_You">Ge You</a>&rsquo;s trademark dry, quirky humor. Here&rsquo;s his marriage personal at the beginning of the
first movie.</p>

<blockquote><p>征婚启事</p>

<p>你要想找一帅哥就别来了，你要想找一钱包就别见了。硕士学历以上的免谈，女企业家免谈
 （小商小贩除外）。省得咱们互相都会失望。刘德华和阿汤哥那种才貌双全的郎君是不会来征你的婚的，
  当然我也没做诺丁山的梦。您要真是一仙女我也接不住，没期待您长得跟画报封面一样看一眼就魂飞魄散。
  外表时尚，内心保守，身心都健康的一般人就行。要是多少还有点婉约那就更靠谱了。心眼别太多，
  岁数别太小。会叠衣服，每次洗完烫平。叠的都像刚从商店里买回来的一样。说得够具体了吧？</p>

<p>自我介绍一下。我岁数已经不小了。日子小康。抽烟，不喝酒。留学生身份出去的，在国外生活过十几年，
  没正经上过学，蹉跎中练就一身生存技能，现在学无所成海外归来，实话实说，应该定性为一只没有公司、
  没有股票、没有学位的&#8221;三无伪海龟&#8221;。人品五五开，不算老实，但天生胆小，杀人不犯法我也下不去手，
  总体而言属于对人群对社会有益无害的一类。</p>

<p>有意就电取。非诚勿扰。</p>

<p>Marriage Personal</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for a handsome guy, don&rsquo;t bother. No gold-diggers either. To avoid mutual
  disappointment: no women with educational backgrounds of masters and above or entrepreneurs
  (except for small trades and peddlers). Talented and good-looking playboys like Andy Lau and Tom
  Cruise won&rsquo;t be looking to marry you. Of course, I&rsquo;m not dreaming of <em>Notting Hill</em>. If you&rsquo;re
  actually a goddess, I can&rsquo;t handle you. I&rsquo;m not expecting a cover girl who will blow me away with
  her beauty. Modern on the outside, conservative on the inside. An average person with a healthy
  body and mind is fine. If you are also demure, that&rsquo;s even better. Don&rsquo;t be too complicated or too
  young. Proficiency in folding laundry. Preferably pressed and folded like they just came off the
  store shelf. Am I being specific enough?</p>

<p>Let me introduce myself. My age is not small. Middle-class. Smoke but don&rsquo;t drink. Went abroad
  to study. Lived overseas for a dozen years. Never really studied much. Slacked and learned a few
  survival skills. I&rsquo;ve returned without accomplishment. Truthfully, I&rsquo;m what they call a &ldquo;three
  strikes&rdquo; returnee: no company, no stocks, no degree. Morally, I&rsquo;m 50-50. I&rsquo;m no angel, but I was
  born a bit cowardly. If homicide was legal, I still couldn&rsquo;t do it. Overall, I&rsquo;d classify myself
  as a constructive and harmless member of society.</p>

<p>If interested, please call. If not sincere, do not disturb.</p></blockquote>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2wWra0f4A6U?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The first film, although labeled a romantic comedy, is rather melancholy. Xiao Xiao is a real
downer. She constantly feels sorry for herself and is in general a depressing person. It&rsquo;s hard to
imagine Hollywood billing a movie that ended with the attempted suicide of its main female
character as a romantic comedy. The first half shows Qin Fen going on many blind dates and the
succession of women in one way or another incompatible women. There&rsquo;s the woman who parlays their
date into an opportunity to sell him a cemetery plot for his parents, the woman who lives in a
far-flung western province reachable only after an entire day traveling via ox-drawn cart, and the
erotophobic widow who will only agree to sex once a year. The second half&rsquo;s pacing feels off. Its
plot is inconclusive and goes nowhere. Its only redeeming aspect is the scenery of beautiful
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hokkaido">Hokkaido</a>.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, <em>If You Are the One</em> was one of the highest grossing Chinese films in the months
after its release. Its success most likely comes from its two big stars and perhaps the tastes of
Chinese audiences. This <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123446005281078231.html">Wall Street Journal article</a> describes how Chinese romantic comedies
are very different from their Hollywood counterparts. Love isn&rsquo;t always butterflies in one&rsquo;s
stomach, but often a painful struggle.</p>

<p>If you aren&rsquo;t searching for a carefree, happily-ever-after summer movie, then these two movies
aren&rsquo;t that bad. I&rsquo;m watching them to brush up on my Mandarin and to acquaint myself with some of
China&rsquo;s best natural landscapes.</p>

<p>Much of <em>If You Are the One 2</em> takes place in China&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hainan">Hainan</a> island. Qin Fen&rsquo;s vacation
getaway in a <a href="http://www.ilvping.com/routes/linetip-id-16833-cp-2.html">private tree house</a> overlooking the island is visually stunning. So stunning
that the story and characters take a backseat. But that&rsquo;s alright. I have no qualms with watching
Shu Qi walking among tropical plants and preparing to take a bath in the tub on the balcony.</p>

<p>This is even more melancholy than the first one. Qin Fen and Xiao Xiao decide to break off their
engagement and split up. Then his good friend Xiang Shan tells him he&rsquo;s got terminal malignant
melanoma.</p>

<p>The last third of the movie is all about Xiang Shan&rsquo;s farewell ceremony. Pretty much they hold a
funeral while he&rsquo;s still alive and present. Everyone pays their respects. He does this long
confessional at the end laying bare his shortcomings and mistakes. His daughter recites a poem she
wrote. One of the saddest things i&rsquo;ve heard. And then Qin Fen takes him out into the middle of teh
ocean aboard a little dignhy and the guy gets out of his wheelchair and jumps into the ocean to
die.</p>

<hr />
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Shu Qi was once a softcore porn model starring in films with names like <em>Sex &amp; Zen II</em>. Just FYI. She has overcome the stigma by moving into mainstream movies.  Oh, and she has a high ranking on the scientific and authoritative AskMen.com&rsquo;s [&ldquo;Top 99 Women&rdquo; list][12].<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Watched 24 and Heist Movies and Think SEAL Team 6 Is the Shit]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/why-i-watched-24-and-heist-movies-and-think-seal-team-6-is-the-shit/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/why-i-watched-24-and-heist-movies-and-think-seal-team-6-is-the-shit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started watching the television show 24 in March. I continued watching despite lackluster
dialogue and absurd plotlines for the same reason I enjoy heist movies and welcomed the news of
bin Laden&rsquo;s death: I love a well-executed plan.</p>

<p>If you haven&rsquo;t seen 24, don&rsquo;t bother watching past the first season, which is relatively the most
believable. The show ups the ante every season at the cost of reality until Bauer is thwarting not
one but three to four terrorist plots/corporate conspiracies/government coverups that include
presidentiaal assassination attempts; nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons of mass
desctruction; and cyber attacks. And, yes, he does this all within 24 hours. Sometimes after just
having been released from a Chinese prison where he&rsquo;s been tortured for nearly two years. All on
no coffee.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>But I suspend my disbelief because I like to see both the terrorists and the Los Angeles Counter
Terrorism Unit, but more so Jack Bauer, being so on top of their game. They execute their plans so
well it&rsquo;s rather unbelievable. I cannot imagine lumbering government bureaucracies like FEMA or
the FAA being able to do this.</p>

<p>I like watching heist movies because the plot involves a talented and determined team formulating
a plan to accomplish an extremely difficult goal and then carrying it out. Ocean&rsquo;s Eleven, The
Italian Job, and even The Cove in many ways. A typical heist movie runs like a three-act play. The
first act is the preparation where the individuals/conspirators are introduced. There&rsquo;s the nerdy,
rockstar hacker who can break into traffic light systems; the skinny Asian acrobatic contortionist
able to somersault undetected through laser alarm systems; the black guy who really knows his way
around explosives; etc. This preparation phase also includes casing the target and location,
studying the security system, and showing cool technological toys. The second act is the heist
itself, and the third is the aftermath.</p>

<p>When Osama bin Laden was announced killed by a daring U.S. covert raid into Pakistan, crowds
gathered outside the White House and in Times Square to celebrate. American flags and chants of
&ldquo;USA!&rdquo; flew, and rejoicers swung from lampposts to celebrate the death of one of the world&rsquo;s
foremost hide-and-go-seek champions. I was happy because after years of news about ineptitude,
gross negligence, or just outright corruption within government agencies like FEMA, FAA, SEC,
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bureau_of_Ocean_Energy_Management,_Regulation_and_Enforcement#Criticism_and_controversies">MMS</a>, here was an event showing the U.S. government can still successfully execute a
well-planned operation. Obama chose a commando raid over an aerial bombing strike and insisted on
sending enough Navy SEALS and choppers that they&rsquo;d be able to <a href="http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2011-05-10/news/29528067_1_bin-pakistanis-navy-seals-team">fight their way out of Pakistan</a>
if confronted by Pakistani forces. He didn&rsquo;t want a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Mogadishu_(1993)">Black Hawk Down</a>, and his tough decisions
paid off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One of the Saddest Movie Scenes I've Ever Seen]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/one-of-the-saddest-movie-scenes-ive-ever-seen/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/one-of-the-saddest-movie-scenes-ive-ever-seen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently watched the movie Chinese movie <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_Home_(1999_film)">The Road Home</a></em> directed by Zhang Yimou and
starring Zhang Ziyi. It&rsquo;s a movie about two lovers set in the countryside of 1960s China whose
courtship is interrupted by greater political events shaking the country. If you want to watch a
happy, care-free summer movie, don&rsquo;t pick <em>The Road Home</em>. It&rsquo;s quite melancholy. While watching,
I wrote down the absolute saddest scene of the film.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/48ivIU6Szok?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!--more-->


<p>The young male teacher Luo Changyu who&rsquo;s been sent by the Communists from the city to educate
village children tells Zhang Ziyi&rsquo;s character Zhao Di that he&rsquo;s leaving the village for what
rumors say is &ldquo;political questioning.&rdquo; Zhao Di said she&rsquo;s made mushroom dumplings and urges him
should have some before leaving. For some reason, he leaves before eating even though he just said
he would. She takes a bowl of freshly made dumplings and hopelessly chases after the horse-drawn
carriage that&rsquo;s taking him away. She runs and runs, with horrible form I might add. She runs
awkwardly with both hands holding the bowl of dumplings which is secured by a smaller bowl cupped
on top and a towel binding them. I bet she would&rsquo;ve run faster if she&rsquo;d just tucked that bowl in
the crook of her elbow like a football running back.</p>

<p>Up until this point, the courtship between them has been furtive glances, shy conversations, and
having the teacher over at her mother&rsquo;s house for dinner once. Neither Zhao Di nor Luo Changyu
know whether he&rsquo;ll be able to return. This might be the last time they see each other.</p>

<p>Anyways, the running scene is long. The entire time you watch her chasing after this carriage
which is must faster than her. You know she won&rsquo;t catch it, but you hope she knows some shortcut
that&rsquo;ll let her cut in front of the carriage&rsquo;s position. And then she stumbles, the bowl flies out
of her hands, shatters on the ground, and dumplings scatter everywhere. She looks at the
dumplings, then at the disappering carriage, and cries.</p>

<p>This is the saddest scene in the movie. First of all because perfectly good food has been wasted.
Second of all because, well, perfectly good food has been wasted!</p>

<p>I just watched the scene where as she&rsquo;s weaving a piece of bright red cloth, she hears
multiplication table chanting coming from the school house. She leaves her loom and runs out in
the middle of the harsh winter day to the school (which is just a single room) only to find she
was imagining it. The school room is empty. She comes back with thin yellow paper which she uses
to recover the windows which are simply wooden frames put into square holes in the walls. Glass is
expensive. The main musical theme of the movie is plays again. Zhao Di cleans and scrubs down the
entire room. Now she&rsquo;s sitting at one of the student benches staring blankly at the blackboard.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charting My Netflix Usage and Realizing How Much Life I've Wasted]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/charting-my-netflix-usage-and-realizing-how-much-life-ive-wasted/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/charting-my-netflix-usage-and-realizing-how-much-life-ive-wasted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got bored so I graphed the amount of time I&rsquo;ve spent watching Netflix.</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnA0eeA4kI/AAAAAAAAA3o/aiuX4uLg08k/s640/my%20netflix%20usage.png">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnA0eeA4kI/AAAAAAAAA3o/aiuX4uLg08k/s640/my%20netflix%20usage.png</a> 540 237 david xia&rsquo;s netflix usage %}</p>

<p>Okay. Now some Photoshop commentary.</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnEMdxg0WI/AAAAAAAAA3w/OnurK2Qda2s/s640/my%20netflix%20usage%20comments.png">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnEMdxg0WI/AAAAAAAAA3w/OnurK2Qda2s/s640/my%20netflix%20usage%20comments.png</a> 540 237 david xia&rsquo;s netflix usage with commentary %}</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Here&rsquo;s a chart of my friend.</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnA0PsA2aI/AAAAAAAAA3g/unscbIvYUz4/s640/larry%20per%20day.png">https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnA0PsA2aI/AAAAAAAAA3g/unscbIvYUz4/s640/larry%20per%20day.png</a> 540 237 my friend&rsquo;s Netflix Usage per day %}</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the same data grouped by week and plotted with a line for better readability.</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnA0cnOjiI/AAAAAAAAA3k/YwnJ8lVQ9KM/s640/larry%20per%20week.png">https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TdnA0cnOjiI/AAAAAAAAA3k/YwnJ8lVQ9KM/s640/larry%20per%20week.png</a> 540 237 my friend&rsquo;s Netflix usage per week %}</p>

<p>So at least one of us is getting better. Now some quick stats. I watched 4.7 days worth of Netflix
over a span of 88 days. So I spent 5.39% of that time in a televisual-induced vegetative state. My
friend has spent 17.9 continuous days watching Netflix over a span of 898 days, ie 2% of the total
time. So while my friend has watched more overall, I&rsquo;ve gone on a harder speed binge than he has.
But judging by the recent spike in his Netflix usage, he might claim the title if he keeps going.</p>

<p>Methodology:</p>

<p>Netflix subscribers can see their entire viewing history online. These records state the show
watched, date, and duration. I copy/pasted this into Excel and hoped that with a couple of minutes
I&rsquo;d have some sexy looking graphs. Unfortunately, Netflix seems to get the duration completely
wrong a quarter of the time. On closer inspection, Netflix shows how much of a show you&rsquo;ve watched
if you search for that show and go to it&rsquo;s page. For example, if you&rsquo;ve watched 30 minutes of an
hour-long program, the bar will state 30/60 minutes completed.</p>

<p>So I went through nearly 800 records manually checking the correctness of duration. With the hard
part done, I grouped time-watched into distinct days. SInce my friend&rsquo;s viewing history spanned
more than two years, I grouped his time into weeks.</p>

<p>This was somewhat inspired by <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2011/05/netflix-now-owns-almost-30-percent-of-north-american-fixed-internet-traffic.ars">this story</a> of Netflix video streaming accounting for 22.2%
share of North American Internet traffic. Post your graphs of your Netflix-induced comas below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Lost in Translation Told Me About My Life]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/12/what-lost-in-translation-told-me-about-my-life/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/12/what-lost-in-translation-told-me-about-my-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I was flipping through some DVDs trying to decide which movie to watch. I put
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001AQO400?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001AQO400"><em>Lost in Translation</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001AQO400" alt="" /> starring Scarlett Johansson and Bill Murray into my Macbook Pro
and hit play. The film opens with a lingering shot of Johansson&rsquo;s shapely ass. I immediately
decide to keep watching.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Johansson plays Charlotte, a recent Yale graduate who followed her husband to Tokyo for his
photography gig. Alone and unable to speak Japanese in an unfamiliar metropolis, Charlotte wanders
into a Buddhist temple, is affected by the monks&#8217; chanting, and starts listening to a CD titled <em>A
Soul&rsquo;s Search</em>. Frustrated by her husband&rsquo;s busy schedule that prevents him from spending more
time with her, she begins wondering about her life&rsquo;s goals and path. She meets Bob (Murray), a
movie star who&rsquo;s just as frustrated about having to spend a week in Tokyo shooting whiskey ads,
albeit compensated by $2 million.</p>

<p>While lying awake on Bob&rsquo;s hotel bed after watching Fellini&rsquo;s <em>La Dolce Vita</em> and musing about her
life Charlotte asks Bob, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m stuck. Does it get easier?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No,&rdquo; says Bob. Charlotte turns to look at him. &ldquo;Yes,&rdquo; he reverses. &ldquo;It gets easier&hellip;The more you
know who you are and what you want, the less you let things upset you.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I just don&rsquo;t know what I&rsquo;m supposed to be&hellip;What about marriage? Does that get easier?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s hard. And it gets a whole lot more complicated when you have kids&hellip;It&rsquo;s the most terrifying
day of your life the day the first one is born&hellip;Your life as you know it is gone, never to
return.&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve known for a while that at this stage of my life I have the most independence and the least
responsibilities, but watching <em>Lost in Translation</em> threw this fact into stark relief. I&rsquo;m
(almost) nonreliant on my parents&#8217; generous financial support; free of student loans; and
unburdened by a mortgage, spouse, or children. I&rsquo;m free to do whatever I want outside of my job as
long as it&rsquo;s legal. My parents and older coworkers told me to take advantage of my freedom and
take risks. I intend to follow through on that advice.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Bob does add, &ldquo;But they learn how to walk, and they learn how to talk. And you want to be with them. And they turn out to be the most delightful people you will ever meet in your life.&rdquo; I totally agree, but I&rsquo;ll have time to meet these wonderful people later.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
