<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Swimming | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/swimming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-10-28T12:11:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Open Water Swimming Event]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-open-water-swimming-event/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-08T22:51:51-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-open-water-swimming-event</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I visited the southern UK with my parents last March. We visited the coast where I took a photo of the
English Channel and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/davidxia2/posts/10102320113525692">posted it on Facebook</a> with the caption,
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m looking across the English Channel now wondering if I have what it takes to swim across to
France. It&rsquo;s 21 miles across at its narrowest point and the fastest swimmer made it across in a
little over seven hours and the slowest one was 27 hours. Average water temperatures in the summer
are 14-18 degrees Celsius.&rdquo;</p>

<p>My high school swim coach Jen saw it and said, &ldquo;If you are seriously considering, let me know &mdash; I
have many friends who have done this swim (yes I hang out with weirdos)!&rdquo;. Let&rsquo;s start with
something a bit more realistic I said. Jen encouraged me to participate in the annual Wayland Three
Mile Swim which she organizes. The race takes place in Lake Cochituate, a small body of water in
Wayland, Massachusetts which borders my hometown of Wellesley.</p>

<p>So I <a href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/when-routine-becomes-ritual/">trained religiously</a> for three months. A couple of days before June 19,
I took a bus from New York City back to Wellesley for the open water swim that would start at
7:30AM.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>My parents were very supportive of my endeavor and even woke up with me at 5AM to come watch.
We drove fifteen minutes to Wayland Town Beach. I met and hugged Jen and my other high school coach
Sandy both of whom I haven&rsquo;t seen in many years. We waited for a boat to setup the large
neon-colored, inflatable buoys in the lake.</p>

<p>There were twenty swimmers registered for the three mile race. I didn&rsquo;t have any expectations for
myself. I never swam continuously for such a long distance before (I was a sprinter in high school),
so my base goal was to simply finish within two hours, the maximum time allowed.</p>

<p>Summary:</p>

<ol>
<li>I did better than I thought I would. <a href="http://www.coolrunning.com/results/16/ma/Jun19_Waylan_set6.shtml">1 hour and 30 minutes.</a></li>
<li>I had my ass handed to me by 50-year-old men and teenage girls.
(Jeff Naylor, age 57, came in second place with a time of 1:05:21. Jeff, what are you on?
&#35;lifegoals)</li>
<li>I&rsquo;d definitely do it again. The water and weather were perfect. The lake tasted great.
I know because I drank half of it.</li>
</ol>


<p>Here are some photos.</p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/afzPLf7l.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/afzPLf7l.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;480&#8221; title=&#8221;I pose for a photo after finishing the swim. Everything is sore.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>I pose for a photo after finishing the swim. Everything is sore.</div></div>
<div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/prSXIsel.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/prSXIsel.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;480&#8221; title=&#8221;Moments before the race begins. Jeff Naylor is on my left and Sandy Smith on my right.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Moments before the race begins. Jeff Naylor is on my left and Sandy Smith on my right.</div></div>
<div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/Ifoh58ll.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/Ifoh58ll.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;480&#8221; title=&#8221;That&rsquo;s me and my kayak escort Spencer, Jen&rsquo;s son. I&rsquo;m lucky he volunteered. I don&rsquo;t know who I would&rsquo;ve had escort me otherwise.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>That&rsquo;s me and my kayak escort Spencer, Jen&rsquo;s son. I&rsquo;m lucky he volunteered. I don&rsquo;t know who I would&rsquo;ve had escort me otherwise.</div></div>
<div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/8w3OgzLl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/8w3OgzLl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;480&#8221; title=&#8221;Another photo of right before the start.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Another photo of right before the start.</div></div>
<div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/KOXM9t4l.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/KOXM9t4l.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;583&#8221; height=&#8221;470&#8221; title=&#8221;Three mile race results.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Three mile race results.</div></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Strange Swimming Experiences]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-strange-swimming-experiences/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-18T14:14:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-strange-swimming-experiences</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve had some strange swimming experiences.</p>

<p>In 2012 I vacationed on a tiny cay in Belize with a group of college friends.
The island was so small that its surface area was probably equal to that of a  medium-sized suburban
house. An even smaller cay lay a quarter of a mile away with nothing but white sand, coral
reefs, and pristine blue water separating them. One day I decided to swim to the smaller island
and back. I wore a long-sleeved shirt and pants to not get sunburned and waded into the water with
my snorkel mask. I carefully made my way around the sharp corals near the island. Once the water
became deep enough, I was surrounded by nothing but deep blue water.
I couldn&rsquo;t see the bottom or any distinguishable shapes in the ocean.</p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/LDg8qfd.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/LDg8qfd.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;322&#8221; title=&#8221;Photo by Todd Quackenbush is licensed under CC BY-NC-SA 3.0&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Photo by Todd Quackenbush is licensed under CC BY-NC-SA 3.0</div></div></p>

<p>I started seeing ghostly shapes swimming around me. I was scared because I
wasn&rsquo;t sure if I was seeing large fish or if my eyes were just playing tricks on me.
I had seen barricudas, rays, and sharks in the water on previous days. I kept swimming. By now I
was halfway to the other island. After about 20 minutes I reached shore.
The ocean&rsquo;s depths and creatures made me feel naked and vulnerable and at times like I
was going crazy. But I stuck it out and felt strangely triumphant afterwards.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D-Ii7pKSEkQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I was six and attending summer camp. The counselors occasionally took us to the Evelyn Kirrane Aquatics
Center in Brookline, Massachusetts. One day I stepped into the deep-end of a pool without knowing
and began to panic. I tried screaming but couldn&rsquo;t get my mouth out of the water long enough to
take a breath and exhale. I started gulping a lot of water. Luckily, it was a small pool, and I
eventually made my way to the wall. I was surprised, however, that I couldn&rsquo;t signal for help and
that no one seemed to notice my distress. Later in life I learned it&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.ribride.co.uk/blog/drowning-does-not-look-like-drowning/" title="A Drowning Person Does Not Look Like a Drowning Person">difficult for an untrained
person to notice that someone is drowning</a>. Many small children drown each year just a short
distance away from their parents.</p>

<p>I lap swim regularly at the Chelsea Recreation Center. Multiple swimmers share a single lane by
swimming counter-clockwise. One day, another swimmer was swimming towards me in the opposite direction.
According to the rules, we each stuck to our respective right-hand sides. He must&rsquo;ve been a large
person because his wake was bigger than I&rsquo;m used to. I tilted my head to the side and took a breath
just as his wake hit me. Water unexpectedly entered my mouth and nose. I was surprised by how my
brain went into auto-pilot emergency mode. I tensed up and began to flail involuntarily.
The water and lack of breath was a strong signal to my brain that overrode everything else.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
