<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-05-17T15:41:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I'm Looking for in a Volunteering Position]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/10/what-im-looking-for-in-a-volunteering-position/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-31T13:59:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/10/what-im-looking-for-in-a-volunteering-position</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>My Absolute Requirements</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Does not require a law degree</strong>

<ul>
<li>Although I have thought about getting one just so I can apply for certain volunteering gigs that require one.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Does not require me to write code</strong> for a significant portion of my volunteer time. I already do
that full time and am not looking for more. I am fine giving high level tech guidance, however.</li>
</ul>


<h2>My Preferences</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>in-person and local</li>
<li>intellectually challenging</li>
<li>accommodating of my full time work schedule and personal life</li>
<li>5-10 hours a week</li>
<li>months-long to year-long commitment</li>
<li>not just a desk job but also field work</li>
</ul>


<h2>Skills I Want to Learn or Improve Upon</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>public speaking</li>
<li>community organizing and building trust with people who have different backgrounds</li>
<li>negotiating and building consensus with and between people who don&rsquo;t necessarily see eye-to-eye</li>
<li>Learning to lobby public officials and organizations</li>
<li>learning more about the law or government or various industries</li>
<li>investigative reporting</li>
</ul>


<h2>Values of Organizations in which I&rsquo;ll Thrive</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>competence</li>
<li>hard work</li>
<li>innovation or at least open-mindedness</li>
<li>passion and compassion</li>
<li>personal responsibility</li>
</ul>


<h2>Skills I Can Contribute</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of ability</em></p>

<ul>
<li>writing code, creating web sites, general computer stuff (see my <a href="https://github.com/davidxia">github</a>)</li>
<li>writing prose such as reports, summaries, and essays (see my <a href="https://www.davidxia.com/">blog</a>)</li>
<li>analytical and quantitative (I was a math major in college. Now I work at Spotify as a software
engineer.)</li>
<li>effective at collaborating and working as part of a team</li>
<li>good at spoken communication</li>
<li>has a knack for establishing rapport and building strong relationships with all kinds of people</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<h2>Causes I Believe In</h2>

<p><em>In rough order of preference</em></p>

<ul>
<li>civil rights

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;protect individuals&#8217; freedom from infringement by governments, social organizations, and
private individuals. They ensure one&rsquo;s ability to participate in the civil and political life
of the society and state without discrimination or repression&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Environmentalism">environmentalism</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;advocate for the lawful preservation, restoration and/or improvement of the natural
environment&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;attempt to balance relations between humans and the various natural systems on which they
depend in such a way that all the components are accorded a proper degree of sustainability&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Consumer_protection">consumer protection</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;promoting laws and organizations that ensure the rights of consumers as well as fair trade,
competition and accurate information in the marketplace. The laws are designed to prevent
businesses that engage in fraud or specified unfair practices from gaining an advantage over
competitors&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nypirg.org/goodgov/">good governance</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;advocate for eliminating barriers to voting, fighting for better ethics oversight and limiting
the role of powerful interests in elections,&rdquo; etc</li>
<li>examples include making &ldquo;campaign finance information for state and local candidates&rdquo;
available on the Internet, reporting &ldquo;lobbying of state agencies and local governments&rdquo;,
deterring and justly punishing ethical misconduct, and making legislative and budgetary
processes more transparent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labor_rights">labor rights</a>

<ul>
<li>advocating for &ldquo;legal rights and claimed human rights having to do with labor relations
between workers and their employers, usually obtained under labor and employment law. In
general, these rights&#8217; debates have to do with negotiating workers&#8217; pay, benefits, and safe
working conditions&rdquo;</li>
<li>e.g. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/24/business/graduate-students-clear-hurdle-in-effort-to-form-union.html">Grad Students Win Right to Unionize in an Ivy League Case</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community_organizing">community organizing</a>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;community organizers generally assume that social change necessarily involves conflict and
social struggle in order to generate collective power for the powerless. A core goal of
community organizing is to generate durable power for an organization representing the
community, allowing it to influence key decision-makers on a range of issues over time&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community_development#Definitions">community development</a></li>
<li>Education</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Recent Family Photo]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/09/a-recent-family-photo/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-18T18:29:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/09/a-recent-family-photo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/mwtquEjl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/mwtquEjl.jpg</a> 640 640 Post-dimsum photo with my parents and maternal grandparents on their weekend visit to NYC. %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confessions of a Noob Landlord IV - How to Buy a Co-op Unit]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-15T06:57:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a story of I jumped through countless complex bureaucratic, legal, and financial hurdles of
Murphy&rsquo;s Law and emerged with less liquidity and more debt. OK. I&rsquo;m being facetious, but what
happened to me is the easiest and most straightforward way to buy a property. Seriously.
The events below transpired in New York City. The buying process may be different in other areas,
but the most of the process such as contract of sale and mortgage application is the same across
the U.S.</em></p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG">https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG</a> 640 772 By RKO radio pictures (eBay item photo front photo back) [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons. Promotional photo of Cary Grant and Myrna Loy for the film Mr. Blandings Builds His Dream House (1948) %}</p>

<ul>
<li>My mother found an affordable co-op unit for sale while browsing StreetEasy on her iPad
during Christmas vacation in 2015.</li>
<li>We noticed the listing was made by the seller himself. I emailed him that night.</li>
<li>The seller promptly called me. I scheduled a viewing of the unit which is at the top
of a six-floor walk-up.</li>
<li>My parents and I climbed the six flights of stairs and met the seller who was a nice man named
Alan. We walked around and inspected his unit.</li>
<li>We asked Alan about the apartment&rsquo;s condition, the co-op&rsquo;s financials and rules, the property
manager, etc.</li>
<li>We sat down with Alan, chatted, and negotiated. My mother pointed out neither party has a broker
which is good because brokers take a 6% commission. We felt out Alan on how many offers he&rsquo;s
received and what they are.</li>
<li>My mother verbally offered Alan 94% of the listing price. He said he&rsquo;ll see. My mom seemed
confident he&rsquo;d take it. I was impressed by her ability to knock off over $20K right off the bat.</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>My parents and I started looking for a mortgage broker and an attorney who&rsquo;s good with co-op
purchases. (They were professional and competent. Contact me if you want a referral.)</li>
<li>We decided how much money we wanted to borrow and how long. I settled on a 15-year mortgage at a
great interest rate of 2.875%. I minimized closing and discount points in order to pay less money
up front.</li>
<li>My mortgage broker Deborah started collecting relevant documents from me to start the mortgage
approval process. These include but aren&rsquo;t limited to bank statements, pay stubs (W2), federal
income tax returns (1040). I didn&rsquo;t have to use a mortgage broker and could&rsquo;ve shopped around
myself simply by applying online at various commercial banks&#8217; websites. But I&rsquo;m pretty busy,
and the broker&rsquo;s fee would be paid by the lender in my case.</li>
<li>Alan accepted our verbal offer and sent over a contract of sale. This document is a major
checkpoint. It stated what, when, and how we would exchange property and money. Once I signed it
and included a contract deposit (10% of the purchase price), it meant Alan and I were in a
legally binding agreement and that he wasn&rsquo;t considering any other offers.

<ul>
<li>If I reneged, Alan could keep my contract deposit.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not sure what legal recourse or damages I could pursue if Alan reneged. The contract
vaguely stated:

<blockquote><p>In the event of a default or misrepresentation by Seller, Purchaser shall have such remedies
as Purchaser is entitled to at law or in equity, including specific performance, because
the Unit and possession thereof cannot be duplicated.</p></blockquote></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Our respective attorneys went back and forth modifying the contract of sale with riders that
protected each of us, respectively. For example, my attorney Andrew added a clause stipulating
the wall Alan built to divide the bedroom into two bedrooms was approved by the co-op board and
I would get a written approval letter at closing. Alan&rsquo;s attorney Michael added a clause stating
I couldn&rsquo;t back out of the sale if the maintenance increased after I&rsquo;d signed the contract.</li>
<li>I signed the contract on January 25, 2016. And I expected a counter-signed copy back shortly.</li>
<li>So I waited.</li>
<li>And waited.</li>
<li>And waited&hellip;</li>
<li>It seems that the more sellers there are on the contract, the more likely it there are to be
issues. In my case, there were a total of three sellers. Two of them were individuals:
Alan and his ex-wife. The third seller was the estate of Alan&rsquo;s deceased father. This estate
had two executors: Alan and his sister.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re not confused yet, you will be.</li>
<li>Alan told me his ex-wife wasn&rsquo;t being cooperative with the sale but that a court order would
help convince her as a last resort.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, my mortgage broker Deborah was busy securing a lender for me. I also needed to have
the unit appraised which depended on the contract being fully signed.</li>
<li>On February 4, Deborah tells me the co-op has an insurance policy that&rsquo;s shared with other
buildings. She said most lenders won&rsquo;t underwrite a mortgage in a building with a pooled policy.
She said she&rsquo;ll try other lenders.</li>
<li>After an entire month (March 5 to be precise), Alan successfully compelled his ex-wife to sign
with the issuance of a court order. This allowed me to schedule the appraisal.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, I still hadn&rsquo;t secured the mortgage. Guaranteed Rate, Citi, Chase, Wells and various
portfolio lenders all refused. With each lender that turned me down because of
the co-op insurance policy, the more likely it seemed that Deborah and I would have to somehow
convince the co-op board to buy a new individual policy. The property management company would
also have to complete lots of paperwork. I&rsquo;ve never met the board, and the management company
seemed like a tangled bureaucracy. I was seriously questioning how I&rsquo;d be able to pull this off.</li>
<li><em>To be continued&hellip;</em></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skydiving With Friends - Jumping Out of Planes Is Fun]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/skydiving-with-friends-jumping-out-of-planes-is-fun/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-28T10:59:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/skydiving-with-friends-jumping-out-of-planes-is-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On April 16, seven friends and I went skydiving at Skydive the Ranch in New Jersey. We rented
a black SUV (a Hyundai that had terrible acceleration and braking) and each did a tandem dive.
It was a first for many of us including me.</p>

<p>My takeaway was that tandem diving out of a plane at 14-thousand feet is easy. The instructor takes
care of everything. I just had to sit back and enjoy the view. If anything went wrong and I died,
I wouldn&rsquo;t feel that bad about it because I wasn&rsquo;t the one who screwed it up.</p>

<p>Driving seven of your friends out of and back into New York City is nerve-wracking, on the other
hand. I was personally responsible for everyone&rsquo;s lives. Trying to return the rental car on time
while driving through Union Square in Manhattan where
there&rsquo;s a pedestrian fair going on, ambulances and cop cars, and drivers double parking wherever
they want is very stressful.</p>

<p>Hopefully Avis doesn&rsquo;t notice the small white scratch on the mirror of their mint condition car
(18 miles when I got it) that was left when I managed to squeeze through two city buses before they
crushed me.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaSiFui6vt0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing Together and Apart]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/growing-together-and-apart/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-13T10:09:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/05/growing-together-and-apart</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Thanks to Nanette for editing and agreeing to let me publish this and to my friends who gave me
feedback.</em></p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s almost 2016. Let&rsquo;s reset our relationship next year. OK?&rdquo; Nanette asked me two days before
Christmas Eve. I couldn&rsquo;t bring myself to say yes. I felt I would be lying.</p>

<p>I told Nanette we should break up. We spent the next two days crying until our eyes became red and
puffy. I had bought bus tickets for the night of Christmas Eve to travel back to my family in
Boston. It was cold and pouring that evening, but Nanette still accompanied me to the bus stop. I
got on the bus and asked her to go back home. She stood outside in the rain waiting for the driver
to pull out while looking at me through the windows. It broke my heart to see her standing on the
sidewalk, her tears mixing with the rain.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>We kept texting each other while we waited for the bus to leave. Afterwards, she wrote that she
was hoping I would get out at the last minute and spend one more night with her. I texted back
that she deserved someone who would do that unflinchingly. I didn&rsquo;t think I could live up to that.</p>

<p>I felt both trapped and estranged near the end. It was a weird sense of closeness and distance. I
felt physically boxed in because I moved into her Upper West Side apartment in July of 2015. I
didn&rsquo;t have the space or time to think on my own without also considering her. Yet I felt we were
drifting away. We misunderstood and talked around each other more and more. We became less kind
and patient toward each other.</p>

<p>I often felt I was going mad for the paradoxical way I treated her. I loved her yet I&rsquo;d get
frustrated when she couldn&rsquo;t help me in the kitchen. I cared deeply about her yet sometimes
criticized her for wasting my time with words harsh enough to make her cry. Her optimism and
persistence, traits I cherished mostly, sometimes seemed like naivete and stubbornness.</p>

<p>Nanette had more patience and conviction for the life we had built together than I did. I
interpreted the fact that I had doubts two and a half years into our relationship as a sign that
although we were compatible in so many ways, we were not compatible enough. It killed me to know I
could be her biggest source of pain. Wouldn&rsquo;t both of us be happier dating people who might be
better matches? Nanette needed someone who&rsquo;s better at listening instead of quickly trying to come
up with solutions. Someone who could provide more emotional support while she figures out her
career passions and navigates her H1-B visa situation. Someone better at confronting relationship
issues and making up afterwards instead of sulking and letting disagreements fester. I guess in
the end I decided our problems weren&rsquo;t worth the effort it&rsquo;d take to resolve them. I was
discouraged by what I saw as a lack of results from our recent efforts. I felt emotionally burnt
out.</p>

<p>The constant pressure of time gave me more anxiety. As a certain <a href="http://www.thebookoflife.org/stay-or-leave/">thought-provoking website called
the <em>School of Life</em></a> states, &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no excuse for delay. Don&rsquo;t imagine that you&rsquo;re doing
someone a favour by dragging out how long they can persist in the benign illusion that you want
them. Their real priority is to stop wasting their lives&hellip; There&rsquo;s nothing at all wrong with
deciding someone isn&rsquo;t for you. There is something very wrong with ruining large chunks of someone
else&rsquo;s life while you squeamishly and sentimentally hesitate to get out of the
way.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I asked myself hard questions. How do I know if our relationship is worth the effort? How much
should we compromise and expect from each other? Can&rsquo;t I just be happy with what I have?</p>

<p>It was a big and lonely decision. I couldn&rsquo;t bring it up with Nanette. I couldn&rsquo;t talk about it
with most friends as I felt my relationship troubles were a personal failure and that I&rsquo;d be
betraying Nanette. Our friends thought we were great together. Some even drew inspiration from us.
I couldn&rsquo;t ask my family as they&rsquo;d already made up their minds one way or the other and were more
keen on convincing me of something rather than helping me with my contorted thoughts. It was my
own existential crisis with little consequence for everyone else.</p>

<p>Was I ready to, according to the <em>School of Life</em>, &ldquo;exchange a familiar kind of unhappiness for a
new and more complex variety&rdquo;? I had already broken Nanette&rsquo;s heart and trust once before. A month
after we returned to New York City after hiking Mt. Kilimanjaro, I asked to take a break from
seeing each other.</p>

<p>After only a week, I returned and asked her to take me back. Later I realized I was motivated more
by fear and guilt than hope and choice.</p>

<p>I tried to change my behavior and outlook. For a couple of months, things seemed to be improving.
She secretly planned a birthday dinner for me with my close friends, delighted me with gifts
including an expensive Ferragamo card holder to replace the one I lost, and surprised me with
tickets to a competitive scavenger hunt/murder mystery event at the Metropolitan Museum of Art
(just my cup of tea). I got us tickets to an interactive play called &ldquo;Then She Fell&rdquo; and the
Brooklyn Comedy Festival; I spent time teaching her Python for her General Assembly data science
class (I could&rsquo;ve been more patient though). We toured Napa Valley with her college friends for
Thanksgiving break. Our interactions were almost back to normal.</p>

<p>By the end of December, however, we were in a slump again, and my doubts were stronger than ever.
One night Nanette, sensing she was losing me, held my face in her hands as we lay in bed. She
looked into my eyes while hers swelled with tears. &ldquo;Come back. Come back,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;I want to,
but I don&rsquo;t know how,&rdquo; I replied.</p>

<p>My heart had changed. The person who set out for Boston with a heavy heart and silent tears in a
Chinatown bus two days before Christmas was not the same person Nanette met in the summer of
2013.</p>

<p>[redacted]</p>

<!--I was curious to go out and start dating again. After two and a half years, I wanted to see
what was out there. I scheduled five dates in the span of ten days at the end of January 2016 with
girls I met on dating apps. They all felt forgettable. I'd compare them to Nanette and write them
off within an hour of meeting them. Arranging so many dates in such a short amount of time also
took time, money, and concentration. I'd review chat history before each one so I wouldn't call
Joyce Nancy or ask someone who was an NYU student about her OB/GYN residency. Despite my best
efforts, I still arrived late for a couple of dates and blurted out a complete non-sequitur.-->


<p>My heart and head were not in the right place so I stopped and focused on myself instead. I swam
regularly, practiced my guitar, and took singing lessons. But the break up&rsquo;s initial relief and
freedom gave way to guilt, sadness, and loneliness.</p>

<p>Guilt haunted me after the breakup. The fact that I could hurt Nanette so much frightened me, yet
I suffered no divine or worldly punishment. To my bewilderment, life went on. So I had to punish
myself.</p>

<p>I lived austerely and pushed myself harder than usual. I moved into an apartment close to Columbus
Circle and didn&rsquo;t bother unpacking or buying furniture. I put my mattress on the ground, woke up
at 6:30AM every morning, and swam at least 3,500 yards in the Chelsea Recreation Center&rsquo;s pool. I
stopped going out except for the occasional dinner or drinks with friends.</p>

<p>I checked Nanette&rsquo;s Facebook profile more than I should have. I saw that her mother had traveled
from Jakarta to visit her and that they visited the Bronx botanical garden for an orchid
exhibition. Shortly after, Nanette posted a photo of a pink orchid on her wall. &ldquo;Oh yay &mdash; now I
have my own orchid thanks to a certain thoughtful friend. Now I just need to keep it alive&hellip;
Haha.&rdquo; I felt this was a subtle reference to the fact that a new guy was now in her life. Every
couple of weeks or so, she&rsquo;d post a new photo of her blooming orchid. While it was thriving, I was
reminded of how my lack of mindfulness allowed what we once grew to decay.</p>

<p>A few weeks later, when I saw a photo of her with a handsome and gentle-looking man, I knew she
had moved on. My guilt lessened because she seemed happy again. I was surprised, however, by the
jealousy that took its place. I liked the pain though, because it proved I really loved her. I&rsquo;d
be more worried if I didn&rsquo;t feel anything at all.</p>

<p>I held onto this pain. I allowed myself to be sad, to let it wash over me. It killed me but made
me feel alive. (Now I sound like a One Republic song.) The pain felt like a strange animal from
which I could draw strength and inspiration. Hurting also helped me burn into my mind the lessons
I learned. They include but aren&rsquo;t limited to:</p>

<ol>
<li>Talk about issues early and resolve them. I was not as good at communicating as I thought I
was. I was naive and expected Nanette to read my mind and know my wants and dislikes. She was
better than I was at teaching me how to love her than I was at explaining to her about myself.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t make people feel inadequate. This is a nasty fault of mine. Enough said.</li>
<li>Give your significant other your undivided attention when you know she needs it most. I can be
impatient and sometimes I tried to multitask which would upset her, understandably so.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t let myself get burned out. This relates to number one above. I sulked.</li>
<li>Appreciate and acknowledge that different people express love in different ways. Nanette showed
she cared through affection and sentimental gifts: a video compilation of my close friends saying
happy birthday to me when I turned 26, cards and flowers, a surprise delivery of David&rsquo;s Tea even
when she was thousands of miles away in Nairobi. I gave her more practical gifts: backpacking
gear, a green J Crew jacket and brown Uggs for the winter, and even a portable bidet (dual-action
nozzle with cold <em>and</em> hot water).</li>
</ol>


<p>In this introspective and soul-searching period, swimming was both atonement and therapy. My hair
grew coarse; my skin became dry; and I smelled like chlorine. Stroke after stroke, I wanted the
water to purify me. I swam until I was out of breath, until the lack of oxygen drowned out
thoughts of Nanette. Swimming became a new constant that replaced her. On Friday, after swimming
throughout the whole week, I&rsquo;d be a tight wad of nerves and flesh. I&rsquo;d visit a Chinatown massage
parlor where a masseur plied and kneaded me until my muscles opened up.</p>

<p>When I became tired in the pool, my technique deteriorated. I&rsquo;d fight the water instead of working
with it. Great swimmers achieve a huge amount of distance per stroke. They&rsquo;re efficient because
they can find that moment of stillness between each stroke where they just glide.</p>

<p>I sought out stillness in other parts of life as well. I wanted to be single for a while and enjoy
the freedom and solitude. For a time, it was weird to think about everything Nanette and I had
experienced and to know those moments had passed. We hiked <a href="https://youtu.be/W0ft7A9-Z6E?t=1m8s">Mt. Rinjani in Indonesia</a> and
<a href="https://youtu.be/8bkkJC_XreQ">Kilimanjaro in Tanzania</a>. We entangled ourselves in each other on the bed and shared our innermost
secrets. All of a sudden she was no longer in my life. For a while, whenever I&rsquo;d see something
beautiful or funny, I&rsquo;d reflexively want to share it with someone as I&rsquo;d once done with Nanette.
After a while, however, I learned and accepted how to be alone again.</p>

<p>I ended our relationship because I had the hope of something better for both of us. Neither of us
were afraid to get hurt at the beginning. The chance we took led to two and a half amazing years
of unforgettable experiences. I ended it because I wasn&rsquo;t afraid of getting hurt at the end. I was
ready to confront whatever could be on the other side of the breakup even though at the time it
seemed like the end of the world. I got back together with Nanette in August for the wrong
reasons: guilt and fear instead of hope and choice. But choice, as this wonderful <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/03/16/fashion/modern-love-A-Second-Embrace-With-Hearts-and-Eyes-Open-.html"><em>New York
Times</em> &ldquo;Modern Love&rdquo; essay</a> points out, &ldquo;terrifying as it can be, is so much better.&rdquo;</p>

<p>We grow through the people that touch us the most even if their presence is impermanent. I feel
nothing but goodwill towards Nanette. I&rsquo;m eternally grateful for how she shared so much of herself
with me and had so much faith even when I was mercurial and prickly. I hope that I helped her grow
when we were together as much as she helped me. Now that we&rsquo;re apart, both of us have the freedom
to grow even more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
