<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Columbia University | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/columbia-university/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-01-27T16:16:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Have No Debt, How Un-American of Me]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/03/i-have-no-debt-how-un-american-of-me/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/03/i-have-no-debt-how-un-american-of-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently got off the phone with the debt collectors of the Federal Perkins loan I borrowed for
college. I shudder when I think of debt collectors. Sure, developed countries&#8217; attitudes and
policies surrounding debt has improved a lot since Charles Dickens&#8217; time when debtors were simply
thrown into the slammer, but I still shudder.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The debt collection agency is called Campus Products and Services. They&rsquo;re a division of
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affiliated_Computer_Services">Affiliated Computer Services</a>, which is in turn a subsidiary of the Xerox Corporation.</p>

<p>As my <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Perkins_Loan">nine month grace period</a> of no interest accumulation expired, I received a letter from
ACS. The company wrote the letter with all capitals in hard-to-read monospace font. The only
logical conclusion I could make was that ACS still uses typewriters and hires switchboard
operators. If you have &ldquo;computer&rdquo; in your company&rsquo;s name, you should check if those computers have
fonts that don&rsquo;t make you look like you&rsquo;re from an authoritarian police state.</p>

<p>ACS&#8217; letter had no information on how to pay during the grace period. It read: &ldquo;Your grace period
will expire February 28, 2011. The amount due with your first monthly payment is $40.00. We will
send you your first bill about three to four weeks before the due date.&rdquo; So where do I mail a
check if I abhor paying interest?</p>

<p>I called ACS to ask. The operator worried when she asked if my email address was jlr[some
arbitrary numbers]@hotmail.com. Excuse me, but who the fuck is that? &ldquo;So has ACS sent e-mails to
that address?&rdquo; I asked. &ldquo;No, all correspondence is done through post,&rdquo; she said. Good, because I
don&rsquo;t want jlr[some arbitrary numbers]@hotmail.com to get my financial lowdown.</p>

<p>Luckily, the operator told me I could pay early through their <a href="http://www.ace-education.com">website</a> or snail mail. Finding
a human being in the ACS automated answering system was circuitous. Why do these telephonic
systems make speaking with a real person so hard? The option &ldquo;press 0 to speak with an operator&rdquo;
hides in some dark telephonic cul-de-sac. &ldquo;If you would like to speak with an operator, please
press 0 and then do 50 push-ups, then press 1, then knock on Cheryl&rsquo;s door at Utica, NY&hellip;&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Roommate Horror Stories]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/the-best-roommate-horror-stories/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/the-best-roommate-horror-stories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We all have roommate horror stories. Here are some particularly bad ones I&rsquo;ve heard from my friends.</p>

<ul>
<li>The roommate who filmed a porno of herself and her boyfriend on your bed.</li>
<li>The roommate whose friends smoked pot and vomited in your dormitory floor&rsquo;s communal male
showers. This roommate stayed out late reenacting <em>Fight Club</em> scenes with his wrestling team,
played video games all night during final exams with the volume on high, and one day began
<a href="/2009/10/college-student-stores-22-bottles-of-urine" title="College student stores 22 bottles of urine">storing his urine in bottles</a> and leaving them in his room indefinitely.<!--more--></li>
<li>The female Korean roommate who became unemployed and collected unemployment checks after
graduating from an Ivy League institution. She dyed her hair purple, but she did it in the bathtub
which became purple until you spent an entire weekend bleaching and scrubbing the color out. Said
roommate then asked your permission for a Danish male friend to crash at your two-bedroom
apartment for two weeks. Two weeks turned into two months of the apartment&rsquo;s only toilet clogged
by rock-hard Danish turds, tardiness at your job from waiting for the bathroom in the morning, and
listening to them sing Broadway duets every single day.

<ul>
<li>But there were advantages to having this female Korean roommate. While unemployed, she bought
over $400 of liquor ranging from Frangelico to Vermouth and a shit-ton of frozen chicken nuggets
that she ate for dinner. She installed a window air conditioning unit for your apartment. She
didn&rsquo;t bother taking either the alcohol or the AC unit when she moved out.

<ul>
<li>But there were downsides to these benefits. When your parents visited, you had to convince them
that contrary to the bottles of Baileys Irish Cream you were not an alcoholic. To install the
window AC unit, your roommate damaged the window by drilling holes into its metal frame.

<ul>
<li>She never updated her bank and billing accounts with her new postal address. So if you
really wanted, you could drain her accounts, and you now know how much she&rsquo;s paying for
utilities at her new apartment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The female roommate who wanted to make some extra cash. She responded to Craigslist personals by
strangers who had the urge to urinate on other human beings and were willing to pay large sums of
money to do so.</li>
<li>The roommate who washed his clothes once every three months. And when he did wash them,
separated them into two piles. Not whites and colors. He sniffed each article of clothing. One
pile was for the clothes that were putrid; the other for clothes that unless washed would be
classified by the Environmental Protection Agency as a biohazard.</li>
<li>The college roommate whose friend projectile vomited in your shared dorm room. The vomit then
soaked into the room&rsquo;s carpet. The patch of carpet next to your bed emitted foul, sour odors for
the rest of the school year.</li>
<li>The college roommate whose visiting friend got high and punched out all your dormitory floor&rsquo;s
ceiling panels. The school&rsquo;s housing department assessed the damage to be in the thousands of
dollars and slapped the liability on both of you.</li>
</ul>


<p>Post your roommate horror stories below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make Money by Making People Drunk]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/how-to-make-money-by-making-people-drunk/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/how-to-make-money-by-making-people-drunk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my sophomore year at Columbia, my friend Peter and I decided to take the student-run
Columbia Bartending Agency&rsquo;s <a href="http://columbiabartending.com/the-school/">mixology course</a>. We paid $200 for the opportunity to get drunk
by 7PM on Thursdays as well as learn to make some drinks. In preparation for the agency&rsquo;s final
exam for certification, Peter and I decided to throw a bar tending party in my room. My roommate
was worried about my hosting a loud party in a alcohol-free dorm building and selling alcohol to
minors, but I persuaded him by assuring that I would enforce his list of regulations below (which
I drew up):</p>

<ol>
<li>These are not Matt&rsquo;s rules.</li>
<li>Matt doesn&rsquo;t know about this event.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t go through Matt&rsquo;s shit.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t steal Matt&rsquo;s shit.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t pour drinks on Matt&rsquo;s shit.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t attract the attention of public safety.</li>
<li>No orgies, &ldquo;but if one will inevitable arise, you must call me [Matt].&rdquo;<!--more--></li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t mess up Matt&rsquo;s drawings.</li>
<li>No trying to sniff through Matt&rsquo;s dirty laundry.</li>
<li>No carnal knowledge on Matt&rsquo;s bed.</li>
<li>Every guest must go through a background check with Matt.</li>
<li>For tonight, Matt doesn&rsquo;t live here.</li>
</ol>


<p>We called it David&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casablanca_(film)#Plot">Café Américain</a> and charged every guest a $5 all-you-can-drink cover. The
fee went towards buying the liquor, which isn&rsquo;t cheap in Manhattan. Most people paid. Amazingly,
we actually made a profit at the end of the night. It reminded me of one of the
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142400580?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0142400580">Great Brain&rsquo;s</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0142400580" alt="" /> money-making schemes.</p>

<p><strong>Revenue</strong><br/>
$131</p>

<p><strong>Cost</strong><br/>
$6 (ice, mint)<br/>
$24 (grenadine, Rose&rsquo;s Lime, grapefruit, 5 limes, 2 lemons, lime juice, lemon juice)<br/>
$56 (tequila, light rum, vodka, kahlua, triple sec)<br/>
<strong>$86 total</strong></p>

<p><strong>Profit</strong><br/>
$27 David<br/>
$18 Peter<br/>
<strong>$45 total</strong></p>

<p><strong>Profit Margin</strong><br/>
52%</p>

<p>We kept our customers happy by offering a wide selection of drinks (see menu at bottom). Our
profit margin came from pilfering a dozen 1-liter Nalgene bottles worth of free mixers (soda,
seltzer, fruit juices, milk), cups, napkins, and sugar from our campus dining hall.</p>

<p>We tried to replicate our success a second time but weren&rsquo;t so lucky. We charged girls $3 and guys
$5 and ended up in the black. But our profits were paltry.</p>

<p><strong>Revenue</strong><br/>
$143.45</p>

<p><strong>Cost</strong><br/>
$137.57</p>

<p><strong>Profit</strong><br/>
$5.88</p>

<p><strong>Profit/person</strong><br/>
$2.94</p>

<p><strong>Profit/person/hour</strong><br/>
$.49</p>

<hr />

<p>Highballs</p>

<ul>
<li>Screwdriver</li>
<li>Greyhound</li>
<li>Salty Dog</li>
<li>Cape Codder</li>
<li>Sea breeze</li>
<li>Madras</li>
<li>Tequila Sunrise</li>
<li>Rickey</li>
<li>Bloody Mary</li>
<li>Bloody Maria</li>
</ul>


<p>Lowballs</p>

<ul>
<li>Mojitos</li>
<li>Mint julep</li>
<li>Vodka Gimlet</li>
</ul>


<p>Martinis</p>

<ul>
<li>Cosmopolitan</li>
<li>Ruby Martini</li>
</ul>


<p>Shaken Drinks</p>

<ul>
<li>Sours</li>
<li>Collins</li>
<li>Daiquiri</li>
<li>Bacardi cocktail</li>
<li>Margarita</li>
<li>Long Island Iced Tea</li>
<li>Acapulco</li>
</ul>


<p>Shooters</p>

<ul>
<li>Kamikaze</li>
<li>Mission Accomplished</li>
<li>Lemon Drop</li>
<li>Prairie Fire</li>
</ul>


<p>Cream Drinks</p>

<ul>
<li>White Russian</li>
<li>Sombrero</li>
</ul>


<p>Floaters/Pousse Cafes</p>

<ul>
<li>King Alphonse</li>
</ul>


<p>Cordials</p>

<ul>
<li>Black Russian</li>
<li>Brave Bull</li>
<li>Russian Turkey</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do Algebra and Castro Have in Common?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/what-do-algebra-and-castro-have-in-common/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/what-do-algebra-and-castro-have-in-common</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What do algebra and Castro have in common? What are Columbia&rsquo;s Contemporary Civilization class
discussions really like? And what&rsquo;s the secret weapon of white male Republicans? Here&rsquo;s some more
hilarious quotes I dug up.</p>

<ul>
<li>God created the integers; all else is the work of man. – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Dedekind">Richard Dedekind</a><br/>
So maybe God lives in Arabia. – <a href="http://www.math.columbia.edu/~neumann/">Professor Walter Neumann</a> on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic_numerals#Origins">Hindu-Arabic numerals</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.math.columbia.edu/fac-bios/Gallagher/faculty.html">Professor Patrick Gallagher</a>: [writing a math proof on blackboard, suddenly stops] It&rsquo;s like
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_Will_Absolve_Me">Fidel Castro</a> once said, &#8221;History will absolve me.&ldquo; And likewise we get a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homomorphism">homomorphism</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://patrickzimmerli.com/">Patrick Zimmerli</a> was a lecturer for my beginning music theory course. In addition to being
upbeat and nice, he was eccentric and hilarious. He encouraged students to dress up on Wednesdays,
which he declared &ldquo;snazzy-Wednesday.&rdquo; He playfully embarrassed by making us sing chords, which he
said helped him relax after a long day. And he told us to call him &ldquo;PZ.&rdquo;</p>

<ul>
<li>PZ to female student Susan who&rsquo;s wearing a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wimple">wimple</a>, on a Wednesday at that: Wow, you&rsquo;re
really hot and on. [The class laughs nervously.] Oh, was that not appropriate for me to say?</li>
<li>The New York Philharmonic used to be the New York Philharmonic Society – lovers of music. Now
they just get paid to be yuppies.</li>
<li>I am inclined to let this discussion go on, but I&rsquo;m just going to end it. We will discuss this
at 2AM while ingesting hallucinogenics. – PZ interrupting a pre-class discussion on whether
glasses makes one&rsquo;s vision worse.</li>
<li>Is that &ldquo;merch&rdquo;? – PZ asking about the shirt of a female student who&rsquo;s a member of Columbia&rsquo;s
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bhangra">Bhangra</a> student group</li>
<li>The brain is not for thinking. Remember that. – PZ</li>
<li>For those of you who find this unbelievably boring just sit there eand think about whether we
should countinue the human species in its current condition. – PZ after some students have trouble
with 4-part reduction.</li>
</ul>


<p>Columbia&rsquo;s philosophy classes are the paragon of intellectual discourse.</p>

<ul>
<li>What do you have against happiness! - an indignant student on Kant&rsquo;s
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0521626951?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0521626951">Groundwork on the Metaphysics of Morals</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0521626951" alt="" /> during Columbia&rsquo;s
<a href="http://www.college.columbia.edu/core/classes/cc.php">Contemporary Civilization</a> course</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s fair to assume they were women. – Contemporary Civilization Professor DEL
after Nick makes a comment about Adam Smith&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Business_process#Adam_Smith">pin factory</a> and refers to the factory workers
as &ldquo;pin ladies&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sorry, I was totally channelling <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosie_the_Riveter">Rosie the Riveter</a> that whole time. – Nick</li>
<li>Okay, Chris. You are not allowed to bring up eunuchs for the rest of the section. – teaching
assistant Buyun during a Chinese history class discussion section</li>
</ul>


<p>Chinese language class cracked me up.</p>

<ul>
<li>Big girl have big dream. Tell me your dreams and aspirations. You can say whatever. This is
Chinese class so just say them even though they probably won&rsquo;t come true. – first-year Chinese
language class lecturer Jia Liu</li>
<li>Although she&rsquo;s very beautiful, no one likes her. - Chinese language class exercise<br/>
Why is that? – Jia Liu asks class<br/>
Because she&rsquo;s bitch. – female student Ruoxi out of left-field</li>
</ul>


<p>Who else brought a pillow to Columbia&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.sciencecore.columbia.edu/">Frontiers of Science</a> lectures?</p>

<ul>
<li>I think if you&rsquo;re teaching climate change it&rsquo;s counter-productive to give everyone a copy of
the worksheets. – <a href="http://www.astro.columbia.edu/~sharmila/">Sharmila Kamat</a> on saving the Earth one handout at a time</li>
</ul>


<p>Sometimes I wish I were still M.K.&rsquo;s roommate.</p>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m not wearing a diaper because I don&rsquo;t want gay people to rape me. – M.K. on why he&rsquo;s not
dressing up as a baby to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York's_Village_Halloween_Parade">Village Halloween parade</a></li>
<li>I can&rsquo;t wait to see James and Rachel hook up. – M.K. on James&#8217; newfound intensity</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m gonna fuck your mom in the ear. – M.K.&rsquo;s retort to Eric&rsquo;s &ldquo;yo mama&rdquo; jokes</li>
<li>I know that shit is real because they film it in my stomach. – M.K. about Pinky and the Brain</li>
<li>The things I do for my mom&hellip;she really appreciates me. – M.K. about his mother</li>
<li>I read somewhere that the chances of your vote counting is one out of five billion. – M.K. on
the futility of voting</li>
</ul>


<p>Keep some people in your life for their entertainment value.</p>

<ul>
<li>Obama has won the election. Attn: all white people report to the cotton fields tomorrow morning.
– Phillip H. text message to Joseph Y.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re interested in someone as more than a friend, even if it&rsquo;s somewhere down the line, you
should want to bone them. – Mishi C.</li>
<li>Have you gone off every exit in New Hampshire? – Margaret W. I have actually explored the
surrounding countryside, motherfuckers! – Seth D.</li>
</ul>


<p>Do you realize you&rsquo;re speaking to reporters on tape?</p>

<ul>
<li>Misfortune is a spectator sport nowadays&hellip;Even white male republicans are using it. – former
Barnard College President <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judith_Shapiro">Judith Shapiro</a><br/>
It&rsquo;s the only way they can get elected. – former Barnard Dean <a href="http://www.columbiaspectator.com/2010/06/04/barnards-denburg-step-down-dean-vp-job">Dorothy Denburg</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Quotes From That Baller Weird College Kid]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/best-quotes-from-that-baller-weird-college-kid/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/best-quotes-from-that-baller-weird-college-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>J.O. was an eccentric and benign person to all who knew him during their time as undergraduates at
Columbia University. He would drop by your dormitory room at the most inopportune times without
calling, clean out your refrigerator, and ignore basic social cues, but without him the world
wouldn&rsquo;t have the quotations recorded here for posterity.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-x0HSRGyodA?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Here&rsquo;s an audio clip of J.O. ranting about an unconsummated college crush:</p>

<p>Audio clip: Adobe Flash Player (version 9 or above) is required to play this audio clip. Download
the latest version <a href="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash&amp;promoid=BIOW" title="Download Adobe Flash Player">here</a>. You also need to have JavaScript enabled in your browser.</p>

<p><audio controls><source src='/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/JO-rant.mp3'></audio></p>

<p>&ldquo;Multivariable, that really brings me back.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;J.O. is done for the weekend. Back to the problem sets that are his life.&rdquo;</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Sam: Good old multivariable. That really brings me back.<br/>
J.O.: No, this is my book from last year&hellip;The <em>beginning</em> of last year.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Deaf people suck.&rdquo; – J.O., out of absolutely nowhere.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hug?&rdquo; – J.O. to girls during awkward moments. Always met with rejection.</p>

<p>&ldquo;J.O. created a group: Honors Mathematics 06-07″ – Facebook newsfeed</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shortest math joke ever: Let epsilon &lt; 0&rdquo; – a post on J.O.&rsquo;s Facebook group</p>

<p>Alex: J.O., can you help me with this integral?<br/>
J.O.: I probably could with some method.<br/>
Alex: How would you go about it?<br/>
J.O.: Whatever.<br/>
Alex: Can you help me?<br/>
J.O.: Whatever.<br/>
Alex: So you don&rsquo;t know how to do it?<br/>
J.O.: Whatever. [walks away]</p>

<p>[J.O. is showing off his Rubik&rsquo;s Cube skills during a study break in the student lounge. His cell
phone rings.]<br/>
&ldquo;Stop fucking calling me!&rdquo;<br/>
[He answers and turns his tone of voice 180-degrees.]<br/>
&ldquo;Oh, hey Sarah.&rdquo;</p>

<p>[J.O. cornering Hopkins in the hall]<br/>
J.O.: What are you up to tonight?<br/>
Hopkins: Nothing much.<br/>
J.O.: Yeah, I think I&rsquo;ll go to the parties or whatever and watch <em>Battlestar Galactica</em>.<br/>
Hopkins: Cool.<br/>
J.O.: No, seriously. It&rsquo;s good now.<br/>
Hopkins: Cool.<br/>
J.O.: Do you know where everyone is?<br/>
Hopkins: Nope<br/>
J.O.: Is julia here?<br/>
Hopkins: I don&rsquo;t know. (Later, I see her on the 11th floor and warn her to stay clear.)</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve always been sub-40.&rdquo; – J.O. when asked if he&rsquo;s &ldquo;sub-40″ aka can solve a Rubik&rsquo;s Cube in
under 40 seconds.</p>

<p>[J.O. and Katie talking at her door while I watch, gaping. J.O. is hiding a book behind his back
while they talk about physicist Richard Feynman.]<br/>
J.O.: I own [book].<br/>
Katie: cool, me too<br/>
J.O.: Guess what book I have?<br/>
Katie: Chemistry<br/>
J.O.: No, [book]. Do you want to borrow it?<br/>
Katie: No.<br/>
J.O.: Why do I have this urge to have a conversation with you?<br/>
Katie: [no response]<br/>
J.O.: You have dimples.<br/>
Katie: No.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Everyone has weed. No one has rolling paper anymore.&rdquo;</p>

<p>[J.O. opens beer can and spills some on Matt K&rsquo;s shoes.]<br/>
Matt: Hey, you got beer all over my clean socks!<br/>
J.O.: Cry me a river, bitch.<br/>
[J.O. drinks his beer.]</p>

<p>[J.O. attempts to throw a Pepsi can still containing some Pepsi into a trash can being carried by
his peer Yossi. Pepsi flies out of the can in mid-flight and splatters all over Yossi&rsquo;s face and
shirt and begins collecting on Yossi&rsquo;s chin until it dribbles onto the floor. Everyone stares in
shock.]</p>

<p>J.O.: Aw, man. You didn&rsquo;t even get the recycling bin.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Recycle, noob.&rdquo; – J.O. to me while picking my can out of the trash.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m in the national league, bitches. We don&rsquo;t do DH [designated hitter].&rdquo; – J.O. passionately
arguing with Matt K. in a restaurant about baseball or football is a superior sport.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I feel like you&rsquo;re asking for my daughter&rsquo;s hand in marriage.&rdquo; – J.O. to me.</p>

<p>&ldquo;So I was talking to this girl the other day by the elevator when some kid who was standing nearby
says to me later, &lsquo;Wow, you&rsquo;re so smooth&rsquo;&hellip;Damn straight. I am a smooth motherfucker.&rdquo; – J.O. on
how he talked to Sari when they went to summer camp.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh, those tricky Jews.&rdquo; – J.O.</p>

<p>Did you just come from a funeral? – J.O. to Professor Lipshitz who happens to come to class one
day wearing all black attire.</p>

<p>&ldquo;M. Night Shamylan needs to get a real job!&hellip;Oh, my God. They&rsquo;re bringing back <em>The Mole</em>!&rdquo; – J.O.
during previews before <em>Iron Man</em> screening.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Rachel V. is the female Erdos.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
