<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/career/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-11-11T17:28:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My QCon NYC 2016 Slides - Reach Production Faster With Containers in Testing]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-20T17:15:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are the slides from my <a href="https://qconnewyork.com/ny2016/presentation/reaching-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing">QCon NYC 2016 talk titled &ldquo;Reach Production Faster with Containers in
Testing.&rdquo;</a> in various formats. <span xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" property="dct:title">All formats of &ldquo;Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing&rdquo;</span> by <a xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/ns#" href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides-reach-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing/" property="cc:attributionName" rel="cc:attributionURL">David Xia</a> are licensed under a <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</a>.</p>

<iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/p1uEfRmocwplbk" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen> </iframe>


<p> <div style="margin-bottom:5px"> <strong> <a href="//www.slideshare.net/DavidXia/qcon-nyc-2016-reach-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing" title="QCon NYC 2016: Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing" target="_blank">QCon NYC 2016: Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="//www.slideshare.net/DavidXia" target="_blank">David Xia</a></strong> </div></p>

<p>More formats here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkSloyT3gxalRuYjQ/view?usp=sharing">PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkSm9BVW5uWFR5TFk/view?usp=sharing">Keynote</a></li>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkRkpQWk5paUZOUW8/view?usp=sharing">PowerPoint</a></li>
</ul>


<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/w0P47Ugl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/w0P47Ugl.jpg</a> 640 619 %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Years of Working at Spotify, Four Years of Shared Values]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/four-years-of-working-at-spotify-four-years-of-shared-values/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-13T13:01:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/four-years-of-working-at-spotify-four-years-of-shared-values</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can&rsquo;t believe it&rsquo;s been four years since I started working at Spotify. Every Friday, the
Technology, Product, and Design group at Spotify&rsquo;s New York City office
gathers to eat freshly catered snacks, introduce new hires, announce &ldquo;wins of the week,&rdquo; and
commemorate the anniversaries of existing employees.</p>

<p>Last Friday was my turn to stand before the couple hundred members of TPD. It&rsquo;s customary for people
celebrating their employment anniversaries to speak about their favorite Spotify memory.
I don&rsquo;t get many chances to address so many of my colleagues at
once. So I took this opportunity to prepare a short statement. It went something like this.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s my favorite Spotify memory? I have a hard time with this question because I don&rsquo;t have a
good answer. There&rsquo;s so many.</p>

<p>I find another question more interesting. That question is, &ldquo;What, after four years, makes me look
forward to getting up every weekday morning and working at Spotify?&rdquo; Four years is a long time to
be doing anything continuously.</p>

<p>I can tell you what&rsquo;s not the main reason. It&rsquo;s not the snacks or perks or the amazing office.
It&rsquo;s not even Celebration X [Spotify&rsquo;s massive 10-year anniversary party in Stockholm].
These are all great things, but they&rsquo;re not the main reason I show up everyday.</p>

<p>The main reason is values. I&rsquo;ve never been at a place where I share so many values with my
colleagues and the company. My teammates like Matt and Staffan and Mats share my values of hard
work, competence, and personal responsibility (and beer). The company constantly strives to become
a better version of itself through being risk-taking, passion, and compassion.</p>

<p>Every day is a new memory. Every day I feel blessed to be here working with all of you. Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanette on Nairobi's Hopeful Youth]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2015/04/nanette-on-nairobis-hopeful-youth/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2015/04/nanette-on-nairobis-hopeful-youth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Nanette&rsquo;s fourth day in Nairobi, she and three other Kiva fellows visited a non-profit
organization that teaches disadvantaged youth the skills they need to land jobs and make a living.
The <a href="http://www.capyei.org/" title="Community and Progress Youth Empowerment Institute">Community and Progress Youth Empowerment Institute</a> (CAP-YEI) caters to dropouts,
unemployed graduates, street youth, retrenched workers, and pretty much any young person at risk
of falling through the cracks. These young people can take vocational courses in information
technology, hospitality, automobile, customer relations, and sales. Note: dropout here doesn&rsquo;t
have the same connotation it usually does in the United States. It refers to students that drop
out of school not because they don&rsquo;t want to attend but because their family can&rsquo;t afford to pay
tuition.</p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/UkX3KWrl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/UkX3KWrl.jpg</a> 640 480 The front of the CAP school. %}</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Fredrick is a recent CAP graduate who received and <a href="https://zip.kiva.org/loans/9135">fully paid back his first Kiva Zip loan of
$125</a>. After finishing CAP, Fredrick set up a stall at a busy
intersection in Nairobi selling used clothes. He pays the city a hundred Kenyan shillings a week
or a little over one US dollar for a vendor&rsquo;s permit. After using his first Kiva Zip loan to set
up his small business, which has a Facebook page and makes deliveries to customers, Fredrick told
Nanette he wants another loan to buy more used items to sell, like sandals. Nanette&rsquo;s friend Safia
bought a pink pair of Nike shorts from him for 200 shillings at the end of their visit.</p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/OZOwCQtl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/OZOwCQtl.jpg</a> 640 480 Fredrick&rsquo;s clothes stall. %}</p>

<p>{% img_caption center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/O91nAV1l.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/O91nAV1l.jpg</a> 640 480 Nanette posing with a pair of pink Nike shorts next to Fredrick and a CAP administrator. %}</p>

<p>Nanette visited <a href="https://zip.kiva.org/loans/8527">another borrower also named Fredrick</a> who&rsquo;s
still studying in CAP creates and sells practice worksheets for primary school students. He sells
each sheet of simple math questions for 20 shillings or a little over 20 US cents.</p>

<p>CAP runs schools in Nairobi, Nyeri, and Naivasha. Its Nairobi location offers classes in
electrical wiring, hospitality, and security. Other locations have customer service, garments, and
manufacturing classes.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Their goal when they open a new center is to make sure the majority if not all the kids they
teach, land a job. That&rsquo;s their main goal. That&rsquo;s their metric,&rdquo; said Nanette. &ldquo;So they don&rsquo;t just
randomly choose a place that has a lot of kids that don&rsquo;t go to school. They also find a location
where there are kids and there are also industries to support them.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The persistence and optimism of CAP&rsquo;s instructors and students inspired Nanette tremendously.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s nice to see real change,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;They track their students. Where they go. What they&rsquo;re
doing. How a Kiva Zip loan can be a big part of it because a lot of students want to start their
own businesses. To see two borrowers doing really well, improving their lives and going back to
school &mdash; you can see the real impact.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Since Kiva Zip has given only 12 loans so far to CAP graduates, CAP wants to expand this
partnership to give more of their students money to bootstrap their entrepreneurial ideas. They
cite their young borrowers&#8217; one hundred percent repayment rate and point out the many other
graduates that also have a lot of potential.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m very impressed with the students. They&rsquo;re poor, but they&rsquo;re so motivated, polite, hopeful,
and positive. All of them spoke up [in class],&rdquo; Nanette said excitedly. &ldquo;They kept asking us about
Kiva loans. They shared how the school has changed their lives and what they want to do after they
graduate.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not exaggerating. Everybody was sitting in their seat paying attention and taking notes.
Everybody has books. Everybody was writing down stuff. And these are dropout kids who are poor!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Nanette Got Into Kiva - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2015/03/how-nanette-got-into-kiva-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2015/03/how-nanette-got-into-kiva-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the first part of a series in which I write about how Nanette worked for and finally got
accepted into Kiva, a well-respected microfinance organization. She&rsquo;s now having a great time in
Nairobi helping borrowers and improving the operations of Kiva Zip. This series of posts is a gift
for her and a tribute to her hardwork.</em></p>

<p>The sun was setting over Manhattan, and Nanette was staring at Excel spreadsheets and PowerPoint
slides on her clunky work laptop. Throngs of tourists seethed through Times Square 20 floors below
her at Ernst and Young&rsquo;s Times Square office.</p>

<p>It was January 2014, and Nanette felt lost and unsure of herself. She had been working for Ernst
and Young&mdash;EY according to their recent
<a href="http://www.ey.com/ZA/en/Newsroom/News-releases/2013---Press-release---July---Ernst---Young-rebrands-globally">rebranding campaign</a>&mdash;for
two and a half years.
She knew that something was missing, but figuring out what that something was and how to get it,
would take her more than a year.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&ldquo;I find myself sitting in front of Excel sheets or PowerPoint decks, and I don&rsquo;t know what happens
to those docs after that,&rdquo; said Nanette when I interviewed her in January 2015. &ldquo;When I was young,
I always thought that I would do something bigger. I think at that time, I felt disappointed with
myself.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Nanette didn&rsquo;t always feel this way. She graduated in 2011 from University of Virginia&rsquo;s McIntire
School of Commerce with a degree in accounting and finance. After graduation, Nanette moved into
an apartment in Manhattan&rsquo;s midtown east at 245 East 44th Street with her friend and classmate
Alyssa. She had received a full time offer from EY in November 2010 and began her first day of
work on October 6, 2011.</p>

<p>When I asked Nanette in the second half of 2013 how she initially felt about her job, she said her
first year at EY was &ldquo;one of the best years of [her] life.&rdquo; Nanette had just broken up, for the
final time, with her previous boyfriend. She was single and free. She traveled around the
continental United States on business trips with other young, fresh-out-of-school colleagues. She
often had to put in long hours, but her travel and living expenses were paid for. Nanette enjoyed
the VIP statuses awarded to her by airlines, hotels, and rental car companies. She relished it
all: the experience of new cities and her single, carefree working life with some jetsetter charm
sprinkled on top. She had walked the streets of Chicago, Philadelphia, Washington D.C., Boston,
Santa Monica, London, and Edinburgh among others.</p>

<p>Nearly two and a half years later, Nanette began to feel a certain type of hunger. She began
looking for ways to volunteer. She kicked off 2014 by attended eight networking events to meet
like-minded people and &ldquo;explore ways to make helping people a bigger part of her life instead of
just volunteering a few hours a week.&rdquo; These networking events focused on social entrepreneurship
or impact investing. What interested others, however, did not always appeal to Nanette. One woman
at a Meetup event described her idea of creating a community group dedicated to eating organic
food. But Nanette is not passionate about food. She felt others were as lost as she was. Available
job openings were for community managers or did not sponsor work visas. Nanette quickly realized
she had to stop talking and start doing.</p>

<p>It took Nanette months of searching within herself and online to figure out what she liked and an
applicable opportunity. In January 2014, Nanette began spending three hours a day for three months
on her search for something new. In March, she found Net Impact, a nonprofit organization where
people can contribute their professional skills to various social and environmental groups.
Through Net Impact, nonprofits that don&rsquo;t have money to hire consultants get them for free. This
organization matched her interests and background. Nanette wanted to apply but realized she had
missed an application deadline by several days.</p>

<p>Luckily Nanette&rsquo;s Ernst and Young colleague Ali Briggs was the Programs Co-Chair of Net Impact&rsquo;s
New York City chapter.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Remember I decided to do more instead of just talking and networking? So I did a lot of research,
and then I stumbled onto NI&rsquo;s page. I went to the about page and saw my friend&rsquo;s name there. I
thought, &lsquo;Alright, I should apply.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>

<p>Although Nanette did not submit an application, in March, Ali helped place her with a non-profit
organization that paired Jewish entrepreneurs with Jewish mentors. According to Nanette, the
group&rsquo;s goal was not only to help entrepreneurs but also to create a sense of community. Nanette
met at least once a week with two young Jewish women who were full time employees of the
nonprofit. They prepared fundraising materials, clarified the nonprofit&rsquo;s mission, and reviewed
how funds were spent.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That was a good first project to give me a window into what non-profit work was like&hellip;To see how
they need to fundraise all the time. They need to keep costs down all the time. They have a lot of
restrictions.&rdquo;</p>

<p>PresenTense wanted to grow but faced many resource restrictions. The group wanted to expand to
other cities and become bigger through marketing and new business development. At the same time,
according to Nanette, they wanted to improve their operations and clarify their mission first. And
they wanted to do all this on a limited budget of time and money.</p>

<p>Nanette enjoyed working with PresenTense, but she still felt something was missing. &ldquo;So I got into
Net Impact&hellip;but after a couple of weeks I discovered it wasn&rsquo;t giving me a lot of new things to
learn. I felt that I still had a lot of time. My project back then was a nine-to-six job. So I had
a lot of free time.&rdquo; Ernst and Young had staffed Nanette in a project management role for a large
bank.</p>

<p>About three weeks after Nanette started volunteering with Net Impact and PresenTense, she applied
to volunteer with Accion. This nonprofit organization gives loans ranging from $2,500 to $50,000
to local entrepreneurs who are not able to get loans through banks. Accion also provides their
borrowers with pro-bono consultants like Nanette.</p>

<p>Although Nanette was only in the second class of volunteers Accion had assembled, she was
impressed by how organized it was. Nanette had to report back regularly and felt accountable for
her work.</p>

<p>Accion assigned Nanette to help a woman in her mid-30s who ran an online business selling
alcoholic cupcakes. This woman started her business almost two years ago and had recently received
a loan from Accion. She wanted to use the money to sell more cupcakes in more places. Nanette
worked with another volunteer to analyze where else the online bakery should sell its cupcakes.
Whole Foods, Fairway, or Groupon? In the end, they recommended that the owner try selling on Etsy.</p>

<p>On June 11, when all the projects were finished, Accion&rsquo;s volunteer consultants presented their
work to other volunteers, their business owner clients, and Accion board members. The CEO of
Accion&rsquo;s east coast chapter <a href="http://www.accioneast.org/home/support-accion/learn/in-the-news.aspx/d=2075/title=Paul_Quintero__CEO_Series_on_Small_Business_Lending">Paul Quintero</a>
also attended. Around eighty people gathered in the corporate offices of Pimco in midtown
Manhattan that evening.</p>

<p>After these two experiences, Nanette realized she didn&rsquo;t want to be a pro-bono consultant for
businesses that had taken out microfinance loans but wanted to contribute to microfinance groups
themselves. Her next volunteering experience with Zidisha would let her do just that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Spotify Top Tracks Widget]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2013/04/new-spotify-top-tracks-widget/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2013/04/new-spotify-top-tracks-widget</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out the new Spotify Top Tracks Widget I made for Spotify.</p>

<iframe src="http://charts.spotify.com/embed/charts/most_streamed/us/latest" width="300" height="400" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
