<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Uncategorized | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/uncategorized/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-17T23:54:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Fascinating and Weird People]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/06/four-fascinating-and-weird-people/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-01T06:36:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/06/four-fascinating-and-weird-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are the stories of four fascinating and weird people that will make you laugh, be inspired,
or cringe. Chang and Eng Bunker were conjoined twins who married two sisters and were slave-owners
on the side of the Southern Confederacy. Rose Wilder Lane is the daughter of the author who wrote
the <em>Little House</em> childrens books, a founding member of the American Libertarian movement, and just
all around boss ass bitch. John Harvey Kellogg was the inventor of corn flakes, doctor, zealous
anti-masturbation campaigner, and eugenicist.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>1. Chang and Eng Bunker</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chang_and_Eng_Bunker">Chang and Eng</a> were two conjoined twins born
in Vietnam in the 1800s. The term &ldquo;Siamese twins&rdquo; is based on them.</p>

<blockquote><p>The brothers were joined at the sternum by a small piece of cartilage, and though their livers
  were fused, they were independently complete.</p></blockquote>

<p>After a Scotsman noticed them and paraded them around as a freak show attraction for ten
years, the Bunker twins settled down in Wilkesboro, North Carolina. They married two local white
women who were sisters. They became naturalized American citizens and even owned slaves.</p>

<p>The Bunkers and their wives slept in a bed built for four. After a while their wives started to not
get along. So they alternated between two different houses. Chang had twelve children while
Eng had ten. Today their descendents number more than 1,500 and hold reunions. Their liver is on
display in at the Mütter Museum in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>

<h2>2. Rose Wilder Lane</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane">Rose Wilder Lane</a> was the eldest child of Laura
Ingalls Wilder, the ostensible author of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Little_House_on_the_Prairie_books">Little House book series</a>.
Lane was by all means a boss ass bitch who lived a full life.</p>

<p>Sick of crop failures and tough frontier life, Lane moved in 1908 to San Francisco, California.
She married a salesman named Gillette Lane and became pregnant. Sadly, her son was stillborn, and
a subsequent surgery left her unable to have kids.</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Early career, marriage and divorce <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Early_career.2C_marriage_and_divorce">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Early_career.2C_marriage_and_divorce</a> %}
She felt her intellectual interests did not mesh with the life she was living with her husband.
Keenly aware of her lack of a formal education, during these years, Lane read voraciously and
taught herself several languages. Her writing career began around 1908, with occasional
freelance newspaper jobs that earned much-needed extra cash.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>Lane&rsquo;s writing career took off. She wrote for publications like <em>Harper&rsquo;s</em> and <em>Saturday Evening
Post</em>.</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Freelance writing career <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Freelance_writing_career">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Freelance_writing_career</a> %}
In the late 1920s, Lane was reputed to be one of the highest-paid female writers in America, and
along with Hoover, she counted among her friends well known figures such as Sinclair Lewis,
Isabel Paterson, Dorothy Thompson, John Patric, and Lowell Thomas.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>When Lane&rsquo;s mother approached her with a rough autobiographical manuscript of her own childhood,
Lane sensed that an American public fatigued by the Great Depression would take to the story of
the loving, persistent, and independent Ingalls family. Lane encouraged and helped her mother
rewrite and sell the story as a children&rsquo;s novel. The book became a big success, and an entire
series replete with T.V. shows, merchandise, and museums followed. Their family was raking
in the dough.</p>

<p>I read the entire series as a kid and stil wax nostalgic for it. I thought Lane&rsquo;s mother, who&rsquo;s the
titled author, wrote every book on her own and only received encouragement from her Lane. It turns
out, however, that the truth is more interesting.</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Literary collaboration <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Literary_collaboration">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Literary_collaboration</a> %}
&hellip;an ongoing mutual collaboration that involved Lane more extensively in the
earlier books, and to a much lesser extent by the time the series ended, as Wilder&rsquo;s confidence
in her own writing ability increased. Lane insisted to the end that her role was little more than
that of her mother&rsquo;s adviser, despite documentation to the contrary&hellip;Literary historians
believe that Lane&rsquo;s editing skills brought the dramatic pacing, literary structure, and
characterization critically needed to make the stories publishable in book form.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>Even more fascinating is Lane&rsquo;s societal and political views. She was a libertarian, economically
laissez faire, anti-racist, and anti-communist. She protested paying income taxes, opposed the New
Deal, and thought Social Security was a Ponzi scheme that would destroy the United States.</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Later years and death <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Later_years_and_death">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Later_years_and_death</a> %}
Lane played a hands-on role during the 1940s and 1950s in launching the &ldquo;libertarian movement&rdquo;
and began an extensive correspondence with figures such as DuPont executive Jasper Crane and
writer Frank Meyer, as well as her friend and colleague, Ayn Rand. She wrote book reviews
for the National Economic Council and later for the Volker Fund, out of which grew the Institute
for Humane Studies. Later, she lectured at, and gave generous financial support to, the Freedom
School headed by libertarian Robert LeFevre.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>I want to reread the <em>Little House</em> books now knowing she was a die-hard libertarian who along with
her mother purposefully wove themes of individualism into the series.</p>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Later years and death <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Later_years_and_death">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Wilder_Lane#Later_years_and_death</a> %}
Rose Wilder Lane died in her sleep at age 81, on October 30, 1968, just as she was about to
depart on a three-year world tour. She was buried next to her parents at Mansfield Cemetery in
Mansfield, Missouri.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<h2>3. John Harvey Kellogg</h2>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t read the entire Wikipedia entry on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Harvey_Kellogg">John Harvey Kellogg</a> yet since
a colleague only recently drew my attention to this smart, prolific, and bizarre man. These parts
stood out to me at first glance though.</p>

<ul>
<li>he invented corn flakes with his brother, Will Keith Kellogg</li>
<li>he was a medical doctor &ldquo;who ran a sanitarium using holistic methods, with a particular focus on
nutrition, enemas, and exercise. Kellogg was an advocate of vegetarianism&rdquo;</li>
<li>he also created various phototherapeutic and electrotherapeutic inventions</li>
<li>he advocated sexual abstinence and &ldquo;advocated keeping the diet plain to prevent sexual arousal&rdquo;</li>
<li>he was an &ldquo;especially zealous campaigner against masturbation&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>{% blockquote_nobr Masturbation prevention <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Harvey_Kellogg#Masturbation_prevention">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Harvey_Kellogg#Masturbation_prevention</a> %}
He also recommended, to prevent children from this &ldquo;solitary vice&rdquo;, bandaging or tying their hands,
covering their genitals with patented cages and electrical shock.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<ul>
<li>he liked yogurt enemas</li>
<li>he was a eugenicist</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[College Isn't and Shouldn't Be the Best Years of Your Life]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/college-isnt-and-shouldnt-be-the-best-years-of-your-life/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/college-isnt-and-shouldnt-be-the-best-years-of-your-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;College will be the best four years of your life.&rdquo;</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re a high schooler, someone&rsquo;s probably told you this. If you&rsquo;re an adult, you&rsquo;ve probably
said this to some impressionable young person. If you think this sentence is bullshit and at worst
a harmful sentiment to say or hear, you&rsquo;re with me.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Imagine a statesman declares to his country&rsquo;s citizens, &ldquo;The best years of our country are going
to be the next four years.&rdquo; I would think, &ldquo;So you&rsquo;re implying that it&rsquo;s all downhill after that?&rdquo;
That&rsquo;s essentially what adults are telling young people when they say the above, whether they know
it or not.</p>

<p>On the surface, the sentence seems optimistic and exciting, but it&rsquo;s actually quite depressing. So
if college is the best time of my life, what can I look forward to after graduation? Why can&rsquo;t the
best years of my life always be ahead of me? Or why can&rsquo;t I look forward to enjoying each stage of
my life for what can be? Youth brings wonder but naiveté; middle-age will give me freedom but
responsibility; and old-age will deliver wrinkles but also wisdom.</p>

<p>So stop bandying about this saying. It shouldn&rsquo;t be true so let&rsquo;s not make it a self-fulfilling
prophecy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Hate Shopping for Clothes]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/why-i-hate-shopping-for-clothes/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/why-i-hate-shopping-for-clothes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I hate shopping for clothes not because I don&rsquo;t like seeing what&rsquo;s new at stores or because I
don&rsquo;t care about what I wear. I hate it because searching for clothes that fit me in American
stores is nearly impossible.<!--more--> My measurements are:</p>

<ul>
<li>neck: 14.5″</li>
<li>chest: 38″</li>
<li>sleeve: 32.5″</li>
<li>waist: 28″</li>
<li>inseam: 30″</li>
</ul>


<p>No store sells 28-inch waist pants. I&rsquo;ve looked everywhere. Perhaps children&rsquo;s clothing stores but
not adults.</p>

<p>All the shirts I ever come across are rectangular shaped. Even the fitted ones don&rsquo;t always fit
me. If the shoulders fit then the lower half seems too big, and if the lower half of the shirt
fits, the shoulders are too tight.</p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;ll resort to ordering pants online from now on. I&rsquo;ll just have to put up with buying
without trying them on first.</p>

<p>And it doesn&rsquo;t help that my mother would buy clothes that were a couple sizes bigger than me.
&ldquo;You&rsquo;ll grow into it,&rdquo; she&rsquo;d say. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m already 23. I think I&rsquo;ve stopped growing.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Love the Moth. Why Is Voss Underwriting Them?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/i-love-the-moth-why-is-voss-underwriting-them/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/11/i-love-the-moth-why-is-voss-underwriting-them</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://themoth.org/">The Moth</a> is an organization that hosts events made of real stories told live on stage. Every
event has a different theme around which story tellers weave their narratives. They&rsquo;re one of my
favorite podcasts. I love listening to the well-crafted stories told by writers, artists, and
regular folk.</p>

<p>The stories are about 15 minutes long with simple narrative arcs, but their messages are often
complex. Some of the most memorable stories for me are:</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Mike Birbiglia talks about breaking up with his girlfriend while stranded on an island:</p>

<p>{% audio <a href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-149-mike-birbiglia.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-149-mike-birbiglia.mp3</a> %}</p>

<p>Steve Burns of children&rsquo;s show <em>Blues Clues</em> talks about grappling with TV fame.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CwmtkFPYXsg?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I admire the Moth&rsquo;s storytellers. It&rsquo;s not easy speaking in front of a large audience let alone
<a href="/2010/12/how-to-tell-good-stories/">captivating them with a great story</a> without notes.</p>

<p>I often download their latest podcast on Sunday morning and listen to it while biking or jogging.
The Moth makes their podcast free and sometimes has an ad at the end of the podcast. Usually the
ad is for a product or brand that makes sense with The Moth&rsquo;s branding and demographic. I envision
that demographic to be highly educated urbanites ages 30 to 50 who are married and listen to NPR
and skew liberal.</p>

<p>So I was surprised to hear an ad for Voss water in the last two Moth podcasts. Here at 15:08</p>

<p>{% audio <a href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-195-adam-gopnik.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/moth-podcast-195-adam-gopnik.mp3</a> %}</p>

<p>and here at 17:30.</p>

<p>{% audio <a href="http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/the-moth-podcast-194-david-chang.mp3">http://cdn.themoth.prx.org/the-moth-podcast-194-david-chang.mp3</a> %}</p>

<p>These ads are read by the host Dan Kennedy and include a reason why Moth listeners should buy the
product or subscribe to the brand.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the script for the Voss ad:</p>

<blockquote><p>Voss is the perfect pairing for your special dining moments. A night worth talking about always
  starts with Voss on the table because with Voss comes great conversation. And with a great
  conversation comes a story worth sharing.</p></blockquote>

<p>Am I hearing this right? If I drink bottled water I&rsquo;ll have better conversations and be a rockstar
conversationalist?</p>

<p>Is this brand mismatch? The Moth is a non-profit organization where people share stories. Voss is
a luxury lifestyle product in the form of bottled water. They call it <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artesian_water">artesian water</a> which is
simply water from an aquifer that&rsquo;s under positive pressure. What&rsquo;s so great about that? And even
if this kind of water were all that, there have been allegations that Voss water is really just
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voss_(water)#cite_note-3">tap water</a> in a sleek glass bottle.</p>

<p>But there is a silver lining. Voss has a <a href="http://www.thevossfoundation.org/about/">foundation</a> that helps people in Sub-Saharan Africa
get access to clean drinking water. In 2010 the Voss Foundation
<a href="http://www.thevossfoundation.org/assets/Voss-Foundation-2010-Year-in-Review.pdf">spent $137,346 toward its cause</a>. It seems like a drop in the bucket in solving
<a href="http://www.cfr.org/africa/water-stress-sub-saharan-africa/p11240">Sub-Saharan Africa&rsquo;s water problems</a>, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing.</p>

<p>I think of the situation as a bunch of people buying fancy bottles and transferring their wealth
to a company good at marketing. This company then gives a portion (I have no idea what percentage
because Voss seems to be a private company with no public financial statements) to helping people
who have a hard time finding potable water.</p>

<p><em>Update: Since writing this post The Moth has not had anymore Voss ads in their podcasts. Yay.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Timeline Bogus, Andy Sparks Would Never Post Picture of That Mullet]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/facebook-timeline-bogus-andy-sparks-would-never-post-picture-of-that-mullet/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/facebook-timeline-bogus-andy-sparks-would-never-post-picture-of-that-mullet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook timeline is bogus. There&rsquo;s no way Andy Sparks could&rsquo;ve gotten a girlfriend with that mullet.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-ZnGKlByC9cI/TnwKjxX8wLI/AAAAAAAABCo/tvwqUB4W-Ss/s640/fb-sparks-mullet.jpg" title="Andy Sparks Mullet is Chick Repellent" alt="Andy Sparks Mullet is Chick Repellent" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
