<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: New York City | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/new-york-city/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-18T10:02:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Test Your Home's Water for Lead]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2017/02/how-to-test-your-homes-water-for-lead/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-20T19:37:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2017/02/how-to-test-your-homes-water-for-lead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read the <em>New York Times</em> article <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/03/24/nyregion/how-nyc-gets-its-water-new-york-101.html">&ldquo;How New York Gets Its Water&rdquo;</a> a while ago. The end of the
article described how you could order a free lead testing kit.</p>

<blockquote><p>The <a href="https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2015-11/documents/2005_09_14_faq_fs_homewatertesting.pdf">EPA offers some guidance</a> on how and when to obtain an in-home testing kit through your local
water supplier. In New York City, residents can obtain one <a href="http://www1.nyc.gov/nyc-resources/service/1266/water-lead-test-kit-request">at no cost through 311</a>.</p>

<p>For more information, visit <a href="www.epa.gov/safewater/lead">www.epa.gov/safewater/lead</a>, or call the Safe Drinking Water Hotline
at 1-800-426-4791.</p></blockquote>

<p>I read this article in the aftermath of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flint_water_crisis">Flint water crisis</a> and wanted to test my
apartment&rsquo;s drinking water. I filled out the online form, received a package in the mail containing
two large plastic bottles, a pre-paid mailing label, and detailed instructions. The instructions
said to fill one bottle with water after not using any faucet in my apartment for six hours. I
filled the second bottle with water after having run the tap. After dropping the bottles now full
of water into a mailbox, NYC&rsquo;s Nureau of Water Supply sent me the results only week or so later.</p>

<blockquote><p>We have received the results of your recent tap water lead test. Both samples were under the
federal action level of 15 micrograms per liter (μg/L). Your specific results were:</p>

<p>First draw: 0 μg/L
1-2 minute flush: 0 μg/L</p></blockquote>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/uxwBi0bl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/uxwBi0bl.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/98MoXGNl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/98MoXGNl.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Sailing Class]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-sailing-class/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-24T13:37:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/07/my-first-sailing-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend a bunch of Spotify collleagues and I took our first sailing classes at Manhattan Yacht
Club in Jersey City. I could get used to this sport. The sun was brutal though. I&rsquo;ll never get used
to that.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8hPEr4sa-YM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/g6jwSpXl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/g6jwSpXl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221;></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/rbyvOtml.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/rbyvOtml.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221; title=&#8221;I had to wear a hot and stuffy life vest on a 90-degree day.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>I had to wear a hot and stuffy life vest on a 90-degree day.</div></div></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/5cHxUtKl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/5cHxUtKl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221; title=&#8221;A great view of lower Manhattan.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>A great view of lower Manhattan.</div></div></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://i.imgur.com/ivnVCYXl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/ivnVCYXl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;480&#8221; height=&#8221;640&#8221; title=&#8221;Sailing close to the Statue of Liberty.&#8221; ><div class='caption'>Sailing close to the Statue of Liberty.</div></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My QCon NYC 2016 Slides - Reach Production Faster With Containers in Testing]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-20T17:15:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are the slides from my <a href="https://qconnewyork.com/ny2016/presentation/reaching-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing">QCon NYC 2016 talk titled &ldquo;Reach Production Faster with Containers in
Testing.&rdquo;</a> in various formats. <span xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" property="dct:title">All formats of &ldquo;Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing&rdquo;</span> by <a xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/ns#" href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/my-qcon-nyc-2016-slides-reach-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing/" property="cc:attributionName" rel="cc:attributionURL">David Xia</a> are licensed under a <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</a>.</p>

<iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/p1uEfRmocwplbk" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen> </iframe>


<p> <div style="margin-bottom:5px"> <strong> <a href="//www.slideshare.net/DavidXia/qcon-nyc-2016-reach-production-faster-with-containers-in-testing" title="QCon NYC 2016: Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing" target="_blank">QCon NYC 2016: Reach Production Faster with Containers in Testing</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="//www.slideshare.net/DavidXia" target="_blank">David Xia</a></strong> </div></p>

<p>More formats here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkSloyT3gxalRuYjQ/view?usp=sharing">PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkSm9BVW5uWFR5TFk/view?usp=sharing">Keynote</a></li>
<li><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0By_v8MtsRMKkRkpQWk5paUZOUW8/view?usp=sharing">PowerPoint</a></li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://i.imgur.com/w0P47Ugl.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/w0P47Ugl.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;619&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confessions of a Noob Landlord IV - How to Buy a Co-op Unit]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-15T06:57:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/06/confessions-of-a-noob-landlord-iv-how-to-buy-a-co-op-unit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a story of I jumped through countless complex bureaucratic, legal, and financial hurdles of
Murphy&rsquo;s Law and emerged with less liquidity and more debt. OK. I&rsquo;m being facetious, but what
happened to me is the easiest and most straightforward way to buy a property. Seriously.
The events below transpired in New York City. The buying process may be different in other areas,
but the most of the process such as contract of sale and mortgage application is the same across
the U.S.</em></p>

<p><div class='image center <a'><img  src="href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG">https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8d/Cary_Grant_Myrna_Loy_Mr_Blandings_Builds_His_Dream_House_1948.JPG</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;640&#8221; height=&#8221;772&#8221; title=&#8221;By RKO radio pictures (eBay item photo front photo back) [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons. Promotional photo of Cary Grant and Myrna Loy for the film Mr. Blandings Builds His Dream House (1948)&#8221; ><div class='caption'>By RKO radio pictures (eBay item photo front photo back) [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons. Promotional photo of Cary Grant and Myrna Loy for the film Mr. Blandings Builds His Dream House (1948)</div></div></p>

<ul>
<li>My mother found an affordable co-op unit for sale while browsing StreetEasy on her iPad
during Christmas vacation in 2015.</li>
<li>We noticed the listing was made by the seller himself. I emailed him that night.</li>
<li>The seller promptly called me. I scheduled a viewing of the unit which is at the top
of a six-floor walk-up.</li>
<li>My parents and I climbed the six flights of stairs and met the seller who was a nice man named
Alan. We walked around and inspected his unit.</li>
<li>We asked Alan about the apartment&rsquo;s condition, the co-op&rsquo;s financials and rules, the property
manager, etc.</li>
<li>We sat down with Alan, chatted, and negotiated. My mother pointed out neither party has a broker
which is good because brokers take a 6% commission. We felt out Alan on how many offers he&rsquo;s
received and what they are.</li>
<li>My mother verbally offered Alan 94% of the listing price. He said he&rsquo;ll see. My mom seemed
confident he&rsquo;d take it. I was impressed by her ability to knock off over $20K right off the bat.</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>My parents and I started looking for a mortgage broker and an attorney who&rsquo;s good with co-op
purchases. (They were professional and competent. Contact me if you want a referral.)</li>
<li>We decided how much money we wanted to borrow and how long. I settled on a 15-year mortgage at a
great interest rate of 2.875%. I minimized closing and discount points in order to pay less money
up front.</li>
<li>My mortgage broker Deborah started collecting relevant documents from me to start the mortgage
approval process. These include but aren&rsquo;t limited to bank statements, pay stubs (W2), federal
income tax returns (1040). I didn&rsquo;t have to use a mortgage broker and could&rsquo;ve shopped around
myself simply by applying online at various commercial banks&#8217; websites. But I&rsquo;m pretty busy,
and the broker&rsquo;s fee would be paid by the lender in my case.</li>
<li>Alan accepted our verbal offer and sent over a contract of sale. This document is a major
checkpoint. It stated what, when, and how we would exchange property and money. Once I signed it
and included a contract deposit (10% of the purchase price), it meant Alan and I were in a
legally binding agreement and that he wasn&rsquo;t considering any other offers.

<ul>
<li>If I reneged, Alan could keep my contract deposit.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not sure what legal recourse or damages I could pursue if Alan reneged. The contract
vaguely stated:

<blockquote><p>In the event of a default or misrepresentation by Seller, Purchaser shall have such remedies
as Purchaser is entitled to at law or in equity, including specific performance, because
the Unit and possession thereof cannot be duplicated.</p></blockquote></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Our respective attorneys went back and forth modifying the contract of sale with riders that
protected each of us, respectively. For example, my attorney Andrew added a clause stipulating
the wall Alan built to divide the bedroom into two bedrooms was approved by the co-op board and
I would get a written approval letter at closing. Alan&rsquo;s attorney Michael added a clause stating
I couldn&rsquo;t back out of the sale if the maintenance increased after I&rsquo;d signed the contract.</li>
<li>I signed the contract on January 25, 2016. And I expected a counter-signed copy back shortly.</li>
<li>So I waited.</li>
<li>And waited.</li>
<li>And waited&hellip;</li>
<li>It seems that the more sellers there are on the contract, the more likely it there are to be
issues. In my case, there were a total of three sellers. Two of them were individuals:
Alan and his ex-wife. The third seller was the estate of Alan&rsquo;s deceased father. This estate
had two executors: Alan and his sister.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re not confused yet, you will be.</li>
<li>Alan told me his ex-wife wasn&rsquo;t being cooperative with the sale but that a court order would
help convince her as a last resort.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, my mortgage broker Deborah was busy securing a lender for me. I also needed to have
the unit appraised which depended on the contract being fully signed.</li>
<li>On February 4, Deborah tells me the co-op has an insurance policy that&rsquo;s shared with other
buildings. She said most lenders won&rsquo;t underwrite a mortgage in a building with a pooled policy.
She said she&rsquo;ll try other lenders.</li>
<li>After an entire month (March 5 to be precise), Alan successfully compelled his ex-wife to sign
with the issuance of a court order. This allowed me to schedule the appraisal.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, I still hadn&rsquo;t secured the mortgage. Guaranteed Rate, Citi, Chase, Wells and various
portfolio lenders all refused. With each lender that turned me down because of
the co-op insurance policy, the more likely it seemed that Deborah and I would have to somehow
convince the co-op board to buy a new individual policy. The property management company would
also have to complete lots of paperwork. I&rsquo;ve never met the board, and the management company
seemed like a tangled bureaucracy. I was seriously questioning how I&rsquo;d be able to pull this off.</li>
<li><em>To be continued&hellip;</em></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Always Feels Good to Return to New York City]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/it-always-feels-good-to-return-to-new-york-city/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-04T17:41:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2016/04/it-always-feels-good-to-return-to-new-york-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sunday March 27 was my first day back in New York City after vacationing in the UK for ten days.
I stepped into a subway car and noticed
everyone was crowded around the entrance so I pushed my way into the less populated mid-section.
I soon realized why people were avoiding that area. A skinny, middle-aged man was trying to get the
attention of two young women sitting next to him. I don&rsquo;t remember what he was saying, but it was
obvious they felt uncomfortable and didn&rsquo;t want to talk. After they got off, he looked around and
asked,</p>

<p>&ldquo;What is going on? Why are all the women standing?</p>

<p>&ldquo;I crashed my jaguar. Now look at my knees. This one&rsquo;s bigger than that one. But I still get up to
give the women a seat. No woman should be on her feet. A man that hits his woman ain&rsquo;t worth shit.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Most people were trying their best to ignore him. I couldn&rsquo;t help but laugh a bit. He then tried
to strike up a conversation with some other men around him. I missed the beginning but was able
to overhear this:</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ll kill them. I&rsquo;ll do it for nothing. I don&rsquo;t want you to pay $100,000 for your daughter to go
to Harvard and then get raped by a rich motherfucker. I hate rapists and pedophiles so I&rsquo;ll do it
for free!&rdquo;</p>

<p>I got off at my stop and started reading the <em>New York Times</em> on my phone.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Donald J. Trump and Senator Ted Cruz of Texas traded insults on Easter Sunday morning over recent
smears against their wives, while Mr. Trump ruled out creating internment camps for American
Muslims and said he would study a proposal to allow delegates to bring guns to the Republican
National Convention.</p><footer><strong>New York Times <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2016/03/27/donald-trump-and-ted-cruz-continue-clash-over-spouses/">http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2016/03/27/donald-trump-and-ted-cruz-continue-clash-over-spouses/</a></strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Ah, it&rsquo;s good to be back.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
