<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Economy | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/economy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-10-20T17:35:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Foster Wallace on American Consumer Culture]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/03/david-foster-wallace-on-american-consumer-culture/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/03/david-foster-wallace-on-american-consumer-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently watched some interviews of David Foster Wallace. It&rsquo;s fascinating to hear him speak.
He&rsquo;s a deeply intelligent, neurotic, and sentimental man.</p>

<p>My favorite parts are when DFW talks about American consumer culture. He describes the US as
&ldquo;<a href="http://youtu.be/AlUmT_biDwI?t=1m30s">one enormous engine and temple of self-gratification</a>,&rdquo; which works very well in growing the
economy but doesn&rsquo;t nourish other parts of people.</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://youtu.be/AlUmT_biDwI?t=7m36s" title="David Foster Wallace's quote on mixed messages for American youth">For young people in America</a>, there are very mixed messages from the culture. There&rsquo;s a
  streak of moralism in American life that extols the virtues of being grown up and having a family
  and being a responsible citizen. But there&rsquo;s also the sense of do what you want, gratify your
  appetite because when I&rsquo;m a corporation, appealing to the parts of you that are selfish and
  self-centered and want to have fun all the time, is the best way to sell you things&hellip;[This is one
  more example of] the American economic and cultural systems that work very well in terms of
  selling people products and keeping the economy thriving do not work as well when it comes to
  educating children or helping us help each other know how to live and to be happy.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light a Fire Under Politicians' Asses]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/light-a-fire-under-politicians-asses/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/10/light-a-fire-under-politicians-asses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The inner populist in me is heartened to see the Occupy Wall Street movement grow and even
<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/16/world/occupy-wall-street-protests-worldwide.html?hp">spread to other countries</a>. It&rsquo;s about time the penny-wise-pound-foolish policies of careerist
politicians and hamstrung governments came back to bite them in the ass.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I want to see the Occupy Wall Street movement not only gain more steam but also to become more
organized and remain vigilantly peaceful. Right now I&rsquo;m not sure what it stands for besides
general malaise. The movement is not a response to the financial crisis or Wall Street barons as
supporters might say. If Wall Street made boatloads of money and Main Street also enjoyed low
unemployment and decent salaries, this movement wouldn&rsquo;t exist. That&rsquo;s why no one occupied Wall
Street in 2008 right after the crash.</p>

<p>Instead, it took three years of high unemployment and falling wages and <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/16/realestate/rents-in-manhattan-rebound-to-record-highs.html">rising rents</a> to
slowly generate this movement. Occupy Wall Street supporters are demonstrating more against the
political elite not the financial elite. It&rsquo;s the political elite who didn&rsquo;t fix things afterward
the financial elite fucked up. Now the commoners are thinking &ldquo;wait, if the people in charge are
incompetent, what gives them the right to rule?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s some insightful analysis by George Friedman of Stratfor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Privileged and Precarious Life]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/my-privileged-and-precarious-life/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/my-privileged-and-precarious-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m always painfully aware of how privileged my life is. I grew up in New England&rsquo;s affluent
suburbs as part of the upper middle class. I attended college at Columbia University with generous
financial aid. And now I&rsquo;m working in one of the few industries that&rsquo;s aggressively hiring in a
job position that&rsquo;s seeing growth. There&rsquo;s a stark contrast between my situation and those less
fortunate around me. New York City&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.labor.ny.gov/stats/pressreleases/pruistat.shtm">current unemployment rate of 8%</a> remains unchanged since
a year ago. U.S. <a href="http://www.google.com/publicdata/explore?ds=z1ebjpgk2654c1_&amp;met_y=unemployment_rate&amp;tdim=true&amp;fdim_y=seasonality:S&amp;dl=en&amp;hl=en&amp;q=national%20unemployment%20rate#ctype=l&amp;strail=false&amp;nselm=h&amp;met_y=unemployment_rate&amp;fdim_y=seasonality:S&amp;scale_y=lin&amp;ind_y=false&amp;rdim=state&amp;ifdim=state&amp;tdim=true&amp;hl=en&amp;dl=en">unemployment is 9.1%</a>.</p>

<p>Right now there&rsquo;s so much more demand for technical talent than supply of it that I wish I could
wave a magic wand and turn
<a href="http://www.census.gov/compendia/statab/2011/tables/11s0624.pdf">idle construction workers, durable goods manufacturers, and fishermen</a> into
<a href="http://railsforzombies.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> developers.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Although my life is privileged, I&rsquo;m afraid it&rsquo;s precarious. The basic human necessities for
survival are water, food, shelter, and (depending upon climate) clothing. I can create a website
and scrape data, but at the end of the day I can&rsquo;t eat my Ubuntu virtual or code a web app to
generate potable water. Although I can create a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linked_list">linked list in C</a>, if I&rsquo;m left by myself in
the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Side_of_the_Mountain">Catskill mountains</a> or the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_House_on_the_Prairie#Story">frontiers of society</a>, I doubt I&rsquo;d come out like Sam
Gribley or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laura_Ingalls_Wilder">Laura Ingalls Wilder</a>.</p>

<p>I often think of what I&rsquo;d do in a catastrophic scenario. A day after my friend said I was silly
for worrying about doomsday scenarios, I wake up to hear Mayor Bloomberg
<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/08/27/nyregion/new-york-city-begins-evacuations-before-hurricane.html?_r=1&amp;hp">ordering the evacuation</a> of the city&rsquo;s coastal areas and shutting down the transit system. We
also quickly forget major crises as soon as they pass.</p>

<p>These are only some of the recent natural disasters.</p>

<ul>
<li>July-August 2010. Floods triggered by heavier-than-normal monsoon rains hit northwest Pakistan.
By the time the waters began to recede in late August, more than 160,000 square kilometres of land
— about one-fifth of the country — was under water. More than 1,700 people were killed and 17.2
million people have been affected.</li>
<li>Jan. 12, 2010. A 7.0-magnitude earthquake in Haiti killed over 230,000 people.</li>
<li>May 12, 2008. A 7.9-magnitude earthquake in Sichuan, China killed over 70,000 people.</li>
<li>May 3, 2008. Cyclone Nargis, swept along by winds that exceeded 190 kmh and waves six metres
high struck the Burmese peninsula and may have left as many as 100,000 dead, according to U.S.
estimates.</li>
<li>Oct. 8, 2005. A 7.6-magnitude earthquake in Kashmir, Pakistan killed at least 80,000 people and
left three million homeless.</li>
<li>Dec. 26, 2004. A 9.0-magnitude quake off the coast of Sumatra triggered tsunamis that swept
through the coastal regions of a dozen countries bordering the Indian Ocean. The death toll has
been estimated at between 225,000 and 275,000.</li>
</ul>


<p>And let&rsquo;s not forget about the disasters we humans create ourselves: crime, terrorism, war,
financial crises, pollution, etc.</p>

<p>The food I eat and the goods I buy come from a sprawling yet fragile industrialized system. My
Macbook Air I&rsquo;m typing on is made from many components from many companies. I don&rsquo;t know how to
draw water from a well, how to slaughter a chicken, or do subsistence farming. My atavistic side
feels neglected. Of course, these are skills that won&rsquo;t benefit me as a service worker in this
post-industrial age, but I feel exposed and vulnerable. I live off the top of so many other layers
of civilization that make everything run smoothly, provide my Macbook Air electricity, and deliver
food to my local grocery stores. The more complex and specialized society becomes, the energy is
required to maintain it. Just look at America&rsquo;s decaying infrastructure. I see it everyday when I
take New York&rsquo;s crowded and creaking subway, when I try to avoid all the potholes in Manhattan
streets.</p>

<p>A really scary documentary I watched is <em>Collapse</em>. It&rsquo;s an 82-minute monologue with Michael
Ruppert, ex-LA cop and investigative reporter. Supporters think he&rsquo;s a visionary and radical
thinker. Critics call him a conspiracy theorist and an alarmist.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WAyHIOg5aHk?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<blockquote><p>The key to understanding infrastructure lies at the heart of complex civilizations. When roads
  and bridges fail; levees aren&rsquo;t rebuilt; when dams, transmission lines and generating stations are
  not maintained; when any of a hundred possible things fail for lack of money or
  material&hellip;civilization starts to break down. – Michael Ruppert</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make Money When the Market Tanks]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/how-to-make-money-when-market-tanks/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/how-to-make-money-when-market-tanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday morning I bet over 95% of my 401k savings into a 3x leveraged inverse ETF based on mid
cap companies (<a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=smdd">UltraPro Short Mid Cap 400 – SMDD</a>). And then I <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/Easily__Amused/status/98844234798473216">tweeted</a>,</p>

<blockquote><p>I Hope the Economy Tanks Because I Just Bought a 3x Leveraged Inverse ETF</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p>Today the market dropped over 4% in its biggest percentage drop since February 2009. But I also
open my portfolio to see this:</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-dhB3R7N3iMY/TjsU7kFdccI/AAAAAAAAA9c/3wbKhyfpkrs/s800/Screen%252520shot%2525202011-08-04%252520at%2525205.22.29%252520PM.png">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-dhB3R7N3iMY/TjsU7kFdccI/AAAAAAAAA9c/3wbKhyfpkrs/s800/Screen%252520shot%2525202011-08-04%252520at%2525205.22.29%252520PM.png</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;430&#8221; height=&#8221;398&#8221;></p>

<p>I hedged my long positions in equity and made off with a bit extra.</p>

<p>Now another funny picture. My blog post showed up in Google finance.</p>

<p><img class="caption <a" src="href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-rMdp1mbkktM/TjsV9Knz3nI/AAAAAAAAA9s/sBGw-gR7Yv0/s640/Screen%252520shot%2525202011-08-04%252520at%25252011.18.16%252520AM.png">https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-rMdp1mbkktM/TjsV9Knz3nI/AAAAAAAAA9s/sBGw-gR7Yv0/s640/Screen%252520shot%2525202011-08-04%252520at%25252011.18.16%252520AM.png</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;540&#8221; height=&#8221;308&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Individualism to Collectivism, the American Nowadays]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/from-individualism-to-collectivism-the-american-nowadays/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/from-individualism-to-collectivism-the-american-nowadays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>An essay I wrote for United States history class in my junior year of high school. My prose can
definitely be tightened, but the kernel of my idea is still intriguing.</em></p>

<p>David Xia<br/>
AP2 US<br/>
Jan. 11, &lsquo;05</p>

<p><strong>From Individualism to Collectivism: The American Nowadays</strong></p>

<p>Americans have always been proud of their &ldquo;rugged individuality.&rdquo; The roots of this sentiment
originated in the conditions of the establishment of the country. From proclaiming their
independence from England in 1776 to the gradual settling of the Great West, self-autonomy was
trumpeted as the defining characteristic of the American. However, when one now examines the
current trend in society today, the old rugged individualism exemplified by the romanticized
cowboy of the West has disappeared.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The United States from its very origins was indicative of an autonomous people. The emigrants
from Europe were either religious dissenters or the impoverished who were brave enough to set out
for a completely unknown and potentially dangerous new land. By their very nature they were
independent. The settlers of the West paralleled the original colonists in pragmatism and more
importantly in their self-reliance. The cowboys had to ride long distances to drive their cattle
to railroad stations. The &ldquo;Sooners&rdquo; of Oklahoma depended on themselves to secure a favorable
strip of land and then to protect it from other whites and the Native Americans. When the
pioneer&rsquo;s Conestoga wagon broke down he himself had to fix it for there was no one else around to
help him. A common phrase was &ldquo;Good enough&rdquo; out of necessity.</p>

<p>People in America now desire desperately to be part of something greater than themselves: a
collective group made up of many and dedicated to a cause. This cause can be supporting a sports
team. Millions who never had any personal connection with the Boston Red Sox showed up for the
team&rsquo;s belated World Series victory parade. Indeed, even T-shirts were printed declaring &ldquo;Red Sox
Nation.  Not only in the world of sports can one witness such zealous collective groups but also
in schools. &#8220;Raider Pride&rdquo; apparel and the many clubs after school represent the current urge to
be part of a group, which has relegated individualism to a lower status. Instead of the lone
cowboy or maverick or trailblazer who sets out on his own path, almost all Americans belong to
what Kurt Vonnegut calls &ldquo;artificial families. Individuality is now not so much practiced as
enthusiastic loyalty to a greater group.</p>

<p>Another place to look in order to see a dearth of individualism is in the marketplace.
Advertisers who set tones and attitudes for their wares often invoke the sense of independence.
This tactic is used for such merchandise as the Apple iPod, with its blatant white earphone cords
that just shout, &ldquo;Look at me. I&rsquo;m unique because I have an iPod.&#8221; Many car companies also
declare their car gives drivers freedom on the road without constraints, especially in the case of
SUVs. However, when one takes a closer look at the fundamental paradox of the marketers&#8217;
arguments, one can see that this merchandise individualism is but a thin veneer for mass
marketing. How can someone truly be an individual if he buys a product that, although proclaims
will blazon his independence, is targeted and sold to millions of other consumers?  The answer is
that buyers are not concerned with their image, nor are they ignorant that millions of others
share their accessories. American buyers buy objects for the sake of feeling a sense of belonging
to a family of other like-minded buyers.</p>

<p>This &ldquo;be your own person&rdquo; mentality slowly deteriorated as the frontier melted away and was a result of the American citizen realizing that he was not completely unaffected by external events, both national and international.  The frontier forced Americans to be individualists.  No help on the way meant self-help on the spot.  As the West gradually became settled and more and more areas became urbanized, Americans could afford to not be ruggedly independent.  If the plumbing was broken, one called a plumber.  If the car wouldn&rsquo;t start, drop it off at the mechanic.  Then the realization that there were many greater forces besides the annual crop problems also took an effect.  Americans increasingly became aware of their nation&rsquo;s huge role on the world stage.  Terrorism and the economic quagmire of their country forced them to band together in order to champion a cause.  In the last presidential election any common American could have seen the many candidate-based support (or discouragement) organizations such as the notorious Swift-boat Veterans for Truth.</p>

<p>Although rugged individualism has all but disappeared from American society, at least the old cowboy myths and stories of the once daring colonists still live on.  Moreover, these romanticized accounts now gleam brighter than ever when juxtaposed with our current collectivist mentality.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
