<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Writing & Literature | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/writing-and-literature/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-05-26T00:51:59+02:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Slice of My Day - Hugh Jackman, Mother's Day, and Southern Gothic]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2015/05/a-slice-of-my-day-hugh-jackman-mothers-day-and-southern-gothic/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-11T02:45:12+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2015/05/a-slice-of-my-day-hugh-jackman-mothers-day-and-southern-gothic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I saw the trailer for a <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/independent/dukalesdream/" title="Dukale's Dream trailer">new movie</a> that features traveling, fighting poverty, and Hugh Jackman. It
reminded me of Nanette because those are some of her favorite things. It&rsquo;s a movie about how one
white guy saves the Africans. It&rsquo;s in the vein of movies like <em>The Last Samurai</em> starring Tom Cruise,
<em>Dances with Wolves</em> starring Kevin Costner, <em>Avatar</em> starring Sam Worthington, and <em>The Help</em>
starring Emma Stone.</p>

<p>Today was mother&rsquo;s day. Here&rsquo;s an interview between a mother and her adorable seven-year-old
daughter that becomes quite dark for a little bit.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ARsN5MftEA0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>While reading <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0679732241/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0679732241&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkId=2NRE7R3CYLVS5HSV" title="The Sound and the Fury on Amazon"><em>The Sound and the Fury</em></a>, I searched up the definition of &ldquo;Southern Gothic,&rdquo; the
genre in which Faulkner&rsquo;s book belongs.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>{% blockquote_nobr Southern Gothic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Gothic">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Gothic</a> %}
Southern Gothic is a subgenre of Gothic fiction unique to American literature that takes place
exclusively in the American South.</p>

<p>Common themes in Southern Gothic literature include deeply flawed, disturbing or eccentric
characters who may or may not dabble in hoodoo, ambivalent gender roles and decayed or derelict
settings, grotesque situations, and other sinister events relating to or coming from poverty,
alienation, crime, and violence.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>Previously for me, Southern Gothic conjured images of giant, slightly derelict plantations
shrouded by fog and Spanish moss, symbols of a bygone era. In this way, the South seemed forlorn and
slightly romantic in a <em>Gone with the Wind</em> kind of way.</p>

<p>The Wikipedia page goes on to say</p>

<blockquote><h3>Photographic representation</h3>

<p>The images of Great Depression photographer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walker_Evans" title="Wikipedia: Walker Evans">Walker Evans</a> are frequently seen to evoke the visual
depiction of the Southern Gothic, Evans claiming that &ldquo;I can understand why Southerners are
haunted by their own landscape&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Another noted Southern Gothic photographer was surrealist, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clarence_John_Laughlin" title="Wikipedia: Clarence John Laughlin">Clarence John Laughlin</a>, who
photographed plantations, cemeteries, and other abandoned places throughout the South (primarily
Louisiana) for nearly 40 years.</p></blockquote>

<p>So I search for &ldquo;Clarence John Laughlin&rdquo; expecting to find images like this:</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/NGbniaB.png">https://i.imgur.com/NGbniaB.png</a> This is actually a scene from the movie The Lucky One %}</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/wAaoERJl.png">https://i.imgur.com/wAaoERJl.png</a> Gone with the Wind movie poster %}</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/C3qT0mYl.png">https://i.imgur.com/C3qT0mYl.png</a> Gone with the Wind ending scene %}</p>

<p>Instead, I find images like <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0679732241/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0679732241&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkId=2NRE7R3CYLVS5HSV" title="The Sound and the Fury on Amazon">these</a>:</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/nE0WSuZ.jpg">https://i.imgur.com/nE0WSuZ.jpg</a> Clarence John Laughlin photo 1 %}</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/zhNOMgl.png">https://i.imgur.com/zhNOMgl.png</a> Clarence John Laughlin photo 2 %}</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="https://i.imgur.com/YdW0ary.png">https://i.imgur.com/YdW0ary.png</a> Clarence John Laughlin photo 3 %}</p>

<p>Creepy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Read Steve Jobs' Biography]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/why-you-should-read-steve-jobs-biography/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/01/why-you-should-read-steve-jobs-biography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve got 140 pages left to go in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1451648537/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1451648537">Steve Jobs&#8217; biography</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1451648537" alt="" />, and I&rsquo;ve laughed, shuddered,
but most of all, felt inspired by all the pages so far. I can&rsquo;t believe I didn&rsquo;t know more about
Jobs&#8217; personal background; the creation, near death, and triumphant rise of Apple; or the myriad
other people in the tech world that were related to Jobs&#8217; life.</p>

<p>Isaacson writes with clarity and detail. The anecdotes are numerous and often funny. The portrait
Isaacson paints of Jobs has inspired, scared, and taught me a lot. I admire Jobs&#8217; passion for life
and creation; I&rsquo;m repulsed by his streaks of cruelty. Because of and despite of his character
strengths and flaws, he left a lasting legacy. The biography&rsquo;s author Walter Isaacson put it this
way:</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>The Apple II, which took Wozniak&rsquo;s circuit board and turned it into the first personal computer
that was not just for hobbyists.</li>
<li>The Macintosh, which begat the home computer revolution and popularized graphical user interfaces.</li>
<li><em>Toy Story</em> and other Pixar blockbusters, which opened up the miracle of digital imagination.</li>
<li>Apple stores, which reinvented the role of a store in defining a brand.</li>
<li>The iPod, which changed the way we consume music.</li>
<li>The iTunes Store, which saved the music industry.</li>
<li>The iPhone which turned mobile phones into music, photography, video, email, and web devices.</li>
<li>The App store, which spawned a new content-creation industry.</li>
<li>The iPad, which launched tablet computing and offered a platform for digital newspapers,
magazines, books, and videos.</li>
<li>iCloud, which demoted the computer from its central role in managing our content and let all of
our devices sync seamlessly.</li>
<li>And Apple itself, which Jobs considered his greatest creation, a place where imagination was
nurtured, applied, and executed in ways so creative that it became the most valuable company on
earth.</li>
</ul>


<p>Anyone who owns an Apple product, from occasional iPod users to the most hard-core cult-of-Apple
fanboys, should crack open this book.</p>

<p>Here are some of my favorite excerpts:</p>

<h3>Product design simplicity</h3>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Jonathan Ive page 343, Steve Jobs %}
Why do we assume that simple is good? Because with physical products, we have to feel we can
dominate them. As you bring order to complexity, you find a way to make the product defer to you.
Simplicity isn&rsquo;t just a visual style. It&rsquo;s not just minimalism or the absence of clutter. It
involves digging through the depth of the complexity. To be truly simple, you have to go really
deep. For example, to have no screws on something, you can end up having a product that is so
convoluted and so complex. The better way is to go deeper with the simplicity, to understand
everything about it and how it&rsquo;s manufactured. You have to deeply understand the essence of a
product in order to be able to get rid of the parts that are not essential.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<h3>Jobs obsessing over the color of the iMac in a print ad</h3>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Walter Isaacson, Steve Jobs %}
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Clow">Lee Clow</a> was preparing a series of colorful magazine ads, and when he sent Jobs the page
proofs he got an outraged phone call in response. The blue in the ad, Jobs insisted, was different
from that of the iMac. &ldquo;You guys don&rsquo;t know what you&rsquo;re doing!&rdquo; Jobs shouted. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m going to get
someone else to do the ads, because this is fucked up.&rdquo; Clow argued back. Compare them, he said.
Jobs, who was not in the office, insisted he was right and continued to shout. Eventually Clow got
him to sit down with the original photographs. &ldquo;I finally proved to him that the blue was the blue
was the blue.&rdquo; Years later, on a Steve Jobs discussion board on the website Gawker, the following
tale appeared from someone who had worked at the Whole Foods store in Palo Alto a few blocks from
Jobs&rsquo;s home: &ldquo;I was shagging carts one afternoon when I saw this silver Mercedes parked in a
handicapped spot. Steve Jobs was inside screaming at his car phone. This was right before the
first iMac was unveiled and I&rsquo;m pretty sure I could make out, &lsquo;Not. Fucking. Blue. Enough!!!&rsquo;&rdquo;
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<h3>Apple stores</h3>

<p>{% blockquote_nobr Walter Isaacson, Steve Jobs %}
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ron_Johnson_(businessman)">[Ron] Johnson</a> said that the size of a store signaled the importance of the brand. &ldquo;Is Apple
as big of a brand as the Gap? he asked. Jobs said it was much bigger. Johnson replied that its
stores should therefore be bigger. &#8220;Otherwise you won&rsquo;t be relevant.&rdquo; Jobs described Mike
Markkula&rsquo;s maxim that a good company must &ldquo;impute&rdquo; – it must convey its values and importance in
everything it does, from packaging to marketing. Johnson loved it. It definitely applied to a
company&rsquo;s stores. &ldquo;The store will become the most powerful physical expression of the band,&rdquo; he
predicted.
{% endblockquote_nobr %}</p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;ll read more biographies. Who needs fictional characters when you&rsquo;ve got real ones like
Jobs?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Zubrin's "the Significance of the Martian Frontier"]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/robert-zubrins-the-significance-of-the-martian-frontier/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/robert-zubrins-the-significance-of-the-martian-frontier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Zubrin">Robert Zubrin</a>, an American aerospace engineer and author, wrote the essay
<a href="http://www.nss.org/settlement/mars/zubrin-frontier.html">The Significance of the Martian Frontier</a>. He argues that the technological and cultural
advancements of &ldquo;Western humanist civilization&rdquo; were the result of a frontier – a wild and unknown
territory of vast resources. The Greeks had the Mediterranean. The United States had the American
West (never mind that the Native Americans were here long before).</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Zubrin argues for the need of a new frontier, namely Mars. He cites <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frederick_Jackson_Turner">Frederick Jackson
Turner</a>&rsquo;s essay &ldquo;<a href="http://www.gutenberg.org/files/22994/22994-h/22994-h.htm">The Significance of the Frontier in American History</a>&rdquo; and uses it to
argue that human civilization will decline and turn to mush if we find another frontier soon.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s an inspirational essay, and although it smacks a bit of social Darwinism and white man&rsquo;s
burden, is well worth the read. Reminds me of an <a href="/2011/05/from-individualism-to-collectivism-the-american-nowadays/">essay I wrote in high school</a> about how
Americans have lost their rugged individualism.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s sad that Zubrin probably won&rsquo;t see his dream of Martian colonization fulfilled within his
lifetime. He seems like a baller guy. He&rsquo;s accomplished a lot such as inventing the concept of a
nuclear salt-water rocket, a nuclear thermal rocket powered by plutonium or uranium dissolved in
water. He&rsquo;s written a ton of books on the case of Martian expansion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wisdom of Traditional Cuisines]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/the-wisdom-of-traditional-cuisines/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/the-wisdom-of-traditional-cuisines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading Michael Pollan&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143038583/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=0143038583"><em>The Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0143038583&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369" alt="" />, I learned how much wisdom
traditional cuisines embodied and that certain foods are eaten together not only because they
taste good but because there are health benefits.</p>

<p>The Japanese eat raw fish, which can contain bacteria, with wasabi, a potent anti-microbial.
Strong spices of cuisines originating from tropical areas have antibacterial properties because
food is likely to spoil in hot temperatures. Asian cuisine often combines soy ingredients with
rice because this makes these foods more nutritious than when eaten alone.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Many Meso-American dishes are prepared by cooking corn with lime and eating it with beans. Cooking
corn with an alkali such as lime, allows its <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niacin">niacin</a>, an essential human nutrient, to be
absorbed by our bodies. If you didn&rsquo;t eat niacin, your skin would peel off, you&rsquo;d become
paralyzed, and you&rsquo;d slowly go crazy. It&rsquo;s called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pellagra">pellagra</a>. So corn and niacin are good
stuff, but you&rsquo;d still lack a complete set of essential amino acids. That&rsquo;s where the beans come
in. Corn and beans lack essential amino acids lysine and methionine, respectively, and by eating
both you&rsquo;re good to go.</p>

<p>So skip the Jenny Craig, South Beach, Atkins diet. Eat traditional cuisine. Would you rather trust
millennia of passed down knowledge or Jenny Craig and some American cardiologists?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Gettysburg Address as Given by Holden Caulfield]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/12/the-gettysburg-address-as-given-by-holden-caulfield/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/12/the-gettysburg-address-as-given-by-holden-caulfield</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I wrote this speech on October 27, 2004 for my Advanced Placement United States history class.
It&rsquo;s how I imagined the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gettysburg_Address">Gettysburg Address</a>&rdquo; woud&rsquo;ve sounded if Holden Caulfield from
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316769177?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0316769177">The Catcher in the Rye</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0316769177" alt="" /> were delivering it.</em></p>

<p>A long time ago, when I wasn&rsquo;t born yet, our nation was created. I think it was in 1776. I could
be wrong. I was never really good in history and all. There was this one time when Mr. Spencer was
my history teacher, and I had to write an essay on the Egyptians. Boy, you should have seen how
bad my essay was. I even wrote to Mr. Spencer at the end of the essay that it was fine if he
wanted to flunk me. But he just invites me over to his house and tells me he&rsquo;s worried and asks me
about what I&rsquo;m planning to do later in my life. That talk got me thinking. It really did.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Anyway, I think our country was founded in 1776. I&rsquo;m not good with dates and all, but I know that
America was meant to be based on liberty and equality. But the founding fathers never gave liberty
and equality to the slaves. You&rsquo;ve probably heard about this. I don&rsquo;t see how giving equality to
the whites and not giving it to the blacks is fair. What a bunch of phonies.</p>

<p>All of a sudden, we&rsquo;re in this goddam civil war. I think this big war will decide whether our
nation can go on keeping the standards of liberty and equality. If our side loses, the South will
never be united with the North. It&rsquo;ll mean that our big effort at creating such a great state with
liberty and equality will fail. And it was them in the South who started the war by leaving and
firing on Fort Sumter. What a bunch of princes. And that Jefferson Davis and Robert Lee are the
biggest morons you ever saw because they&rsquo;re at the head of it all.</p>

<p>So, after this huge Gettysburg battle, I think we should use this area as a cemetery for all the
soldiers who died here. The people who died here deserve this place. What really knocks me out is
that many of the people went on charges knowing they&rsquo;d get shot. But they still charged the enemy
and gave up their lives, hoping that they could keep our nation united. This is why we should give
them a resting place. There was this one time, when I was at one of those private schools filled
with some of the biggest morons you ever saw. The school was Pencey Prep. There was this one kid
called Ackley. One day he got into a fight with those princes and ended up jumping out the window
and getting killed. I felt bad for him. I really did. I don&rsquo;t even know where <em>he&rsquo;s</em> resting today.</p>

<p>Anyway, we can&rsquo;t memorialize this cemetery more than those soldiers already have. These soldiers&#8217;
noble actions will always honor their graves and all. I wish that I can pay just as much tribute
to this cemetery as these dead men have. But I&rsquo;ll probably never come close to them. If everybody
forgets what I&rsquo;m saying here right now, they won&rsquo;t forget what these brave men did here. They
really won&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>So, after all that our men gave up here, we should try to finish what they started. These soldiers
were people who didn&rsquo;t chuck the crap around, and they did what they knew they had to. They
weren&rsquo;t phonies who said one thing and then, before you know it, did another.  My brother&rsquo;s name
is D.B. You&rsquo;ve probably heard of him. He was a much better writer than me, but he wasn&rsquo;t like
these fighters. Boy, you wouldn&rsquo;t believe it, but he went to Hollywood and just sold himself away
to the movies. <em>He</em> was a phony. Anyway, we should keep fighting this war and win it in order to
complete the mission these men died for.</p>

<p>I had a little brother, too. You&rsquo;ve probably heard of him. His name was Allie. He was my favorite,
but he died of leukemia when he was very young. His death killed me. It really did. His death
wasn&rsquo;t vain. He taught me to stay genuine and true to myself, to not be a phony. I hope that these
soldiers did not die here for nothing. At least they meant for us to continue our nation and not
let it fragment and all. With our determination we can keep not just this democratic government
but all the other ones working. At the beginning of the war, I really didn&rsquo;t think all the lives
were worth it. But then I saw what was at stake. And I became devoted to winning this. I really
did. These soldiers fought for a rebirth and re-emergence of our nation as one that is united.
What really knocks me out is that not only was their mission to reinvigorate our country and give
it a new beginning as a unified nation, but that it was also to give more liberty and equality to
our people. If we win, the small portion of freedom that we started with will widen and grow to
include not just whites but also blacks. These soldiers were men who when you&rsquo;re done reading
about their heroic actions, you wish that you could just call them up and ask them about what they
felt and what motivated them to fight. They weren&rsquo;t phonies. They really weren&rsquo;t.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
