<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chinese Culture | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/chinese-culture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-04-21T00:40:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making History]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2012/02/making-history/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2012/02/making-history</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Final paper submission on December 12, 2009 for Columbia University&rsquo;s Nonfiction Workshop class.</em></p>

<p>China has a long history of forgetting its past. When intellectuals criticized the first emperor
in 213 BCE for burning classical books that could undermine his rule, he buried them alive. Two
millennia later, Mao Zedong told throngs of teenage Red Guards to incinerate genealogical books,
shatter antique pottery, and kill intellectuals during the Cultural Revolution. Political leaders
saw China&rsquo;s traditional culture as a backwater, and remembering was not important. Despite this
cultural destruction, much has survived, and much more has been revived. In the summer of 2009, I
tried to salvage my own piece of the past. I tried to write my family&rsquo;s history. I am still trying.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>My goal was to write a definitive history – &ldquo;definitive&rdquo; in the sense that it saw through politics
and myth and objectively portrayed people and events. I wouldn&rsquo;t point the finger at an easy
scapegoat but instead be an equal-opportunity critic. The family history would capture my
grandparents and parents&#8217; lives from rural, Chinese villages to upper middle class, American
suburbia and reflect China&rsquo;s transformation from monarchy to the central government&rsquo;s so-called
socialism &ldquo;with Chinese characteristics.&rdquo; I imagined my family&rsquo;s future generations reading and
drawing inspiration from this Horatio Alger narrative of progress based on hard work. They would
continue writing this living document when the story arrived at my life. As I interviewed
relatives and tried to shape their individual experiences into a larger narrative, however, I
began to doubt my intentions and the possibility of my goal.</p>

<p>When I returned to China in 2009, I told my family to forgo tourist traps. It was the eve of the
60th anniversary of Mao&rsquo;s victory over the Nationalists, and I was visiting my relatives in the
southern, coastal city of Xiamen. I wanted to explore the island city, see its native egrets, and
learn to play its lazy Sunday mahjong games. I wanted to visit Gulangyu, a small island off the
coast of Xiamen devoid of automobiles but filled with piano music and Victorian-style villas
through which my parents strolled after their married 22 years ago. Most of all, I wanted to write
down my family&rsquo;s stories. As I wrote, I realized how little I knew.</p>

<p>My family needed to be coaxed. Everyday conversations included dinner plans, my uncle&rsquo;s day as a
marketing director, and the annoying tenants who rented their apartment units. Every night, I
spirited a family member away from the television and closed the study room door. Pen in hand and
voice recorder primed, I made him or her talk. &ldquo;Where was your geological survey team in this
photo, Grandpa?&rdquo; &ldquo;Why did the military officer think you were his sister, Grandma?&rdquo; It was slow at
first, but I would soon hit a tender area and inertia would dissipate. My pen ran to keep up with
their anecdotes, and my recorder inched just a bit closer to their words.</p>

<p>&ldquo;In our village, men were much more important than women,&rdquo; said my grandmother after she carried a
pot of chicken broth stewed with red mushrooms to the dinner table. I kept the recorder on as I
dipped my spoon into the earthy broth of the mushroom, an expensive fungus that grew only in the
wild. &ldquo;Women would never in their whole lives eat at the table&hellip;At the time, I was very young, and
I couldn&rsquo;t stand it. Later, when I turned 16, I ran away.&rdquo; After the civil war, the Communist
Party rewrote the Chinese woman&rsquo;s story when Mao emphasized their importance to China&rsquo;s
reconstruction by proclaiming that they &ldquo;held up half the sky.&rdquo; Legions of them joined the party,
and posters of agriculturally productive women driving tractors through fields of rice filled the
streets. After my grandmother ladled the last red mushroom into my bowl, she said, &ldquo;Men and women
are equal now. Some women are even more formidable than men.&rdquo; My grandmother let us eat while she
lingered in the kitchen washing dishes and putting away utensils. &ldquo;Grandma, leave the dishes,&rdquo; I
said. &ldquo;Come eat first.&rdquo;</p>

<p>My grandmother was born in 1940, nine years before the Communists won the civil war and began
rewriting both China&rsquo;s future and history. For the first time in nearly 4,000 years, foreign
incursions and technological inferiority made Chinese people realize their &ldquo;Middle Kingdom,&rdquo; the
literal translation of &ldquo;China,&rdquo; was no longer the center of the world. Under an empress&#8217; reign, my
grandmother&rsquo;s mother Wang Xi bound her feet in cotton bandages. Bundles of straw strapped to her
pants prevented the cloth from tearing as she hobbled on her knees. After four millennia of
dynastic rule, she delicately unwound the bandages and witnessed the founding of a republic in 1911.
Five years later, she saw the country disintegrate into warlord-controlled fiefdoms. After
the warlords came the Japanese, Nationalists, Communists, revolutions, famine, and waves of social
engineering projects. She lived through them all.</p>

<p>My grandfather showed me his version of our family tree tucked inside his nightstand drawer. He
copied it from his kinship clan&rsquo;s main genealogy book, which is kept in his ancestral village of
Xiqi in Fujian province. In my grandfather&rsquo;s string-bound booklet, columns of characters written
right to left list his grandfathers, father, brothers, and sons. The entries for his grandmothers,
mothers, sisters, and daughters are written in less detail under those for males. By tradition,
sons carried on the family name while daughters belonged to someone else&rsquo;s family once they were
married.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Will I be written into Grandpa&rsquo;s family tree?&rdquo; I asked my mother after we returned from our 2009
trip. By tradition, I belonged to my father&rsquo;s family tree but not my mother&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know what the custom will be in the future,&rdquo; she replied.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, my relatives&#8217; oral histories skipped like scratched records, and I could barely
make out their faces in tiny, black-and-white photographs. As I strained my eyes on grainy
pictures of my grandfather&rsquo;s geology team posing against of China&rsquo;s northwestern mountains, I knew
nothing could replace concrete, firsthand experience. Gaps between our lives confronted me when I
sought continuity from their experiences to mine. I asked my grandparents to bring me to the
village where they grew up. I believed I needed pure sensory stimuli for a smoother narrative. And
so, one weekend, we took a trip to Xiqi where, for nearly 800 years, their ancestors tilled the
land and passed on their way of life despite repeated attempts at erasure.</p>

<p>Xiqi has always been a starting point for its villagers and never a destination. Its peasants have
always looked outward, trying to escape from the impoverished valley into which they were born.
According to my grandparents, one stayed in the indigent countryside if he or she didn&rsquo;t have the
academic ability to gain acceptance to a university. When the first Xiqi broke into higher
education, villagers slaughtered pigs, carried him on a litter, and sang for three days.</p>

<p>By the mid 1950s my grandparents had more reasons to leave. Dangling the carrot of land reform,
the Chinese Communist Party tapped into an unlimited pipeline of peasant manpower for their civil
war against the Nationalists. Coming from land-owning families, my grandparents faced the
aftermath of a 22-year civil war won by promising the confiscation of landlord property. While
applying to schools, my grandfather faced increasing political discrimination. The 1949 Communist
victory had upended society. Landlords became public enemies, and the poorest peasants became the
most respected revolutionaries. The history makers were no longer imperial magistrates or urban
businessmen but communist demagogues who prophesied the inevitable triumph of the proletarian
juggernaut.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t have any big achievements or contributions in my life,&rdquo; my grandfather said on our way
to Xiqi, &ldquo;but I worked hard and was very capable as an average working class man.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Because my grandfather is known for his practicality and plain-spokenness, his sudden
sentimentality caught me off guard. As we wound our way through Anxi County&rsquo;s serpentine routes,
rows of tea terraces and sleepy hamlets that girdled mountains were triggering something in him.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I worked on this road that year when I wasn&rsquo;t accepted to any universities,&rdquo; he said pointing out
the car window. &ldquo;This is it. Right here. Your grandmother and I both worked on it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Although the location was the same, the paved, narrow road was a far cry from the original dirt
trail my grandparents helped build 54 years ago. In 1955, my grandfather&rsquo;s class background led to
his rejection from every university to which he applied. At home, village peasants persecuted him
by forcing him to build the road. They singled him out to carry the heaviest bricks.</p>

<p>As we walked through the fields, my grandfather reminisced about the second time he applied to
universities. He took the National College Entrance Examination again in 1956, and applied to
unpopular schools specializing in strenuous professions. A friend had advised him to pick a
burdensome field to repent for being a landlord. One day at end of August, he sprinted home with
an admission letter from Changchun College of Geology. That afternoon, his father helped him carry
a worn-out trunk with two old shirts and no blanket to the train station.</p>

<p>&ldquo;If it weren&rsquo;t for college, I&rsquo;d be just like the village peasants right now,&rdquo; he said as we kicked
up dust that drifted towards women hunched over tea bushes in the fields. &ldquo;I&rsquo;d be stuck here. My
face toward the loess soil, my back toward the sky.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Two years after my grandfather left for college, my grandmother left home at the age of 16 when
her family could no longer pay for her middle school lunches. She was not the only one searching
for food. The Great Chinese Famine had begun. As she traveled 140 miles to the city of Sanming and
earned 28 cents a day carrying bricks for a construction company, China tried to transform its
agrarian economy into an industrial one; the government hoped to accomplish in three years what
took other industrialized nations centuries. It was the Great Leap Forward, but it created a
famine, aided by local officials falsifying records of agricultural output, that killed anywhere
between 17 to 50 million people. To this day, no one knows the approximate figure because the
government has not released historical records. My grandparents left their native province
thinking they would never return, but two decades later, Deng Xiaoping&rsquo;s economic reforms lured
them back. Upon their return, they found that a new crop of practical politicians – those who had
not been hounded to execution and suicide during the Cultural Revolution for their lukewarm faith
in Maoist ideology – had once again rewritten history.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Some people said that back then, if Mao farted and proclaimed his fart smelled good, you couldn&rsquo;t
say he was wrong,&rdquo; my grandfather said as we entered Xiqi. &ldquo;If you did, you were a
counter-revolutionary.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Why are you saying all this?&rdquo; grumbled my grandmother.</p>

<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s freedom of speech now,&rdquo; he snapped. &ldquo;Americans can criticize even their president. Stop
pretending like we live in a Marxist-Leninist society.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Xiqi&rsquo;s villagers had stopped pretending. Maoist sayings painted on the walls of houses to
demonstrate one&rsquo;s revolutionary fervor had faded nearly beyond recognition. The once bright red
ink had weathered away or perhaps had been scrubbed off by peasants. One saying stated &ldquo;Everyone
must bear responsibility for counter-revolutionaries,&rdquo; while another stated &ldquo;Everyone engages in
production, every household ensures security.&rdquo; These slogans, forged during the Cultural
Revolution to condemn capitalists, have been replaced by Haier and China Mobile advertisements.
Xiqi&rsquo;s surrounding mountains, resembling a prone tiger to villagers, were once stripped bare of
trees by peasants desperate to fuel their stoves with firewood and unable to afford gas or coal.
Today, the tiger has grown a coat of saplings, but rows of tea terraces are also carved into its
flanks. Before Deng&rsquo;s economic reforms, Xiqi peasants scraped out a meager living through
subsistence farming; now they&rsquo;ve devoted acres of farmland to growing tea as a cash crop.</p>

<p>During my visit, the village&rsquo;s 200 people were all engaged in tea production. Women wearing straw
hats crouched and plucked tea in the fields. Lying on blankets by the roadside, leaves then
withered in the sun before being cooled and tossed. Men hauled cloth bags bigger than themselves
onto dirt-caked motorcycles and displayed their goods at farmers&#8217; markets – grassroots free market
economics. Buyers fermented leaves in large, metal cylinders that rotated like miniature cement
mixers. I watched a skinny boy stuff the curling, hot leaves in a sack, slingshot it over his
shoulder, and hit the floor with a loud slap.</p>

<p>My grandfather said Xiqi&rsquo;s villagers have done very well compared to others in rural China.
Revenue from hundreds of acres of tea shrubs and donations from wealthy, overseas family members
have funded houses, roads, and a new temple. They have abandoned their old, rammed earth
dwellings. Some live in gated, four-story houses fitted with ceramic roof tiles next to hollow,
dilapidated hovels. By pooling their money, families have constructed ornate ancestral shrines.
Overseas donations led to the construction of a new temple for the Taoist god Xuan Wu that cost a
quarter of a million US dollars. Standing near its threshold, I traced my finger up the spines of
serpentine dragons carved onto stone pillars and tracked my eyes along power lines, water pipes,
and paved roads crisscrossing outside.</p>

<p>When my grandmother showed me the house where her mother Wang Xi lived, I thought of my previous
visit to China. During the summer, typhoons venturing from their Pacific breeding grounds,
frequently slam into the coast of southeastern China with 100 mile-per-hour winds. When good
weather and weekends coincided, my uncle and aunt drove my family to the water-filled basin of
Great Golden Lake and circular tulou fortresses. As their small BMW drove through Fujian&rsquo;s
mountains, I saw the effects of tropical storms on precarious slopes – iron oxide-laden soil
splayed across four lanes and car-sized boulders defiantly blocking roads. As the summer of 2006
waned, I asked my family to plan a visit to my great-grandmother whom I never knew. News of
landslides on the roads to her house in Anxi County, 80 miles from Xiamen, caused my family to
defer the trip in hopes of better weather. Weekends came and went, landslides continued to jam
county highways, and I grew anxious. On the last weekend before my flight back to Boston, my
request for an attempted trip was answered with &ldquo;next time.&rdquo; &ldquo;You&rsquo;ll come back again,&rdquo; said my
relatives. My great-grandmother was 107 years old when she died the next year.</p>

<p>Two years later, I was standing in her house and looking at her photograph. The same day, I saw
the modest dwellings where my grandparents were born: a hovel with no windows for my grandmother,
a shack where dozens of rocks held down loose roof tiles for my grandfather. I pressed my palms
against gravelly walls as I peeked through the smashed windows of the local elementary school.
Above one classroom&rsquo;s chalkboard, a Chinese flag is framed by two thin metal plates reading, &ldquo;The
interests of the fatherland are the highest priority of all.&rdquo; My grandparents first met at this
school while carrying out the Communist&rsquo;s directive of educating illiterate peasants by teaching
night classes. I smelled the incense sticks my grandfather held as paid respect to his ancestral
shrine – rows and rows of spirit tablets, wood steles engraved with patriarchs&#8217; names in gold
paint, tracing his family back 39 generations. He lit some more sticks and handed them to me. We
sent spiritual money to Xuan Wu by burning joss paper, visited my grandfather&rsquo;s cousin in the room
they learned to play the Chinese lute as children, and drank Fujian&rsquo;s finest Oolong tea from cups
whose white porcelain brought out the tea&rsquo;s jade hue.</p>

<p>As I received the cup my great-uncle passed to me and inhaled the Oolong&rsquo;s bittersweet flavor, I
realized the disparity between China&rsquo;s past and present was caused not only by changes in
technology, governance, and culture. Political victors had constantly rewritten national narrative
to the point that a new language defined fundamental concepts and everyday life. As my grandfather
chatted with his cousin in the Min Nan dialect of southern Fujian, my mother concentrated on
listening for bits she understood while I merely followed the sounds of their voices. Born in
Yan&#8217;an, the city of deliverance for embattled Communist troops and the birthplace of their
revolution, my mother grew up 200 miles away from her parent&rsquo;s native dialect. Since my
grandparents didn&rsquo;t plan on returning to Fujian during her childhood, they never taught her Min
Nan. Besides, whenever they fought, they found it convenient to argue in a language their children
didn&rsquo;t understand. My mother&rsquo;s first language was Mandarin, the resolution of a 1913 conference of
political delegates instead of linguistic specialists who convened to unify China&rsquo;s spoken
language. The political leaders who overthrew the emperors wanted to build a new nation and
consolidate power. They started by standardizing pronunciation. When Fujian people spoke Min Nan
to my mother or charged her a higher price because they viewed her as an outsider, she told her
parents they should&rsquo;ve taught her the language.</p>

<p>By the time I was born, written language had also changed. I grew up learning a variety of Chinese
characters called &ldquo;simplified characters.&rdquo; I believed they were a natural evolution from older
traditional characters instead of the result of a political party&rsquo;s Orwellian implementation. I
harbored this misconception until I read Robert S. Ramsey&rsquo;s Languages of China. It was spring and
I was sitting in Columbia University&rsquo;s East Asian library. The east wall&rsquo;s stained glass image of
Justice wielding a sword and scale scattered light onto the pages of the chapter &ldquo;Chinese Writing
Today.&rdquo; Ramsey described many Chinese intellectuals&#8217; thoughts of discarding traditional Chinese
characters at the turn of the 19th century and alphabetizing the language. They rejected
traditional characters as one facet of a backwards culture that allowed &ldquo;foreign devils&rdquo; to
eviscerate their land and people. China would either modernize its government, economy, and even
language or perish. After the Nationalist Party lost the civil war in 1949 to a party that
believed it could conquer Mother Nature herself, language reform became a national priority.
Advocates of the Latinization Movement hoped to liberate their country &ldquo;from the shackles of
monosyllabic Chinese characters&rdquo; and increase peasant literacy by adopting an alphabet. The
Communist party began two simultaneous approaches to alphabetization – designing a phonetic
writing system and simplifying existing characters.</p>

<p>I closed the book and felt as if all the characters I had learned were fake, as if the Communist
party had played a gigantic practical joke on me. &ldquo;How come you never told me?&rdquo; I interrogated my
parents that night with a conspiracy theorist&rsquo;s sense of urgency. &ldquo;You never asked,&rdquo; said my
mother casually. Today, I ask my parents everything about their previous lives in China. I asked
my mother how she felt about moving every time the government relocated her father&rsquo;s geology team
to a town where she had no friends and didn&rsquo;t know the local dialect. I asked my father how long
my grandfather was jailed in a &ldquo;political reeducation camp&rdquo; because someone spoke about his
Nationalist Party affiliations to curry Communist favor.</p>

<p>Trying to understand my family&rsquo;s history was like untangling gum from hair. There were too many
gaps, and memory was too slippery. Obedience to authority and dogma defined my parents&#8217; lives.
Teachers praised students who wrote the best essay criticizing the latest politician to get on
Mao&rsquo;s bad side. Liu Shaoqi one day; Deng the next. Historical figures and narratives that didn&rsquo;t
support the prevailing political climate were forgotten. Physical objects that undermined
political rule were destroyed. The cultural destruction of the 1960s reached Xiqi as well. The
village&rsquo;s genealogical records and religious icons were decimated.</p>

<p>But centuries-old customs and folklore survive today despite waves of social engineering projects
bent on eradicating a traditional culture once seen as primitive. They had restored their history.
As I visited Xiqi&rsquo;s ancestral shrines, I saw that villagers had remade spirit tablets destroyed in
the Cultural Revolution. The temple has an effigy of Xuan Wu, the patron saint of Mi Nan speakers.
A little bigger than a basketball, the warrior god, clad in golden armor and a red cape, sits on a
throne. His right hand is posed in a meditative gesture, and his left holds a bronze sword
commissioned by my grandmother. As I looked at its calm face, my grandparents told me how it was
saved during the Cultural Revolution.</p>

<p>A farmer walking back home from the fields one day saw a government official carrying the statue.
The farmer asked him what he was doing with it. The official was about to smash it. &ldquo;Why all the
fuss over a figurine?&rdquo; asked the farmer. &ldquo;Here, give it to me. I&rsquo;ll deal with this simple matter.&rdquo;
The official gave Xuan Wu to the farmer who feared divine retribution and secretly protected it in
his house. Over time, villagers began seeing the official walking outside during winter without
warm clothes. They whispered among themselves that Xuan Wu had taken revenge on the official by
destroying his sanity. The official died a painful death, and once the Cultural Revolution ended,
Xuan Wu returned to his temple.</p>

<p>After we drove back to Xiamen, I began crafting a narrative from the material I collected. But
wondered if I was accurately portraying my family&rsquo;s past and if my motives to write a &ldquo;definitive&rdquo;
history were as pure as I thought. As I looked over my writing, I realized I&rsquo;d omitted my
grandparents&#8217; shortcomings as parents for their own children, my black sheep older uncle, and my
parents&#8217; less than ideal marriage. I recognized the similarities between a genealogist who skimmed
over family flaws to idealize his image and a government that suppressed failures of blind
ideology to romanticize its reputation. My intentions were not as shady as those of political
figures, but they were just as self-serving. I had extolled my grandparents&#8217; hard work, spun a
continuous narrative from their lives to mine, and claimed credit for their successes. The
Nationalists and Communists had rewritten the past into a narrative of progress in order to
glamorize themselves. I was in danger of honoring my ancestors in order to honor myself.</p>

<p>During that summer, my six-year-old cousin walked around the apartment with a red book called
<em>Three Character Classic</em>. Written entirely in phrases of three characters, this book encapsulated
Confucian ethics for young children. Although he couldn&rsquo;t read or understand most of the
characters, my cousin, encouraged by his parents, could recite from memory maxims that prescribed
respect towards his elders and devotion to his nation. <em>Read the history books, examine the
records, connect the ancient with the present, and you&rsquo;ll be as close as an eyewitness&hellip;</em> After 50
years of banning <em>Three Character Classic</em> from schools and nearly a century of demonizing
Confucianism as a cultural handicap, the Communist Party has tacitly reversed their attitude.
State-owned publishing houses have begun reprinting Confucian classics in simplified characters.
Original texts for adults and abridged versions for children have crowded bookstore shelves. This
was, however, not the same Confucianism as before. China&rsquo;s government and people selectively
retold the Confucian narrative. They emphasized the importance of social harmony and obedience to
state authority and ignored Confucius&#8217; disparagement of businessmen and sexism towards women. I
could hear the revisionist pens of party historians sketching out a new draft.</p>

<p>Before I left China for the United States, I bought a copy of <em>Three Character Classic</em>. As I read
it with my mother on the plane, I asked her the meanings of characters I didn&rsquo;t know and the
implications of phrases I didn&rsquo;t understand. Between my attempts to read through the <em>Three
Character Classic</em>, I tried to write my family history.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Calculate Your Birthday According to Chinese Calendar]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/how-to-calculate-your-birthday-according-to-chinese-calendar/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/how-to-calculate-your-birthday-according-to-chinese-calendar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My birthday according to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gregorian_calendar">Gregorian calendar</a> is September 23, 1988. But the Gregorian
calendar seems a bit passé. So this year I will celebrate my birthday according to the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_calendar">Chinese calendar</a>.</p>

<p>To calculate your Chinese calendar birthday go to <a href="http://site.baidu.com/list/wannianli.htm">Baidu&rsquo;s calendar converter</a>; go to the year,
month, and day of your birth; hover over that day and note the 农历 month (月) and day (曰). Mine is
the 8th month and 13th day. Now go to this year and hover over dates in a similar range until you
see the same month and day. This year, my lunar birthday is September 10, 2011 instead of
September 23 and next year it&rsquo;ll be September 28.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts About if You Are the One 1 & 2]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/some-thoughts-about-if-you-are-the-one-1-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/some-thoughts-about-if-you-are-the-one-1-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just watched the Chinese movie <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001QW5704/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373&amp;creativeASIN=B001QW5704"><em>If You Are the One</em></a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001QW5704&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373" alt="" /> and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/7798978127/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=easiamus00-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373&amp;creativeASIN=7798978127">its sequel</a><img src="https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=easiamus00-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=7798978127&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373" alt="" />. I&rsquo;m
disappointed by the first and confused by the second. The two films tell the story of a nearly
50-year-old bachelor looking to get married and a single woman 20 years his younger whose heart is
hung up on another married man. These two characters are played respectively by Beijing&rsquo;s Ge Yo
and Taiwan&rsquo;s Shu Qi<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, two well-known celebrities.</p>

<p>Shu Qi&rsquo;s character Xiao Xiao is an attractive late-twenties flight attendant who is in love with a
married man. This guy promised her that he&rsquo;d leave his wife and marry her. But guess what? He
renegs and leaves her hanging. Heartbroken but still not over him, she continues to wait for him
to change his mind. But while she&rsquo;s waiting, why not broadcast an online personal? That&rsquo;s how she
meets Qin Fen who did the same.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Here&rsquo;s Qin Fen&rsquo;s personal both in Chinese and English because it&rsquo;s that funny. It&rsquo;s a good example
of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ge_You">Ge You</a>&rsquo;s trademark dry, quirky humor. Here&rsquo;s his marriage personal at the beginning of the
first movie.</p>

<blockquote><p>征婚启事</p>

<p>你要想找一帅哥就别来了，你要想找一钱包就别见了。硕士学历以上的免谈，女企业家免谈
 （小商小贩除外）。省得咱们互相都会失望。刘德华和阿汤哥那种才貌双全的郎君是不会来征你的婚的，
  当然我也没做诺丁山的梦。您要真是一仙女我也接不住，没期待您长得跟画报封面一样看一眼就魂飞魄散。
  外表时尚，内心保守，身心都健康的一般人就行。要是多少还有点婉约那就更靠谱了。心眼别太多，
  岁数别太小。会叠衣服，每次洗完烫平。叠的都像刚从商店里买回来的一样。说得够具体了吧？</p>

<p>自我介绍一下。我岁数已经不小了。日子小康。抽烟，不喝酒。留学生身份出去的，在国外生活过十几年，
  没正经上过学，蹉跎中练就一身生存技能，现在学无所成海外归来，实话实说，应该定性为一只没有公司、
  没有股票、没有学位的&#8221;三无伪海龟&#8221;。人品五五开，不算老实，但天生胆小，杀人不犯法我也下不去手，
  总体而言属于对人群对社会有益无害的一类。</p>

<p>有意就电取。非诚勿扰。</p>

<p>Marriage Personal</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for a handsome guy, don&rsquo;t bother. No gold-diggers either. To avoid mutual
  disappointment: no women with educational backgrounds of masters and above or entrepreneurs
  (except for small trades and peddlers). Talented and good-looking playboys like Andy Lau and Tom
  Cruise won&rsquo;t be looking to marry you. Of course, I&rsquo;m not dreaming of <em>Notting Hill</em>. If you&rsquo;re
  actually a goddess, I can&rsquo;t handle you. I&rsquo;m not expecting a cover girl who will blow me away with
  her beauty. Modern on the outside, conservative on the inside. An average person with a healthy
  body and mind is fine. If you are also demure, that&rsquo;s even better. Don&rsquo;t be too complicated or too
  young. Proficiency in folding laundry. Preferably pressed and folded like they just came off the
  store shelf. Am I being specific enough?</p>

<p>Let me introduce myself. My age is not small. Middle-class. Smoke but don&rsquo;t drink. Went abroad
  to study. Lived overseas for a dozen years. Never really studied much. Slacked and learned a few
  survival skills. I&rsquo;ve returned without accomplishment. Truthfully, I&rsquo;m what they call a &ldquo;three
  strikes&rdquo; returnee: no company, no stocks, no degree. Morally, I&rsquo;m 50-50. I&rsquo;m no angel, but I was
  born a bit cowardly. If homicide was legal, I still couldn&rsquo;t do it. Overall, I&rsquo;d classify myself
  as a constructive and harmless member of society.</p>

<p>If interested, please call. If not sincere, do not disturb.</p></blockquote>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="304" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2wWra0f4A6U?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The first film, although labeled a romantic comedy, is rather melancholy. Xiao Xiao is a real
downer. She constantly feels sorry for herself and is in general a depressing person. It&rsquo;s hard to
imagine Hollywood billing a movie that ended with the attempted suicide of its main female
character as a romantic comedy. The first half shows Qin Fen going on many blind dates and the
succession of women in one way or another incompatible women. There&rsquo;s the woman who parlays their
date into an opportunity to sell him a cemetery plot for his parents, the woman who lives in a
far-flung western province reachable only after an entire day traveling via ox-drawn cart, and the
erotophobic widow who will only agree to sex once a year. The second half&rsquo;s pacing feels off. Its
plot is inconclusive and goes nowhere. Its only redeeming aspect is the scenery of beautiful
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hokkaido">Hokkaido</a>.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, <em>If You Are the One</em> was one of the highest grossing Chinese films in the months
after its release. Its success most likely comes from its two big stars and perhaps the tastes of
Chinese audiences. This <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123446005281078231.html">Wall Street Journal article</a> describes how Chinese romantic comedies
are very different from their Hollywood counterparts. Love isn&rsquo;t always butterflies in one&rsquo;s
stomach, but often a painful struggle.</p>

<p>If you aren&rsquo;t searching for a carefree, happily-ever-after summer movie, then these two movies
aren&rsquo;t that bad. I&rsquo;m watching them to brush up on my Mandarin and to acquaint myself with some of
China&rsquo;s best natural landscapes.</p>

<p>Much of <em>If You Are the One 2</em> takes place in China&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hainan">Hainan</a> island. Qin Fen&rsquo;s vacation
getaway in a <a href="http://www.ilvping.com/routes/linetip-id-16833-cp-2.html">private tree house</a> overlooking the island is visually stunning. So stunning
that the story and characters take a backseat. But that&rsquo;s alright. I have no qualms with watching
Shu Qi walking among tropical plants and preparing to take a bath in the tub on the balcony.</p>

<p>This is even more melancholy than the first one. Qin Fen and Xiao Xiao decide to break off their
engagement and split up. Then his good friend Xiang Shan tells him he&rsquo;s got terminal malignant
melanoma.</p>

<p>The last third of the movie is all about Xiang Shan&rsquo;s farewell ceremony. Pretty much they hold a
funeral while he&rsquo;s still alive and present. Everyone pays their respects. He does this long
confessional at the end laying bare his shortcomings and mistakes. His daughter recites a poem she
wrote. One of the saddest things i&rsquo;ve heard. And then Qin Fen takes him out into the middle of teh
ocean aboard a little dignhy and the guy gets out of his wheelchair and jumps into the ocean to
die.</p>

<hr />
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Shu Qi was once a softcore porn model starring in films with names like <em>Sex &amp; Zen II</em>. Just FYI. She has overcome the stigma by moving into mainstream movies.  Oh, and she has a high ranking on the scientific and authoritative AskMen.com&rsquo;s [&ldquo;Top 99 Women&rdquo; list][12].<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Started Taking Chinese Medicine Seriously]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/why-i-started-taking-chinese-medicine-seriously/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/why-i-started-taking-chinese-medicine-seriously</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Growing up, I scrunched my nose when my mom opened the kitchen cabinet housing our supply of
chinese medicine. Blackened twigs, pungent bark, shriveled roots, orange fungi, and miniature
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calabash">calabash</a> gourd-shaped bottles of black beads. This trove of potions and powders looked
medieval and mysterious. Enveloped during childhood by science books, I dismissed whatever didn&rsquo;t
have a scientific explanation, which included the seeming shamanism of Chinese medicine.</p>

<p>So what changed my mind? If it weren&rsquo;t for Chinese medicine, my birth could&rsquo;ve run into
complications. The chances were slim, but you don&rsquo;t want to mess around with the possibility of
brain and internal organ damage.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Several years ago, my mom told me the story of my birth. I&rsquo;d been hanging around in her womb for
seven months, enjoying free food, oxygen, and even waste disposal. Life was good. The best
position, or &ldquo;presentation&rdquo; if you&rsquo;re an obstetrician, for a fetus to be in during childbirth is
head first, crown outwards (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presentation_(obstetrics)#Classification">vertex, cephalic)</a>. This orientation is associated with the least
complications.</p>

<p>I, however, decided to go with a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breech_presentation">breech</a> or head-up presentation. The obstetrician noticed
this around the seven month period. Not a serious problem yet but not something to be cavalier
about either. She gave my mom some two-part advice about how to correct my position.</p>

<p>The first was to spend some time everyday tilting her head down and bottom up. I am imagining her
practicing a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adho_Mukha_Svanasana">downward dog yoga position</a>. The second was to fumigate the soles of her feet
with dried wormwood.</p>

<p>Okay, this requires some explanation. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_vulgaris">Common wormwood</a> or mugwort, not to be confused with
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_absinthium">grande wormwood</a> or the herb that college students think is the shit in the alcoholic drink
Absinth, is a perennial plant that has many uses in food and herbal medicine. In the middle ages,
mugwort was a protective plant. Today it is sometimes a seasoning ingredient in cuisines ranging
from Japanese to German. Don&rsquo;t eat too much though. Its oil apparently contains a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thujone">chemical</a>
that&rsquo;s toxic in large doses.</p>

<p>My mom bought some dried mugwort rolled into cigar-like tubes, lit them up, and let the smoke shroud
her big toes. Sounds like a bunch of hogwash right? So I did a bit of research and found this on
Wikipedia:</p>

<blockquote><p>In Traditional Chinese medicine there is a belief that moxibustion of mugwort is effective at
  increasing the cephalic positioning of fetuses who were in a breech position before the
  intervention. A Cochrane review in 2005 found that moxibustion may be beneficial in reducing the
  need for ECV, but stressed a need for well-designed randomised controlled trials to evaluate this
  usage. Since it also causes uterine contractions, it has been used to cause abortion.<strong> A study of
  260 Chinese women at 33 weeks of pregnancy demonstrated cephalic version within two weeks in 75%
  of fetuses carried by patients who were treated with moxibustion, as opposed to 48% in the control
  group.</strong> It has also been shown that acupuncture plus moxibustion slows fetal heart rates while
  increasing fetal movement. Two recent studies of Italian patients produced conflicting results. In
  the first, involving 226 patients, there was cephalic presentation at delivery in 54% of women
  treated between 33 and 35 weeks with acupuncture and moxibustion, vs. 37% in the control group.
  The second was terminated prematurely because of poor compliance with treatment, but found no
  difference between moxibustion and control groups.</p></blockquote>

<p>Oh, snap!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One of the Saddest Movie Scenes I've Ever Seen]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/one-of-the-saddest-movie-scenes-ive-ever-seen/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/06/one-of-the-saddest-movie-scenes-ive-ever-seen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently watched the movie Chinese movie <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_Home_(1999_film)">The Road Home</a></em> directed by Zhang Yimou and
starring Zhang Ziyi. It&rsquo;s a movie about two lovers set in the countryside of 1960s China whose
courtship is interrupted by greater political events shaking the country. If you want to watch a
happy, care-free summer movie, don&rsquo;t pick <em>The Road Home</em>. It&rsquo;s quite melancholy. While watching,
I wrote down the absolute saddest scene of the film.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/48ivIU6Szok?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!--more-->


<p>The young male teacher Luo Changyu who&rsquo;s been sent by the Communists from the city to educate
village children tells Zhang Ziyi&rsquo;s character Zhao Di that he&rsquo;s leaving the village for what
rumors say is &ldquo;political questioning.&rdquo; Zhao Di said she&rsquo;s made mushroom dumplings and urges him
should have some before leaving. For some reason, he leaves before eating even though he just said
he would. She takes a bowl of freshly made dumplings and hopelessly chases after the horse-drawn
carriage that&rsquo;s taking him away. She runs and runs, with horrible form I might add. She runs
awkwardly with both hands holding the bowl of dumplings which is secured by a smaller bowl cupped
on top and a towel binding them. I bet she would&rsquo;ve run faster if she&rsquo;d just tucked that bowl in
the crook of her elbow like a football running back.</p>

<p>Up until this point, the courtship between them has been furtive glances, shy conversations, and
having the teacher over at her mother&rsquo;s house for dinner once. Neither Zhao Di nor Luo Changyu
know whether he&rsquo;ll be able to return. This might be the last time they see each other.</p>

<p>Anyways, the running scene is long. The entire time you watch her chasing after this carriage
which is must faster than her. You know she won&rsquo;t catch it, but you hope she knows some shortcut
that&rsquo;ll let her cut in front of the carriage&rsquo;s position. And then she stumbles, the bowl flies out
of her hands, shatters on the ground, and dumplings scatter everywhere. She looks at the
dumplings, then at the disappering carriage, and cries.</p>

<p>This is the saddest scene in the movie. First of all because perfectly good food has been wasted.
Second of all because, well, perfectly good food has been wasted!</p>

<p>I just watched the scene where as she&rsquo;s weaving a piece of bright red cloth, she hears
multiplication table chanting coming from the school house. She leaves her loom and runs out in
the middle of the harsh winter day to the school (which is just a single room) only to find she
was imagining it. The school room is empty. She comes back with thin yellow paper which she uses
to recover the windows which are simply wooden frames put into square holes in the walls. Glass is
expensive. The main musical theme of the movie is plays again. Zhao Di cleans and scrubs down the
entire room. Now she&rsquo;s sitting at one of the student benches staring blankly at the blackboard.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
