<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Friends | David Xia]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/categories/friends/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-04-21T00:40:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.davidxia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Xia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Awesome Cofounder and Advisors]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/my-awesome-cofounder-and-advisors/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/09/my-awesome-cofounder-and-advisors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>James</h3>

<p>I had the opportunity of meeting James the day he left his law firm to start a company. He&rsquo;s one
of the most affable, able, and ambitious people I know. He told me that he wants to &ldquo;Go big or go
home&rdquo; and for him its closer to the truth than you might think.</p>

<p>James and I worked very closely for half a year. I&rsquo;ve never had a peer with whom I had such a
close working relationship. How close? I spent more nights at his apartment than his girlfriend
and kept an extra toothbrush in his bathroom.</p>

<p>It was six months of engineering and entrepreneurial bootcamp. James and I traveled to Boulder,
Colorado to check out the Techstars incubator program. We flew to Vancouver, Canada to roll out
our beta in an effort to acquire travel bloggers as our core users. I remember landing in
Vancouver the day the city&rsquo;s hockey team, the Canucks, won the fifth game of the 2011 Stanley Cup.
James and I waded through 100,000 drunk, loud Canadians running through the streets with
outstretched palms motioning for high fives. (Being from Boston, the city of the opposing Bruins
team, I feared for my life the day the Canucks lost the championship and Vancouverites
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2011_Vancouver_Stanley_Cup_riot">set police cars on fire</a>.)</p>

<p>I met Ben and Nan, two Berkeley computer science graduates, through James. I&rsquo;m glad to have met
such smart advisors and friends who are insightful, patient, and frank. Launching a startup is
do-or-die. I needed colleagues whom I could count on to call it like they see it and, when
necessary, respectfully say, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re doing it wrong. Do it this way.&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Ben</h3>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/bensussman">Ben</a> taught me how to build scalable websites, use Vim, and understand Git. He helped me on
implementing input box autocompletes to job hunting. He&rsquo;s a great mentor and genuinely likes
teaching. He once said, &ldquo;Teaching you Vim makes me happy.&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Nan</h3>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/thenanyu">Nan</a> helped me see why certain services or business models worked. He explained why companies
like Tumblr and Gilt Groupe were able to become successful. Tumblr became popular because it
created a new type of content by being like Twitter on steroids and having great UI. Gilt took
advantage of distressed luxury inventory during the last recession (which I think never really
ended).</p>

<p>Even after Shoutbound ended, James, Ben, and Nan have been tremendously helpful. All of them
helped me transition to my new position.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Write a 1920s Party Invitation]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/how-to-write-a-1920s-party-invitation/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/08/how-to-write-a-1920s-party-invitation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My friend <a href="http://jonmaimon.wordpress.com/">Jonny</a> is a time traveler from the Roaring Twenties. Today he taught me how to
write a party invitation if I ever found myself in the Jazz Age.</em></p>

<blockquote><p>You are invited&hellip;</p>

<p>Listen up you swell flyboys and Jane&rsquo;s!</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s an old-fashioned speak-easy, so bring your bootleg and giggle water. We&rsquo;re looking for the
finest dolls&hellip;you know a choice bit of calico but none of those dumb Doras. Don&rsquo;t forget to be on
the lookout for squirrels, we don&rsquo;t need the law getting an earful of the fun.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got to scram for now, but this carousing is sure to be a cat&rsquo;s meow.</p>

<p>Get ups: Fellas – A flat cap or fedora. Dolls – Cloche hat and bobbed hair</p>

<p>Address: The Gin Mill, or as some other fellas style it, 200 Oak Avenue Apt. 12, New York City</p>

<p>Time: Past sunset but ahead of the small hours, or as you flappers say, 10:30 PM</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Costa Rica Trip 2010 Video]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/costa-rica-trip-2010-video/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/05/costa-rica-trip-2010-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally got around to editing this. This is filmed with low-resolution point-and-shoot cameras,
handled with wobbly camera work, and edited with no prior film-editing experience.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZS75R9C-wkU?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Miss My Senior Year Roommates]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2011/03/i-miss-my-senior-year-roommates/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2011/03/i-miss-my-senior-year-roommates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a video of my roommates during our senior year at Columbia University. The first part shows Raul calling CAVA after Jason had burned himself while cooking macaroni and cheese. The second half is me antagonizing Jason and David during their midnight snack of whipped cream and bananas.</p>

<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/S2EMtmhIwh0?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<iframe class="fill-width" width="540" height="405" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wAsVfv-ppjM?rel=0"
  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TYrwnPFloNI/AAAAAAAAAyc/rmeBcw8YdiM/s800/zhou-bday.gif">https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_lgMz7QRk66k/TYrwnPFloNI/AAAAAAAAAyc/rmeBcw8YdiM/s800/zhou-bday.gif</a>&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australian Adventures: Car Wrecks and Crazy Aussies]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/australian-adventures-car-wrecks-and-crazy-aussies/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.davidxia.com/2010/09/australian-adventures-car-wrecks-and-crazy-aussies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Adam Urban wrote an exciting series of posts at his blog <a href="http://appleguru.org/blog"><em>Aimful Wanderings</em></a>. He&rsquo;s
currently studying abroad in Australia and has had a good serving of adventures in the outback.
These adventures include:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://appleguru.org/blog/2010/08/31/beach-to-bush/"><strong>Witnessing a car full of passengers careen off a 200-foot-tall cliff</strong></a>. Adam&rsquo;s
younger brother Luke ran to the car expecting severed limbs and bashed-in skulls. Instead, he saw
five unscathed Aussies pop open the totaled doors and carry surfboards, a guitar, and a case of
beer and to the beach in true devil-may-care fashion.</li>
<li><a href="http://appleguru.org/blog/2010/09/14/beach-to-bush-part-3/"><strong>Completely destroying a car and almost dying in the Australian wilderness.</strong></a></li>
</ul>


<p>Man, I wish I had been there for these (mis)adventures.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
